[MUSIC PLAYING]
[放歌！]
This is CS50 Harvard University.
这是哈佛大学的CS50课程。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫 鸡. 马兰：好的。
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
这是CS50，哈佛大学的介绍
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
致计算机科学的智力企业
and the arts of programming.
和编程艺术。
My name is David Malan, and I actually took this course myself, back in 1996.
我的名字是大卫 马兰，实际上我自己在1996年参加了这门课程。
I was a sophomore at the time.
那时候我是大二学生。
I was actually concentrating in government, because a year prior,
我实际上专注于政府，因为一年前，
as a first year, I'd come into Harvard thinking
第一年，我进入哈佛时思考
that I liked history and constitutional law and similar classes in high school.
我喜欢历史和宪法以及高中的类似课程。
And so when I got here, I rather gravitated
所以当我来到这里时，我宁愿被吸引
toward that which was familiar.
向着熟悉的方向。
I figured, if I liked and if I were good at that particular subject
我想，如果我喜欢，如果我擅长那个特定的主题
in high school, then that's presumably who I'm supposed to be here.
在高中，那大概就是我应该在这里的人。
But it wasn't until sophomore year that I got up
但直到大二，我才
the nerve to step foot in the CS50 classroom,
鼓起勇气踏进CS50的教室
and even then, it was only out of curiosity.
即使如此，也只是出于好奇。
Like I had no intention of studying computer science of even taking CS50
就像我甚至不打算学习计算机科学一样 CS50
when I got to campus.
当我到了校园。
But people were talking about it, and there was a lot of beware.
但是人们在谈论它，有很多人要注意。
And it was perhaps for the initiated only,
这也许只适用于发起者，
and I didn't really ultimately what computer science was.
我最终并不知道计算机科学是什么。
But for me, the light bulb went off.
但对我来说，灯泡熄灭了。
I found that, contrary to what I'd seen in high school,
我发现，与我在高中时看到的相反，
where I saw friends of mine like programming away in the computer lab,
在那里我看到我的朋友喜欢在计算机实验室撸代码，
heads down, antisocially just doing whatever it was they were doing,
低着头，反社会只是做他们正在做的事情，
it really wasn't that, once I got to this particular class
真的不是这样，当我上了这门课之后
and this particular place.
和这个特殊的地方。
It was much more about problem solving more generally and just learning
更多的是关于更普遍地解决问题和只是学习
how to express yourself in code, in different languages.
如何用代码、不同的语言表达自己。
So that you can actually solve problems of interest to you.
这样你就能真正解决你感兴趣的问题。
Even if you have no intention of being a computer scientist or an engineer,
即使你无意成为一名计算机科学家或工程师，
but just want to be able to solve problems,
但只想能够解决问题，
analyze data do interesting things, in the arts, humanities, social sciences,
分析数据做有趣的事情，在艺术，人文，社会科学，
physical sciences, or really any other field.
物理科学，或者任何其他领域。
And indeed, this particular path led me to computer science,
事实上，这条特殊的道路把我带到了计算机科学，
but the hope for CS50 more generally is that, indeed, you
但对 CS50 更普遍的希望是，确实，你
just find your way to applying principles
只要找到应用原则的方法
that you'll learn over the coming months to whatever
在接下来的几个月里你会学到什么
field is of interest to you.
菲尔德是你感兴趣的。
With that said, it was definitely a lot of work and not
话虽如此，这绝对是很多工作，而不是
without its frustrations for me.
没有它对我的挫败感。
But there was no better feeling than like banging your head proverbial
但是没有比像belike着你的头更好的感觉了
against the wall for some number of hours, even days, trying to fix a bug,
在墙上呆了几个小时，甚至几天，试图修复一个bug，
a mistake in your code.
代码中的错误。
And then, oh my God, the rush of emotion of accomplishment
然后，哦，我的老天爷，成就感喷薄而出
of pride of exhaustion when you finally solve some problem that's
当你终于解决了一些问题
really been weighing on you.
真的一直在操着你。
It's just so incredibly gratifying but also empowering.
这真是令人难以置信的满足，但也赋予了力量。
Because unlike a lot of fields, like computer science
因为不像很多领域，比如计算机科学
was built by humans themselves.
是人类自己建造的。
And so if a human built this, surely, you, another human,
因此，如果一个人建造了这个，当然，你，另一个人，
can understand it as well.
也能理解。
And so even though there's going to be some distractions along the way,
所以即使一路上会有一些分心的事情，
you're going to see what looks incredibly cryptic, if you've never
你会看到看起来令人难以置信的神秘，如果你从来没有
programmed before.
之前编程。
Over time and with practice, everything just starts to make more sense.
随着时间的推移和实践，一切都开始变得更有意义。
And with time and with practice, you just
随着时间的推移和练习，你只是
get better at this particular field.
在这个特定领域做得更好。
And indeed, really, the key to success in programming in general
事实上，实际上，编程成功的关键是
is just to allow yourself enough time.
只是为了给自己足够的时间。
And so at least, thankfully, I quickly got
所以至少，谢天谢地，我很快就得到了
into the habit of starting early in the week,
养成在一周初开始的习惯，
for instance, when writing actual code.
例如，在编写实际代码时。
Why?
为什么？
Because you're going to run up against a wall.
因为你会撞墙。
You're not going to see some bug.
你不会看到一些错误。
Something's not going to jump out at you, and that's fine.
有些东西不会向你扑来，这很好。
That's when you call it a day, take a break, move onto something else,
那就是你今天到此的时候，休息一下，转移到别的事情上，
and then just come back to it.
然后回到它。
And that's what keeps programming fun for me, even all of these years later,
这就是让我保持编程乐趣的原因，即使在这么多年后，
whether it's teaching or actually applying it.
无论是教学还是实际应用。
But there's, down the road, a history of an MIT hack,
但是，沿着这条路走下去，麻省理工学院黑客的历史，
and it looked a little something like this, in yesteryear.
它看起来有点像这样，在过去。
And there was a little sigh the MIT students, when they made this hack.
当麻省理工学院的学生进行此黑客攻击时，他们叹了口气。
On the wall it says, getting an education from MIT
墙上写着，从麻省理工学院接受教育
is like drinking from a fire hose, which indeed they
就像从消防水带上喝水一样，他们确实
have connected to what should have been otherwise just a water fountain.
已经连接到本来应该只是一个喷泉的东西。
And that's going to be what it feels like, sometimes,
有时候，这就是它的感觉，
not just in computer science per se, but just an unfamiliar field.
不仅仅是计算机科学本身，而只是一个陌生的领域。
If you're not from STEM, if you're not from CS, that's fine.
如果你不是来自STEM，如果你不是来自CS，那很好。
But so much of it, ultimately, is going to be absorbed by you
但这么多，最终，会被你吸收
and going to be within your grasp by terms end.
并且将在条款结束时在你的掌握之中。
So just keep in mind, that's very much the intent,
所以请记住，这很大程度上是我们的意图，
but you'll be amazed what you're able to create, to accomplish,
但你会惊讶于你能够创造什么，完成什么，
just three or so months hence.
仅仅三个月左右的时间。
Indeed, 2/3 of you, contrary to what you might think are assume,
事实上，你们2/3人，与你们可能认为的相反，
have never taken a CS class before.
以前从未上过CS课。
So it's absolutely not the case that the person to the left or the right
所以绝对不是左边或右边的人
surely must know more than you.
肯定比你知道的更多。
Indeed, it's quite the opposite.
事实上，情况恰恰相反。
And as you'll see in the coming weeks, as you write your own code
正如你将在未来几周内看到的那样，当你编写自己的代码时
and solve your own problems, what ultimately matters in this course
并解决你自己的问题，这门课程最终重要的事情
is not so much where you end up relative to your classmates
与其说是你最终相对于你的同学
but where you end up relative to yourself when you began.
但是当你开始时，你最终相对于自己的地方。
And it really is all about that delta, whether you've programmed
这真的是关于三角洲的，无论你是否已经编程
or not, just getting something out of a class like this.
或者不是，只是从这样的课堂上得到一些东西。
And if it does take time, and if you do feel those frustrations,
如果确实需要时间，而且你确实感到沮丧，
but you simultaneously eventually feel that sense of accomplishment,
但同时你最终会感受到那种成就感，
that just means it's all working.
这只是意味着一切都在工作。
And indeed, hopefully, all the more worthwhile and gratifying, ultimately,
事实上，希望最终更有价值和令人满意的是，
as a result.
结果。
So what are we going to do in the coming weeks?
那么，在接下来的几周里，我们要做点啥呢？
So here we are in week zero.
所以这里是第0周。
We'll soon see why computers and computer scientists start counting,
我们很快就会明白为什么计算机和计算机科学家开始计数，
if you will, from 0.
如果你愿意，从 0.
But week 0, is one in which we explore computational thinking,
但是第 0 周，是我们探索计算思维的一周，
thinking like a computer, and starting to clean up your thought processes.
像计算机一样思考，并开始清理你的思维过程。
Getting you to think, to solve problems more methodically,
让你思考，更有条理地解决问题，
and then ultimately, translating that into code.
然后最终将其转换为代码。
And some of you might recognize this environment here, a.k.a.
你们中的一些人可能认识这里的环境，也就是
Scratch, coincidentally also from MIT.
也就是scratch，巧合也来自麻省理工学院。
You might have used it in grade school.
你可能在小学用过它。
We'll use it today and a little bit this weekend in the course's first homework
我们今天将使用它，本周末将在课程的第一个家庭作业中使用它
assignment or problem set.
作业或问题集。
But not so much to play around in a way that you
但与其说是以一种你的方式玩耍
might have if you did use it in yesteryears,
如果你在过去使用它，
but to explore ideas of computer science and programming
而是探索计算机科学和编程的思想
that we're going to use and reuse every week hereafter as well.
此后，我们每周也将使用和重用。
Thereafter, we're going to transition just next week
此后，我们将在下周过渡
to week one, so to speak.
可以这么说，到第一周。
Whereby, we'll introduce you to a more traditional language, a lower level
由此，我们将向你介绍一种更传统的语言，一种较低的水平
language, an older language called C. And in C, you're
语言，一种称为C的较旧语言。在C中，你是
going to use your keyboard, not so much your mouse and pointing and clicking,
去使用你的键盘，而不是你的鼠标和点击，
but you're going to write code that soto look a little something like this.
但是你要写的代码看起来有点像这样。
And if you've programmed before, you can probably
如果你以前撸过代码，你可能
glean what this is going to do.
知道这是怎么回事。
If you've never programmed before, which is the case for most of you,
如果你以前从未编程过，对你们大多数人来说都是这种情况，
this too will soon make sense.
这也很快就会有意义。
But this is the most canonical program that most any programmer ever writes
但这是大多数程序员编写的最规范的程序
called Hello, World, and indeed, that and all
叫Hello, World，事实上，这和所有
of the surrounding syntax above and below just that sentence Hello, World,
在该句子的上方和下方的周围语法Hello，World，
will soon make all the more sense.
很快就会变得更有意义。
You'll learn how to use industry-standard tools, so to speak.
可以说，你将学习如何使用行业标准工具。
Pictured here is something called Visual Studio code, or VS Code.
图为Visual Studio code或VS Code。
You'll use a cloud based version of it initially,
你最初将使用基于云的版本，
so you don't have to suffer with any technical difficulties
所以你不必忍受任何技术上的困难
or headaches like that.
或者像那样头痛。
It'll just work right off the bat, but we'll
它会马上工作，但我们会
use that to [INAUDIBLE] others ultimately
最终将其用于 [听不清] 其他人
to then explore ideas in computer science, principles that you can apply.
然后探索计算机科学的想法，你可以应用的原则。
And we'll take a look underneath the hood,
我们将看看引擎盖下，
so to speak, of your computer at your memory or RAM, Random Access Memory,
可以这么说，你的电脑在你的内存或RAM，随机存取存储器，
where all of the data is ultimately going to be stored.
所有的数据最终都将被存储在那里。
We'll also take a look thereafter at bugs.
之后我们还会看看bug。
A bug is a mistake in a program.
错误是程序中的错误。
Here is an actual bug in an actual computer in yesteryear,
这是过去实际计算机中的一个实际错误，
but we'll teach you how to debug programs, find your own mistakes,
但是我们会教你如何调试程序，发现自己的错误，
find others' mistakes, and improve that code as well.
找出其他人的错误，并改进代码。
We'll transition then to algorithms, step-by-step instructions
我们将过渡到算法，一步一步的指令
for solving some problems, which we'll touch on today too.
为了解决一些问题，我们今天也会涉及到。
And if you picture here, this is actually
如果你在这里想象一下，这实际上是
a pretty representative problem.
一个非常有代表性的问题。
Odds are, you haven't had to deal with something like this,
很有可能，你不必处理这样的事情，
but it's representative sorting, for instance.
但例如，它是代表性排序。
If you think of each of these small bars as being a small number,
如果你把这些小酒吧都看作是一个小数字，
each of the bigger bars is being a bigger number,
每个更大的酒吧都是一个更大的数字，
you might wonder, well, how could you as a human sort all of these bars,
你可能会想，作为一个人，你怎么能整理所有这些酒吧，
like get all the short bars over here, all the big bars over there?
就像把所有的短酒吧都拿到这里，所有的大酒吧都在那边？
Well, odds are, if you're like me, you would probably kind of eyeball it,
好吧，很有可能，如果你像我一样，你可能会盯着它，
and if you could physically interact, you
如果你能进行身体互动，你
might just start grabbing the smallest elements first,
可能只是先开始抓住最小的元素，
put them over on the left.
把它们放在左边。
Maybe grab the biggest elements, put them over on the right.
也许抓住最大的元素，把它们放在右边。
But what's your algorithm there?
但是你的算法是什么？
Like how would you teach someone younger than you, who's never done that before,
比如你怎么教一个比你年轻的人，以前从来没有这样做过，
how to do it?
怎么办？
How would you compel your Mac or PC or phone to do something like that?
你会如何强迫你的Mac或PC或手机做这样的事情？
You can't just wave your hand, and say, oh, figure it out.
你不能只是挥挥手，说，哦，想办法。
Move things around.
四处移动东西。
You have to express yourself more methodically.
你必须更有条理地表达自己。
So we'll translate even ideas like this into code too.
所以我们也会把这样的想法翻译成代码。
And that's what the Googles and others of the world
这就是谷歌和世界上其他人
are doing constantly, as they sort and organize the world's information.
他们不断地整理和组织世界的信息。
We'll use metaphors along the way, if it helps.
如果有帮助的话，我们会沿途使用隐喻。
We'll talk about your computer's memory as being like a postal address.
我们将讨论你的计算机的内存就像一个邮政地址。
Like every mailbox in the world has some form of postal address, street, city,
就像世界上每个邮箱都有某种形式的邮政地址，街道，城市，
state, country, and the like, and it turns out,
州、国家等等，事实证明，
that's how your Mac, your PC, and your phone also work.
这就是你的Mac，PC和手机的工作方式。
You've got a whole bunch of memory, like the picture before,
你有一大堆记忆，就像以前的照片，
but you can think of it really as individual mailboxes.
但是你可以将其视为单个邮箱。
And you can put anything you want in those mailboxes,
你可以把任何你想要的东西放在那些邮箱里，
and you can go to a mailbox to grab information that's from it.
你可以转到邮箱以从中获取信息。
So at the end of the day, that's really all your computer
所以归根结底，这真的是你的电脑
is doing with information.
正在做信息。
It's just organizing it, not into mailboxes per se,
它只是组织它，而不是邮箱本身，
but a term you probably know called bytes, for instance, instead.
但是，你可能知道的术语称为字节，例如。
We'll talk about problems that arise even nowadays.
我们将讨论当今出现的问题。
In fact, most of you are familiar with your Mac,
事实上，你们大多数人都熟悉你的Mac，
PC, even phone like spontaneously rebooting sometimes, crashing,
电脑，甚至手机有时会自发重启，崩溃，
the little annoying spinning beach ball or hourglass icon that happens.
发生的小烦人的旋转沙滩球或沙漏图标。
Like what is with that?
就像这是怎么回事？
Well, those are just bugs in programs that humans at Apple and Google
嗯，这些只是苹果和谷歌人类程序中的错误
and Microsoft and others, they screwed up, and they wrote buggy code.
微软和其他公司搞砸了，他们写了错误的代码。
And your computer, when it encounters those mistakes,
当你的电脑遇到这些错误时，
doesn't know what to do.
不知道该怎么办。
And so 9 times out of 10, so to speak, it just crashes or freezes
所以10次有9次，可以这么说，它只是崩溃或冻结
or the like, but that kind of stuff will make more sense.
或者类似的东西，但这种东西会更有意义。
So even the real world will make sense, and pictured here
所以即使是现实世界也会有意义，如图所示
are some lower level terms we'll eventually get to mid-semester.
是我们最终将在学期中期到达的一些较低级别的学期。
But generally speaking, when something is going this way,
但一般来说，当事情发展成这样时，
as per this arrow, and something is going this way, as per this arrow,
按照这个箭头，有些东西往这边走，按照这个箭头，
like that does not end well.
这样的结局并不好。
And that often is what happens when your computer crashes.
这通常是当你的电脑崩溃时发生的事情。
Someone's using memory up here, but someone else is using memory down here,
有人在这里使用内存，但有人在这里使用内存，
and then they're not really talking left hand and right hand.
然后他们不是真的在说左手和右手。
So that is just a high level overview of some of the problems we'll encounter,
因此，这只是我们将遇到的一些问题的高级概述，
but we'll focus to on data, ultimately.
但我们最终将专注于数据。
So pictured here is something fairly technical called a hash table.
所以这里图片是一个相当技术性的东西，叫做哈希表。
It's an amalgam of something we're going to soon call an array and also
这是一个混合体的东西，我们很快就会称之为数组，也
something we call a link to list.
我们称之为列表链接的东西。
And these are just fancy terms for describing
这些只是用来描述
how you can organize information even more flexibly
如何更灵活地组织信息
than just putting individual values in mailboxes.
而不仅仅是将单个值放入邮箱。
Like how could you build structures, like actual data structures
就像你怎么能建立结构，像实际的数据结构
so to speak, two-dimensional structures at that?
可以这么说，二维结构？
And so what you're seeing here is a glimpse, as some of you
所以你们在这里看到的是一瞥，就像你们中的一些人一样
might have recognized, of some Harry Potter universe names,
可能已经认识到，在一些哈利波特宇宙的名字中，
but they're organized somewhat alphabetically.
但它们的组织方式有点按字母顺序排列。
And notice, that any time there's multiple people with a name that
请注意，任何时候都有多个人的名字
starts with H, like Hermione, Harry, and Hagrid, well, they
从H开始，就像赫敏、哈利和海格一样，他们
can't all fit in that mailbox, if each of these squares along the left
不能全部放在那个邮箱里，如果左边的每个正方形
is that same mailbox.
是同一个邮箱。
So you have to chain them together.
所以你必须把它们链接在一起。
Well, you'll learn how to do that in code.
那么，你将学习如何在代码中做到这一点。
So that even if you get more data than you expect,
所以即使你得到的数据比你预期的要多，
if your business is booming, and you're some web-based business,
如果你的业务正在蓬勃发展，并且你是基于网络的业务，
how do you keep adding and adding information
如何不断添加和添加信息
to your software to actually keep up with it?
你的软件真的跟上了吗？
But this, again, is what code's going to soon look like, as soon as next week,
但是，这也是代码很快就会出现的样子，最快在下周，
in week one, this here being C, but we'll transition in a few weeks
在第一周，这里是C，但我们将在几周内过渡
to a more modern, higher level language, so to speak, called Python.
一种更现代、更高级的语言，可以这么说，叫做Python。
Indeed, the course very deliberately, back in my day and now this,
事实上，课程非常刻意，回到我的时代，现在这个，
introduces you first to C, which funny enough, many people don't
首先向你介绍C，这很有趣，很多人不
tend to program in certainly every day.
倾向于每天编程。
I use C, generally, September, October, November,
我用C，一般，9月，10月，11月，
December, when teaching CS50 itself.
12月，在教授CS50本身时。
But it's everywhere, nonetheless.
但它无处不在。
In fact, even today's other languages, with which you might be familiar,
事实上，即使今天你可能熟悉的其他语言，
like Python and Java and yet others still, you
就像Python和Java以及其他人一样，你
see this same primitive language underneath the hood,
在引擎盖下看到同样的原始语言，
because it's so darn fast.
因为它太快了。
And as you'll learn over the coming weeks,
在接下来的几周里，你会知道，
it really gives you access to and an understanding of what's
它真的让你接触和理解什么是
going on conceptually down here.
从概念上讲，这里。
So that thereafter, after CS50, when you're writing code,
因此，在CS50之后，当你编写代码时，
you can think at a very high level what's actually going on.
你可以在一个非常高的水平上思考到底发生了什么。
So in fact, in just a few weeks, what looks like this in C
所以事实上，在短短几周内，C中看起来像这样的
is going to look instead like this in Python.
在Python中会看起来像这样。
And you'll better understand what's going on underneath the hood,
你会更好地理解引擎盖下发生了什么，
and odds are, after this class, you'll reach for a language,
很有可能，在这堂课后，你会接触到一门语言，
like Python more frequently than C, but you're
像Python比C更频繁，但你
going to benefit from that bottom-up understanding thereof.
将受益于自下而上的理解。
Thereafter and towards term's end, we'll introduce you to a few other ideas,
此后，在学期结束时，我们将向你介绍一些其他想法，
like where do you put large amounts of data?
比如你把大量数据放在哪里？
In things called databases, not things like spreadsheets, like here,
在称为数据库的东西中，而不是像这里这样的电子表格，
but actual databases.
而是实际的数据库。
We're using those same kinds of data structures,
我们使用同样的数据结构，
you lay things out in an interesting way in memory.
你把事情以一种有趣的方式放在记忆中。
Thereafter, we'll transition to a very familiar environment
此后，我们将过渡到一个非常熟悉的环境。
that you and I use every day, the web.
你和我每天都在用到的，网络。
Like the web has become rather the User Interface, or UI,
就像网络已经变成了用户界面，或者UI，
that we use everywhere, on the laptops, desktops, and even mobile devices,
我们在笔记本电脑、台式机甚至移动设备上使用的，
nowadays.
现在。
Well, pictured here is a language called HTML.
嗯，这里图是一种叫做HTML的语言。
It's not a programming language.
它不是一种编程语言。
It's a markup language, and some of you might have made home pages
这是一种标记语言，你们中的一些人可能已经制作了主页
or portfolios in the past.
或过去的投资组合。
But you'll understand what's going on here, but more powerfully,
但你会明白这里发生了什么，但更有力的是，
you'll understand how the computer sees that same kind of code,
你将了解计算机如何看到相同类型的代码，
builds up a hierarchical family tree-type structure in memory.
在内存中构建分层家谱类型结构。
And then you can manipulate that tree with code
然后你可以用代码操作那棵树
to actually add more and more information, chat messages, anything
实际添加越来越多的信息，聊天消息，任何东西
on the screen that you like.
在你喜欢的屏幕上。
And finally, we'll tie all of this together
最后，我们将把所有这些联系在一起
by introducing what are called frameworks and libraries,
通过引入所谓的框架和库，
third-party code that makes it a lot easier to solve problems of interest
第三方代码，使解决感兴趣的问题变得更加容易
to you.
给你。
And so in particular, here, this is the very first web app
特别是，这是第一个网络应用程序。
that I myself made back in like 1997.
我自己在 1997 年做的。
I was part of the first-year intramural sports program,
我是第一年校内体育项目的一部分，
not as an athlete but as the programmer, and I was teaching myself
不是作为运动员，而是作为程序员，我在自学
how to build web applications.
如何构建 Web 应用程序。
I only knew C and maybe a little bit of something else at the time.
我当时只知道C，也许还知道一点别的东西。
But this became, for Harvard at least, the very first website
但至少对哈佛来说，这成为第一个网站。
for the first-year intramural sports program,
对于第一年的校内体育项目，
and it wasn't just a static website with links and images and the like.
它不仅仅是一个带有链接和图像等的静态网站。
It was interactive.
它是互动的。
You could register for sports.
你可以注册参加体育运动。
We could input exactly who was in a tournament bracket or the like,
我们可以准确地输入谁在锦标赛或类似的东西中，
and it could actually automatically keep track of this data.
它实际上可以自动跟踪这些数据。
So there too, after just three months of a class like this,
因此，在像这样的课程仅仅三个月之后，
you'll go from writing quite simply this week
本周你会从很简单的写作开始
and next Hello, World to building things like
下一个你好，世界来建造像这样的东西
this for whether it's web, mobile, or other platforms
无论是网络、移动还是其他平台
as well, if you so choose.
以及，如果你愿意的话。
But we'll get you off of the course's infrastructure, by the end of the term.
但我们会在学期结束前让你脱离课程的基础设施。
You won't be using any toy environments along the way.
一路上你不会使用任何玩具环境。
We'll empower you, ultimately, to write code after CS50, especially if this
我们将授权你，最终，在CS50之后编写代码，特别是如果这个
is the only CS class you ever take, on your own Mac or PC,
是你在自己的Mac或PC上使用的唯一CS类，
using the same software, but not the cloud-based version thereof.
使用相同的软件，但不使用基于云的版本。
But all of this software is itself free and can be used by you
但是所有这些软件本身都是免费的，你可以自己使用
powerfully after the course's own end.
在课程结束后有力地。
But along the way, as you may know, there
但一路上，你可能知道，那里
is this tradition within the class, particularly in healthy times,
这是班上的传统，尤其是在健康时期，
of a number of events that really brings people get together,
一系列真正让人们聚在一起的活动，
not just collaboratively and academically,
不仅仅是合作和学术，
but to just solve problems and generally engage with each other as well.
但只是为了解决问题，通常也要相互接触。
Coming up first, CS50 Puzzle Day, which is meant to be not jigsaw
首先，CS50拼图日，这不是拼图
puzzles but logic puzzles that require no prior experience
谜题，但逻辑谜题，不需要事先经验
with computer science or programming.
计算机科学或编程。
But it's just an opportunity to quietly work on a packet of puzzles
但这只是一个安静地研究一包谜题的机会
with some number of friends for prizes and more.
与一些朋友一起获得奖品等等。
Later in the semester, once you tackle your final projects,
在学期后期，一旦你完成了你的期末项目，
the capstone of the course, where we don't give you a homework to write,
课程的顶点，我们不给你写作业，
you yourself come up with something to build.
你自己想出了一些东西来建造。
We'll get together generally
我们一般会聚在一起
wrap up around 7:00 AM, if you so choose.
如果您愿意，请在上午 7：00 左右结束。
And it's an evening, a 12-hour opportunity to collaborate with
这是一个晚上，一个12小时的合作机会
classmates on your very own final project, in a large space on campus,
同学们在你自己的最终项目中，在校园的一个大空间里，
that ends--
这就结束了——
if you're awake with us-- at 5:00 AM.
如果你和我们一起醒来 - 在早上5：00。
We can hop on some CS50 shuttles and go down the road for some pancakes at IHOP
我们可以跳上一些CS50班车，然后在IHOP的路上吃一些煎饼
around 6:00.
6：00左右。
Of course-- of course, this is
当然——当然，这是
but it's an opportunity finally to lead into what's
但这是一个最终进入世界的机会
called the CS50 fair, which is an end of semester celebration, an exhibition,
叫做CS50博览会，这是学期结束的庆祝活动，一个展览，
of everything that you'll accomplish over the coming months.
在接下来的几个月里，你将完成的一切。
And in fact, pictured here are some of your predecessors in healthy times.
事实上，这张照片是你在健康时期的一些前辈。
The CS50 fair allows you to come with your laptop or phone
CS50博览会允许你携带笔记本电脑或手机
and exhibits of students, faculty, and staff across campus
以及校园内学生、教职员工的展览
put together something in person and on video
亲自和视频组合一些东西
that people can delight in seeing, as you exhibit what it is you created
人们可以很高兴看到，因为你展示了你创造的东西
and what you learned over the course of the several weeks.
以及你在几周内学到的东西。
And ultimately, a chance to just share and inspire others as well.
最终，也有机会分享和激励他人。
And you'll all walk home, ultimately, with your own I took
你们都会走回家，最终，我带着你们自己的
CS50 T-shirts saying as much as well.
CS50 T 恤也说了很多。
So with that high level overview of the course,
因此，有了课程的高级概述，
I propose that we begin to take a look at what computer science itself is
我建议我们开始看看计算机科学本身是什么。
and what it is we're going to be doing over the next several weeks
以及我们将在未来几周内做什么
at this lower level [INAUDIBLE] too.
在这个较低的水平[听不清]也是如此。
So what is computer science?
那么什么是计算机科学呢？
Right?
右？
If you're maybe like me or new people like my friends in high school,
如果你像我一样，或者像我高中时的朋友一样的新人，
you probably assume that it means programming.
你可能认为这意味着编程。
And that's absolutely a big part of it for a lot of people, because with code,
对于很多人来说，这绝对是其中很重要的一部分，因为对于代码，
you can write, you can express ideas, and solve actual problems,
你会写作，你可以表达想法，解决实际问题，
especially involving data.
特别是涉及数据。
But computer science itself is really the study of information, if you will.
但计算机科学本身实际上是对信息的研究，如果你愿意的话。
How do you represent it, and how do you actually process it?
你如何表示它，你如何实际处理它？
And in that sense, computational thinking
从这个意义上说，计算思维
is just the application of ideas from computer science, a course like this,
只是计算机科学思想的应用，像这样的课程，
to problems of interest to you, again, in the arts, humanities, sciences,
再次，在艺术、人文、科学方面，你感兴趣的问题，
social sciences, whatever the domain of interest is to you.
社会科学，无论你感兴趣的领域是什么。
So with that, if computer science is all about information and with it
因此，如果计算机科学是关于信息的，那么它就是这样。
the solving of problems, well, what does it actually mean to solve a problem?
解决问题，那么，解决问题到底意味着什么？
Let's see if we can't propose a model into which all of the lessons learned
让我们看看我们是否不能提出一个将所有经验教训都纳入其中的模型
will ultimately follow.
最终将随之而来。
And I'd propose that this is problem solving.
我建议这是解决问题的方法。
You've got some input, which is like the problem you want to solve.
你有一些输入，就像你想要解决的问题一样。
The goal is to solve it.
目标是解决它。
So that's the so-called output, and then somewhere
这就是所谓的输出，然后在某个地方
in here, the proverbial black box, is some kind of secret sauce
在这里，众所周知的黑匣子，是某种秘密调味料
that gets the work done.
这样就可以完成工作。
And in the coming months, we'll have to decide, well, how are we
在接下来的几个月里，我们将不得不决定，好吧，我们如何
going to represent these inputs and outputs, and really, how do we code up?
将表示这些输入和输出，实际上，我们如何编码？
How do we write solutions for what it is that's solving the problem of interest
我们如何为解决感兴趣的问题编写解决方案
to us?
给我们？
So when it comes to representation of information, like there's a lot of ways
因此，当涉及到信息的表示时，有很多方法。
we can do this.
我们可以做到这一点。
And for instance, if the problem at hand quite
例如，如果手头的问题相当
simply is to take attendance at the beginning of class,
简单来说就是在上课开始时就考勤，
on the first day of school, well, how could we go about doing this?
在开学的第一天，好吧，我们怎么能做到这一点呢？
Well, we could actually use a system called unary.
好吧，我们实际上可以使用一个称为一元的系统。
Well, what is that?
嗯，那是什么？
Well, that's a fancy way of saying 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, maybe 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
嗯，这是一种说1,2,3,4,5，也许是6,7,8,9,10的奇特方式。
And I can use my digits--
我可以使用我的数字——
pun intended-- on my fingers to actually count everyone up.
双关语 - 在我的手指上实际上计算每个人。
And eventually, you need toes and whatnots, if you have to count so high.
最终，你需要脚趾什么的，如果你必须数得这么高的话。
But unary is a very simple system of using
但是一元是一个非常简单的使用系统
a single symbol, a human finger in this case, to just solve some problem,
一个符号，在这种情况下是人类的手指，只是解决一些问题，
like counting the number of people in the room.
就像数房间里的人数一样。
Let's make this slightly more technical for a moment, a little more mathy.
让我们暂时让这个稍微技术性更强一点，更数学一点。
That's just called base-1, where the base under which you're operating
这就是所谓的base-1，你在其中操作的基础
has one digit in it, like literally a human finger, and maybe
里面有一个数字，就像字面上的人类手指，也许
multiple such fingers, if you need to count higher.
多个这样的手指，如果你需要数得更高。
But of course, most of you, if not all of you,
但是，当然，你们中的大多数人，如果不是你们所有人，
generally, vaguely know that computers use something other than unary--
一般来说，模糊地知道计算机使用非一元的东西——
and even you and I probably don't use this that often-- they
甚至你和我可能也不经常使用它——他们
use what language or alphabet instead.
请改用哪种语言或字母表。
Yeah.
是的。
So binary, so binary is indeed the system that computers somehow use.
如此二进制，如此二进制确实是计算机以某种方式使用的系统。
So in this case, bi implying two, and so computers have two digits,
所以在这种情况下，bi 意味着两个，所以计算机有两个数字，
it turns out, at their disposal.
事实证明，由他们支配。
And in fact, if you've ever heard the technical term bit,
事实上，如果你曾经听说过技术术语bit，
which is like a smaller version of a byte-- more on that soon.
这就像一个字节的较小版本——很快就会有更多内容。
Well, a binary digit is the origin of that term "Bit,"
好吧，二进制数字是术语“位”的起源，
because if you get rid of some of the letters, and are left from binary digit
因为如果你去掉一些字母，并且从二进制数字中留下
with just B-I-T, thus is a bit.
只有 B-I-T，因此有点。
A bit is just a 0 and 1.
位只是 0 和 1。
It's two more digits than you might have on your own finger,
它比你自己手指上的数字多两个数字，
and of course, it's fewer though than you and I have.
当然，它比你我少。
You and I typically use, as humans, the decimal system.
作为人类，你和我通常使用十进制系统。
Dec meaning 10, because you and I generally use 0 through 9.
Dec的意思是10，因为你和我通常使用0到9。
So on the one hand--
所以一方面——
another pun intended-- you've got unary.
另一个双关语的意思是——你有一元。
Computers use binary.
计算机使用二进制。
We humans generally think and talk in terms of decimal.
我们人类通常以十进制来思考和说话。
But at the end of the day, these are fundamentally
但归根结底，这些从根本上说是
going to be the same thing, which is to say
将是同样的事情，也就是说
that it's all pretty accessible to us.
这一切都对我们来说很容易获得。
Even if you're not a computer person, I daresay you're about to be.
即使你不是一个计算机人，我敢说你即将成为一个。
So what is a bit?
那么什么是位呢？
Well, a bit then is a 0 or a 1.
好吧，那么一点是 0 或 1。
That is a so-called binary digit.
这就是所谓的二进制数字。
But how do computers only speak in binary?
但是计算机怎么只用二进制说话呢？
How do they solve problems, represent information, using only binary?
他们如何解决问题，仅使用二进制来表示信息？
Well, at the end of the day, if they want to represent 0 and 1,
好吧，归根结底，如果他们想代表 0 和 1，
we need to do so physically somehow.
我们需要以某种方式在身体上这样做。
And I daresay that maybe the simplest way to think about a bit, a 0 or a 1,
我敢说，也许是思考一点的最简单方法，0或1，
is like a light bulb.
就像一个灯泡。
And so by human convention, let's just assume that if you were a computer,
因此，按照人类的惯例，让我们假设如果你是一台计算机，
be it a laptop, desktop, phone, or the like,
无论是笔记本电脑、台式机、手机还是类似产品，
and you want to represent the number 0, you
你想代表数字0，你
know what, you just keep the light switch off.
知道吗，你只要把电灯开关关掉。
You keep a light bulb off.
你关掉一个灯泡。
If by contrast, you're that same computer,
如果相比之下，你们是同一台计算机，
and you want to represent the number 1, you
你想代表数字 1，你
take that same switch, that same light bulb, and just turn it on.
拿起同样的开关，同样的灯泡，然后打开它。
So a light bulb that's on represents a 1, and a light bulb that's off
因此，打开的灯泡表示 1，而灯泡表示关闭
represents a 0.
表示 0。
So why is this relevant to computers?
那么，为什么这与计算机有关呢？
Well, at the end of the day, you and I are charging our laptops or phones
好吧，归根结底，你和我正在为我们的笔记本电脑或手机充电
at night.
在晚上。
So there's some physical resource being replenished there, whether you're
所以那里有一些物质资源正在补充，无论你是
on battery or some power cord.
使用电池或某些电源线。
And so inside of a computer are just thousands,
所以在计算机内部只有数千个，
millions of tiny little switches, nowadays.
如今，数以百万计的微小开关。
You can think of them metaphorically as light bulbs,
你可以把它们比喻成灯泡，
but they don't actually shine light.
但它们实际上并没有发光。
But there are tiny, tiny little switches,
但是有微小的开关，
and those switches, if you've ever heard the term, are just called transistors.
这些开关，如果你听说过这个词，就叫做晶体管。
So like computers have millions of transistors that can either be flipped
所以就像计算机有数百万个晶体管一样，这些晶体管可以翻转。
on to represent 1's or flipped off to represent 0's.
on 表示 1，或翻转表示 0。
And from that very simple mechanism, electricity is there,
从这个非常简单的机制中，电就在那里，
or it's not, a 1 or a 0.
或者不是，1 或 0。
Computers can actually count, obviously, from 0 to 1,
显然，计算机实际上可以从0数到1，
but it turns out, even higher, if they use a little more electricity as well.
但事实证明，如果他们也使用更多的电力，甚至更高。
So how might I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me go ahead and propose that I just grab one of our own light bulbs
好吧，让我继续提议我只拿一个我们自己的灯泡
here on stage.
在舞台上。
This one is off.
这个是关闭的。
So for instance, if this were miniaturized inside of your Mac, PC,
因此，例如，如果这是在你的Mac，PC内部小型化的，
or phone, this would be a transistor, and indeed, here's
或者手机，这将是一个晶体管，事实上，这是
the little switch on the bottom.
底部的小开关。
And if your computer wants to represent a 0, it just leaves the switch off,
如果你的计算机想要表示 0，它只需关闭开关，
and the light is not shining.
而且光线不闪耀。
If you want to represent a 1, well now, I've counted as high
如果你想代表一个1，那么现在，我已经数了
as 1, because the switch is now on.
作为 1，因为开关现在打开。
I've grabbed a little electricity.
我抢了一点电。
I'm holding on to it inside of the computer,
我在电脑里面抓着它，
and so now I see that this is a 1.
所以现在我看到这是一个 1。
All right, but unfortunately, with just one switch, one light bulb,
好吧，但不幸的是，只有一个开关，一个灯泡，
I can only count from 0 to 1.
我只能从 0 数到 1。
How do I count out higher, might you think, intuitively?
我如何直观地计算出更高的数字？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Say it again.
DAVID J. MALAN：再说一遍。
AUDIENCE: More lightbulbs.
观众：更多的灯泡。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so more light bulbs.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，所以更多的灯泡。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
Let me just grab something to put these on, so I can use a few of them
让我拿一些东西来穿上这些，这样我就可以使用其中的一些
at a time.
一次。
And let me propose that here, instead of having just one light bulb,
让我在这里提出，而不是只有一个灯泡，
let me give myself maybe three in total.
让我给自己总共三个。
So all of them are initially off, and if you think of this in miniature form,
所以它们最初都是关闭的，如果你把它想象成微型形式，
in your mind's eye, this is like a computer with three transistors.
在你的脑海中，这就像一台有三个晶体管的计算机。
Three switches representing now the number you and I know as 0.
三个开关代表现在你和我所知道的数字 0。
Why?
为什么？
They're just all off.
他们都关掉了。
So how does a computer go about representing the number 1?
那么计算机如何表示数字1呢？
Well, it turns on one of these light bulbs.
好吧，它打开其中一个灯泡。
And how does the computer represent the number 2?
计算机如何表示数字 2？
Well, you might think, if I may, you just turn on a second light bulb.
好吧，你可能会想，如果可以的话，你只要打开第二个灯泡。
And if you might think, how does a computer represent 3?
如果你可能会想，计算机如何代表 3？
You just turn on the third light bulb.
你只需打开第三个灯泡。
And so as such, with three bits, a computer
因此，用三个位，一台计算机
would seem to be able to count from 0 on up to 1, 2, 3.
似乎可以从 0 数到 1、2、3。
But it turns out, if I'm a little smarter here,
但事实证明，如果我在这里更聪明一点，
I can actually count higher than that.
我实际上可以数得比这更高。
Why?
为什么？
Well, I'm just considering the combination of bulbs being on here.
好吧，我只是在考虑这里的灯泡组合。
What if I do something like this?
如果我做这样的事情怎么办？
This is still 0, I will claim, but what if I propose now that this
这仍然是 0，我会声称，但如果我现在提议这个
will be how a computer represents 1--
将是计算机如何表示 1--
on, off, off.
开，关，关。
This, though, will be how the computer represents 2.
不过，这将是计算机表示 2 的方式。
Notice, I didn't turn on the same two.
注意，我没有打开相同的两个。
I'm just turning on the one in the middle.
我只是打开中间的那个。
This I now claim will be how a computer represents 3.
我现在声称这将是计算机如何表示 3.
This is going to be-- in just a second--
这将在一秒钟内
how a computer represents the number we know as 4,
计算机如何将我们所知道的数字表示为 4，
and yet, I'm still only using three bulbs.
然而，我仍然只使用三个灯泡。
This is going to be the number the computer represents as 5.
这将是计算机表示为 5 的数字。
This is going to be how the computer represents the number 6,
这将是计算机表示数字 6 的方式，
and then lastly, it turns out, with three light bulbs,
最后，事实证明，有三个灯泡，
if you're smart about it, you can count it seems as high as 7.
如果你对它很聪明，你可以数它似乎高达7。
Now, even if you lost track of what I was turning on and why,
现在，即使你忘记了我打开了什么以及为什么，
I claim there were eight different patterns, from all of them
我声称有八种不同的模式，从所有这些模式中
off to all of them on.
对他们所有人开放。
But notice that I started to permute them.
但请注意，我开始排列它们。
I took into account which ones were on and which ones were off.
我考虑了哪些是打开的，哪些是关闭的。
Why, though, do these represent the numbers we know as 0 through 7?
但是，为什么这些代表我们所知道的数字 0 到 7？
Well, let me go ahead, and maybe let's do this.
好吧，让我继续，也许让我们这样做。
Instead of just considering there to be light bulbs,
而不是仅仅考虑有灯泡，
let's assign some special significance to each of them, based on where it is.
让我们根据它们的位置为它们中的每一个分配一些特殊意义。
And maybe for this, could we get maybe three volunteers, three volunteer?
也许为此，我们能不能找三个志愿者，三个志愿者？
OK.
还行。
You're being volunteered.
你被志愿服务了。
OK.
还行。
Come on up.
来吧。
If you want to go over to the stage there.
如果你想去那里的舞台。
Yeah.
是的。
You want to come on up as well, and over here as well.
你也想上来，也想在这里。
So there are some stairs on either end.
所以两端都有一些楼梯。
Maybe a round of applause for our first volunteers of term.
也许为我们学期的第一批志愿者鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好吧。
So you want to be our number 1, and if you want to go ahead and stand
所以你想成为我们的第一，如果你想继续前进并站起来
roughly right here.
大致就在这里。
How about do you want to be number 2?
你想成为第二名怎么样？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
观众：是的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Come on over right to the right of here,
DAVID J. MALAN：从右边过来，
and you'll be number 4, it turns out.
事实证明，你会成为第 4 名。
If you want to come over here, on this end,
如果你想来这里，在这一端，
let's give you all a moment to introduce yourselves briefly to your classmates,
让我们给大家一点时间向同学们简单介绍一下自己，
if you'd like.
如果你愿意。
AUDIENCE: Hi.
观众：你好。
I'm Ellie.
我是艾莉。
I'm a senior.
我是大四学生。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice to meet.
DAVID J. MALAN：很高兴认识。
AUDIENCE: I'm [? Rayhanna, ?] and I'm a first year.
观众：我是[？雷哈娜，？我是一年级的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Welcome.
DAVID J. MALAN：欢迎。
AUDIENCE: Hi.
观众：你好。
I'm Joseph, and I am a first year.
我是约瑟夫，我是一年级的学生。
DAVID J. MALAN: Welcome.
DAVID J. MALAN：欢迎。
All right.
好吧。
So so glad to have all three of you up here.
很高兴你们三个都在这里。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Let me propose now that we'd like you three
现在让我提议，我们想要你们三个
to represent how about the number 0.
来表示数字 0 怎么样。
And I claim now that if each of you now represents a switch,
我现在声称，如果你们每个人现在代表一个开关，
you have fancier light bulbs now.
你现在有更漂亮的灯泡了。
One is a 1.
一个是 1。
One is a 2.
一个是2。
One is a 4, but each of you is still just has a switch
一个是4，但你们每个人仍然只有一个开关
on the bottom, in fact, of your plastic devices.
事实上，在你的塑料设备的底部。
I claim these three volunteers are representing the number 0.
我声称这三名志愿者代表数字0。
Let me ask you all now, how might you represent the number 1?
现在让我问大家，你们如何代表数字1？
How should you cooperate here?
你应该如何在这里合作？
OK.
还行。
So we would have on, off, off, which I think
所以我们会开，关，关，我想
matches what I did with my three light bulbs
与我用三个灯泡所做的相匹配
as well, if you want to go and turn yours off.
同样，如果你想去关掉你的。
How might you three represent the number 2?
你们三个如何代表数字2？
OK, so off, on, off now, from right to left.
好的，所以关闭，现在打开，关闭，从右到左。
How would you three represent the number 3?
你们三个如何代表数字3？
Ah, so that's why my two light bulbs went on at the end.
啊，这就是为什么我的两个灯泡在最后亮了。
How would you three represent the number 4?
你们三个如何代表数字4？
Perfect.
完善。
Number 5, number 6, and number 7?
5号、6号和7号？
All right, and give us one more.
好吧，再给我们一个。
How would you represent 8?
你会如何代表 8？
AUDIENCE: We can't.
观众：我们不能。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
You can't.
你不能。
How about then one more volunteer, one more volunteer?
那么再多一个志愿者，再多一个志愿者怎么样？
OK.
还行。
Come on up.
来吧。
All right.
好吧。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
AUDIENCE: My name is [? Moin. ?]
观众：我的名字是[？莫因。?]
DAVID J. MALAN: If you want to say it into there.
DAVID J. MALAN：如果你想说出来的话。
AUDIENCE: My name is [? Moin. ?]
观众：我的名字是[？莫因。?]
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, [? and Moin, ?] you're
DAVID J. MALAN：好吧，[？和Moin，？]你是
going to be number 8, and if now you all-- actually, let's make this
将成为第8名，如果现在你们都 - 实际上，让我们制作这个
how would you represent number 8, all collectively, as 4 bits
你将如何将数字 8 全部统称为 4 位
or for switches?
还是开关？
OK, 8, and now lastly, give me 15.
好的，8，现在最后，给我15。
Everyone's awkwardly doing arithmetic in their head, oh, using unary.
每个人都笨拙地在脑子里做算术，哦，使用一元。
Yeah.
是的。
Is that everyone--
难道大家——
Yes.
是的。
OK.
还行。
Round of applause.
掌声响起。
OK.
还行。
Thank you all.
谢谢大家。
If you want to leave your numbers over here,
如果你想把你的号码留在这里，
we have a CS50 stress ball for you, but thank you for volunteering.
我们为你准备了一个CS50压力球，但感谢你的志愿服务。
You can turn those numbers off and leave them over here.
你可以关闭这些号码并将它们留在这里。
So thank you.
所以谢谢你。
So how do we go about-- how do we go from there to creating these patterns?
那么我们如何去做——我们如何从那里开始创造这些模式呢？
Well, even though we still had three bits, initially, and three switches,
好吧，即使我们最初仍然有三个位和三个开关，
later four bits and four switches, ultimately, we still
后来四位四开关，最终，我们仍然
used the same approach fundamentally to actually representing information.
从根本上使用相同的方法来实际表示信息。
And now why were they those patterns, and why
现在为什么它们会是这些模式，为什么
did I very deliberately have our volunteers line up in that way?
我是否非常刻意让我们的志愿者以这种方式排队？
Well, I wanted them using base-2, a.k.a.
好吧，我希望他们使用base-2，又名。
binary, but with binary there comes certain rules.
二进制，但二进制有一定的规则。
And even if you're not familiar with binary
即使你不熟悉二进制
beyond that it exists and relates somehow to computers,
除此之外，它存在并以某种方式与计算机相关，
it's actually pretty much identical to the system you and I use
它实际上与你和我使用的系统几乎相同
every day, known as base 10, a.k.a.
每天，被称为基地10，又名
decimal.
十进制。
So let's consider, if you will, by rewinding to primary school for just
因此，如果你愿意的话，让我们考虑一下，只需倒回小学
a moment, like how decimal works.
一会儿，就像十进制的工作原理。
And you'll see that even if you're not a computer person, you actually are.
你会发现，即使你不是一个计算机人，你实际上是。
You just have to tweak your mental model ever so slightly.
你只需要稍微调整一下你的心智模型。
So here is the number that you're probably viewing as 123,
所以这是你可能看到的数字是123，
but why is that?
但这是为什么呢？
Well, it's not really 123.
好吧，这不是真正的 123。
This is just a pattern of three symbols on the screen, 1, 2, 3, and your mind
这只是屏幕上三个符号的图案，1,2,3和你的头脑
is rapidly assigning mathematical meaning to them, 123, but why is that?
正在迅速地赋予他们数学意义， 123， 但为什么呢？
Well, if you're like me, you probably learned back in the day,
好吧，如果你像我一样，你可能在当年学到，
when you have a three-digit number like, this the rightmost number
当你有一个三位数的数字时，这是最右边的数字
is in the 1's place, the middle digit is the 10's place,
在 1 的位置，中间数字是 10 的位置，
the leftmost digit is in the 100's place, and why is that relevant?
最左边的数字在 100 的位置，为什么这很重要？
Well, if you then quickly do some mental math, as you and I just do instantly
好吧，如果你然后快速做一些心算，就像你和我一样立即做
nowadays, that just means 100 times 1 plus 10 times 2 plus 1 times
如今，这只意味着 100 乘以 1 加 10 乘以 2 加 1 倍
3, of course, 100 plus 20 plus 3 gives us the number you and I know as 123.
3，当然，100加20加3给了我们你我都知道的数字123。
But beyond that, how do we get to just two digits instead of as many as 9
但除此之外，我们如何达到两位数而不是多达 9 位
in the decimal system?
在十进制系统中？
Well, let's generalize this.
好吧，让我们概括一下。
In the decimal system, you and I know, if we've
在十进制系统中，你和我知道，如果我们有
got three digits represented by these hashes here,
在这里得到了由这些哈希表示的三位数字，
yes, it's the 1's place, 10's place, 100's place,
是的，这是1的地方，10的地方，100的地方，
and if we keep going 1,000's, 10,000's, and so forth, but why is that?
如果我们继续前进1000个，10000个，等等，但为什么会这样呢？
Well, base terminology is now a little more germane.
好吧，基本术语现在更加相关。
That's technically the 10 to the 0th column, the 10 to the 1, 10 to the 2.
从技术上讲，这是 10 到 0 列，10 到 1,10 到 2。
So these are powers of 10, where 10 is your base.
所以这些是 10 的幂，其中 10 是你的基数。
Computers just simplify things a little bit,
计算机只是把事情简单了一点，
because computers, at the end of the day,
因为计算机，归根结底，
only have access to electricity, on or off.
只能用电，开或关。
They don't have access to 10 different types of electricity, just 2,
他们没有 10 种不同类型的电力，只有 2 种，
on or off, if you will.
打开或关闭，如果你愿意的话。
Well, they just use a different base.
好吧，他们只是使用不同的底座。
And the rightmost digit would be in the so-called 2 to the 0ths.
最右边的数字将是所谓的 2 到 0th。
Then the middle digit is 2 to the 1.
然后中间数字是 2 到 1。
The left most is 2 to the 2, a.k.a.
最左边的是 2 到 2，也就是
1's place, 2's place, 4's place, and as we kept going, 8,
1的地方，2的地方，4的地方，当我们继续前进时，8，
and if we keep going, 16, 32, 64, 128, and so forth,
如果我们继续前进，16、32、64、128等等，
but the idea is fundamentally the same.
但这个想法基本上是相同的。
So why is this how the computer represents
那么为什么计算机是这样表示的呢？
the number you and I know is 0?
你我认识的数字是0？
Well, off, off, off, from right to left or in this case left to right,
好吧，关闭，关闭，关闭，从右到左，或者在这种情况下从左到右，
is just 0.
仅为 0。
Why?
为什么？
Because that's 4 times 0 plus 2 times 0 plus 1 times 0 is, of course, 0.
因为那是 4 乘以 0 加 2 乘以 0 加 1 乘以 0 当然是 0。
This is why 001 represents 1.
这就是为什么 001 代表 1。
This is why 010 represents 2 and 3 and 4 and 5 and 6 and 7 on up.
这就是为什么 010 代表 2 和 3 和 4 和 5 和 6 和 7 向上。
And why did we need a 4th bit to represent 8?
为什么我们需要第 4 位来表示 8？
Well, we kind of needed to carry the 1, so to speak,
好吧，我们有点需要携带 1，可以这么说，
using our familiar human terminology.
使用我们熟悉的人类术语。
But for that we need a 4th bit, another transistor, and this
但为此，我们需要第 4 位，另一个晶体管，以及这个
now represents the number 8.
现在代表数字 8。
And that's why we ended with on-- from left to right-- off, off, off.
这就是为什么我们以开 - 从左到右 - 关闭，关闭，关闭结束。
So I keep saying on and off, or the light bulb is on or off,
所以我一直在说开和关，或者灯泡开或关，
but really, I just mean 1 or 0.
但实际上，我的意思是 1 或 0。
And so computers and we humans think of things digitally
因此，计算机和我们人类以数字方式思考事物
as just being 0's and 1's, but mechanically,
只是 0 和 1，但机械地，
you can think of it indeed is these light bulbs.
你可以想到它确实是这些灯泡。
Now, a bit is not very useful.
现在，一点不是很有用。
Even 3 bits, 4 bits, not that useful.
即使是3位，4位，也不是那么有用。
You can count to 7 or 15, generally speaking,
一般来说，你可以数到7或15，
bytes are a more useful unit of measure.
字节是更有用的度量单位。
And anyone familiar how many bits is in a byte?
有人知道一个字节有多少位吗？
Yeah.
是的。
So 8 bits are in a byte.
所以 8 位在一个字节中。
You can think of it as an octet equivalently.
你可以将其等效地视为八位字节。
In some contexts, there are nuances there, but think of a byte
在某些情况下，那里有细微差别，但想想一个字节
as just being 8 bits, and that's just a more useful measure.
因为只是 8 位，这只是一个更有用的措施。
So what does this mean in real terms?
那么这实际上意味着什么？
So if you've ever downloaded like a music file or a photograph or a video,
因此，如果你曾经下载过音乐文件、照片或视频，
those are measured in bytes.
这些以字节为单位。
Probably not small numbers of bytes, probably
可能不是少量字节，可能
kilobytes for thousands of bytes, megabytes for millions of bytes,
千字节表示数千字节，兆字节表示数百万字节，
gigabytes for billions of bytes, especially for video.
数十亿字节的千兆字节，尤其是视频。
That just means you have a lot of patterns
这只是意味着你有很多模式
of 8 bits, some combination of 0's and 1's on your computer's hard drive.
8 位，计算机硬盘驱动器上 0 和 1 的某种组合。
Here then, with a byte of bits, 8 bits, is how a computer would typically
在这里，用一个字节的位，8位，是计算机通常的样子
represent the number 0.
表示数字 0。
And if that same computer uses all 8 of its bits,
如果同一台计算机使用其所有 8 位，
its full byte, to change it to 1--
它的完整字节，将其更改为 1--
anyone who's quick with math or have seen this before,
任何数学很快或以前看过这个的人，
how high can a computer count with 8 bits or 1?
一台计算机用 8 位或 1 位可以计数多高？
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插话]
Yeah, 255.
是的，255。
Why is that?
为什么？
Well, we're not going to turn this into a constant math exercise.
好吧，我们不会把它变成一个持续的数学练习。
Indeed, after today, we're not really going
事实上，今天之后，我们真的不会去
to think about or talk about bits at this low level.
在这个低层次上思考或谈论位。
But this is the 1's place, 2's, 4's, 8s, 16, 32, 64, 128,
但这是 1 的地方，2、4、8、16、32、64、128，
and if I do all of that math from left to right, that indeed gives me 255.
如果我从左到右做所有这些数学，那确实给了我255。
It ignores how we might represent negative numbers, but perhaps
它忽略了我们如何表示负数，但也许
more on those some other day.
更多关于那些其他日子。
But computers, of course, do so much more
但是，计算机当然做得更多。
than numbers and math and all this low level stuff.
比数字和数学以及所有这些低级的东西。
We send text messages, write documents, emails, and the like.
我们发送短信，撰写文档，电子邮件等。
So how might a computer represent something like the letter A?
那么计算机如何表示类似字母A的东西呢？
I claim, at the end of the day, your Mac, your PC,
我声称，归根结底，你的Mac，你的PC，
your phone just has lots of transistors, lots of switches
你的手机有很多晶体管，很多开关
that it can use in units of 8, in units of bytes.
它可以以 8 为单位，以字节为单位使用。
How, though, if it's already using those patterns of 0's and 1's
但是，如果它已经在使用0和1的模式，如何
apparently to represent numbers from 0 on up,
显然是为了表示从 0 开始的数字，
how do you go about representing letters of the alphabet, might you think?
你怎么去表示字母表中的字母，你会觉得吗？
Yeah?
是的？
OK.
还行。
So we could assign a number to every letter.
因此，我们可以为每个字母分配一个数字。
OK.
还行。
So let me just conjecture, well, let's just
所以让我猜想，好吧，让我们只是
call A 0, for simplicity, B 1, C 2, and now let me play devil's advocate.
叫A0，为了简单起见，B 1，C 2，现在让我扮演魔鬼的代言人。
OK, how do I now represent 0 or 1 or 2?
好的，我现在如何表示 0 或 1 或 2？
Well, we've maybe created a problem for ourselves,
好吧，我们可能为自己制造了一个问题，
if now we have to steal some numbers to represent letters.
如果现在我们必须窃取一些数字来表示字母。
We kind of have to pick a lane, but there's a solution to that
我们必须选择一条车道，但有一个解决方案。
too that we'll see.
我们也会看到。
And it turns out the world is not quite as simple as A being 0.
事实证明，世界并不像A为0那么简单。
A typically is represented, by computers everywhere, phones everywhere,
A通常由无处不在的计算机，无处不在的电话来表示，
with the number 65, the decimal number 65.
数字 65，十进制数字 65。
Using 8 bits, if we turn some of the 0's to 1's, let me just stipulate,
使用 8 位，如果我们把一些 0 变成 1，让我规定，
you can represent the letter A using 8 bits, by turning certain ones on
你可以使用 8 位表示字母 A，方法是打开某些位
and certain ones off, but we will try not to focus on that binary level
和某些关闭，但我们将尽量不关注二进制级别
too much.
太多了。
So if A is 65, it turns out that B is going to be 66,
所以如果 A 是 65，那么事实证明 B 将是 66，
and C is going to be 67, and so forth, and so where does that get us?
C将是67，依此类推，那么这会把我们带到哪里去？
Well, it turns out there's a whole system that maps numbers to letters.
好吧，事实证明有一个完整的系统可以将数字映射到字母。
And here, as I alluded to verbally a moment ago,
在这里，正如我刚才口头提到的那样，
is the pattern of 0's and 1's via which you'd represent 65.
是 0 和 1 的模式，通过它表示 65。
And just quick check here, we won't constantly
只是在这里快速检查，我们不会经常
do math 1's place, that's easy, 2's, 4's, 8's, 16's, 32's, 64's place.
做数学 1 的地方，这很容易，2、4、8、16、32、64 的地方。
So 64 plus 1 gives us 65.
所以 64 加 1 得到 65。
So once I do that, how do I get to all of the others?
因此，一旦我这样做了，我如何找到所有其他人？
Well, it turns out a bunch of Americans years ago came up with this
好吧，事实证明，几年前一群美国人想出了这个
ASCII, the American Standard Code for Information Interchange.
ASCII，美国信息交换标准代码。
Now, what does that mean?
现在，这意味着什么？
Well, it's just an acronym describing what really you proposed,
好吧，这只是一个首字母缩略词，描述了你真正提出的内容，
a mapping between numbers and letters, not quite as simple as 0, 1, 2.
数字和字母之间的映射，不像 0、1、2 那么简单。
Starts at 65, 66, 67 for capital letters,
大写字母从 65、66、67 开始，
but here are most of the letters in use today, at least with this system.
但这是今天使用的大多数字母，至少在这个系统中是这样。
So this is just a big chart from online, and you'll
所以这只是一个来自在线的大图表，你会
see in the middle of this chart, here, here's my 65, A. Here's my 66,
看到这张图表的中间，这里是我的65，A。这是我的66，
B, C, and let's see, 72 is H, 73 is I, and so forth.
B，C，让我们看看，72是H，73是I，依此类推。
So there's a mapping, at least for English, between all of these numbers
因此，至少对于英语而言，所有这些数字之间都有一个映射。
and all of these letters.
以及所有这些信件。
And if we focus here, those are the beginning of our uppercase alphabet.
如果我们专注于这里，这些是我们大写字母表的开头。
So suppose then that today, tomorrow, you receive a text message
所以假设今天，明天，你收到一条短信
from someone, and underneath the hood, now that you're a computer person,
从某人那里，在引擎盖下，现在你是一个计算机人，
you figure out a way to see what pattern of 0's and 1's was sent.
你想出一种方法来查看发送了 0 和 1 的模式。
In this case, it's wireless as opposed to wired,
在这种情况下，它是无线的，而不是有线的，
but it's still some pattern of 0's and 1's.
但它仍然是 0 和 1 的某种模式。
And your phone is turning some switches of its own
你的手机正在转动自己的一些开关
on and off to represent that message from a friend.
打开和关闭以表示来自朋友的消息。
Suppose that the three patterns you received
假设你收到的三种模式
were these three bytes, from left to right,
这三个字节，从左到右，
spelling out a three-letter word.
拼出一个三个字母的单词。
Well, if we do out the math, 1's place, 2's place, and so forth--
好吧，如果我们计算一下，1的位置，2的位置，等等——
I'll spoil it for you.
我会为你剧透的。
Suppose that you received a text message that doesn't literally say 72, 73, 33,
假设你收到一条短信，字面上没有说 72、73、33、
but you've received a pattern of 8 plus 8 plus 8, 24 bits
但是你收到的模式是 8 加 8 加 8,24 位
that if you do out the math represent the decimal number 72, 73, 33.
如果你做数学代表十进制数 72、73、33。
Anyone recall what message you might have received
任何人都记得你可能收到的消息
from the green and white charts?
从绿白图表？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: Hi.
观众：你好。
DAVID J. MALAN: Hi.
DAVID J. MALAN：你好。
Yes, hi is the message, but 72, 73 gives us H and I. What's 33?
是的，嗨是消息，但是 72、73 给了我们 H 和 I.什么是 33？
Any guesses to 33?
对33有什么猜测吗？
Yeah, over here.
是的，在这边。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's an exclamation point.
所以这是一个感叹号。
How would you know that?
你怎么知道的？
Well, you really do need some kind of cheat sheet, a.k.a.
好吧，你确实需要某种备忘单，又名
ASCII in this case.
在这种情况下为 ASCII。
And if we look elsewhere-- let me highlight the left of the chart--
如果我们看看其他地方——让我突出显示图表的左边——
you can see that next to 33 in decimal is indeed the exclamation point.
你可以看到，十进制中的 33 旁边确实是感叹号。
So back in the day, a bunch of humans got in a room,
所以回到过去，一群人进入一个房间，
decided that, hey, when we start building PCs and later Macs and phones,
决定，嘿，当我们开始构建 PC 以及后来的 Mac 和手机时，
we all just have to agree on this form of representation of letters
我们只需要就这种字母表示形式达成一致
of the English alphabet, in this case.
在这种情况下，英文字母表。
We just need to agree on this mapping.
我们只需要就这个映射达成一致。
But somewhat curiously, notice this.
但有点奇怪的是，请注意这一点。
It turns out that, once you paint yourself into this corner
事实证明，一旦你把自己画进这个角落
and start using 65 for A, 66 for B, well,
并开始将 65 用于 A，66 用于 B，好吧，
how do you represent 65 the number and 66 the number,
你如何表示 65 的数字和 66 的数字，
if you want to do math or use Excel or something like that?
如果你想做数学或使用Excel或类似的东西？
Does anyone see the solution, perhaps?
也许有人看到解决方案吗？
How do you represent the number 1 in ASCII?
你如何表示 ASCII 中的数字 1？
Yeah, in the middle?
是的，在中间？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的。
So this is getting a little maybe inception or something,
所以这有点可能是开始什么的，
but you could represent numbers with other numbers.
但是你可以用其他数字来表示数字。
And so if you want to represent the number
所以如果你想代表数字
you and I know as 1, like when you type it on your keyboard,
你和我知道是1，就像你在键盘上打字一样，
turns out the computer stores that as the decimal number 49.
原来计算机将其存储为十进制数 49。
If you hit 2 on your keyboard, the computer is not storing 2, per se.
如果在键盘上按 2，则计算机本身不会存储 2。
It's storing the decimal number 50.
它存储十进制数 50。
Now, thankfully, the paradox stops there.
现在，值得庆幸的是，悖论到此为止。
We just have a mapping now of numbers to numbers.
我们现在只有一个数字到数字的映射。
But really, at the end of the day-- and you're
但实际上，在一天结束时 - 你是
going to learn this when we start writing code in that other language, C,
当我们开始用另一种语言 C 编写代码时，将学习这一点，
next week-- it's just context-dependent, at the end of the day.
下周 - 它只是依赖于上下文，在一天结束时。
Inside of your Mac, PC, and phone, there's just all of these permutations
在你的Mac，PC和手机中，只有所有这些排列
of bits, all of these patterns of 0's and 1's.
位，所有这些 0 和 1 的模式。
And generally speaking, when you open up a text message that you've received
一般来说，当你打开收到的短信时
from someone, it's 0's and 1's.
从某人那里，它是 0 和 1。
But obviously, if it's a text message, the whole point of text messages
但显然，如果它是一条短信，短信的全部意义
is to send text, and so those patterns of 0's and 1's, by default,
是发送文本，因此默认情况下，0 和 1 的模式，
will typically be interpreted as letters of the alphabet.
通常被解释为字母表中的字母。
So you won't see 0's and 1's.
所以你不会看到 0 和 1。
You won't see decimal numbers.
你不会看到十进制数字。
You'll see the English message that your friend intended.
你会看到好友想要的英文消息。
By contrast, if you open up something like Excel,
相比之下，如果你打开像Excel这样的东西，
that same pattern 0's zeros and 1's might indeed work out to be 72, 73, 33.
同样的模式 0 的 0 和 1 可能确实是 72、73、33。
You might see cells in your spreadsheet with literally those three numbers.
你可能会在电子表格中看到带有这三个数字的单元格。
Why?
为什么？
Because spreadsheets are all about numbers and number
因为电子表格都是关于数字和数字的
crunching and math, in many cases.
在许多情况下，加班和数学。
If by contrast, you open up Photoshop and try
相比之下，如果你打开Photoshop并尝试
to look at that same pattern of 0's and 1's, it's not going to be 72, 73, 33.
看看0和1的相同模式，它不会是72,73,33。
It's not going to be 0's and 1's.
它不会是 0 和 1。
It's not going to be hi.
不会是嗨。
It's going to be some color of the rainbow.
这将是彩虹的某种颜色。
You're going to use those patterns of 0's and 1's, it
你将使用0和1的模式，它
turns out too, to represent colors.
原来也是，代表颜色。
And indeed, so long as you and I just agree, as humans long
事实上，只要你和我只是同意，作为人类，只要
have, what these patterns are going to be, all of our systems,
拥有，这些模式将是什么，我们所有的系统，
many of our systems nowadays are indeed interoperable.
如今，我们的许多系统确实是可互操作的。
But I'm being very biased here, and indeed, the A and ASCII
但我在这里非常有偏见，事实上，A 和 ASCII
is very American-centric.
非常以美国为中心。
What do you not see in this chart?
你在这个图表中看不到什么？
If you speak any other language than English,
如果你说英语以外的任何其他语言，
odds are, you're not seeing characters you know and love and need
很有可能，你没有看到你认识、喜爱和需要的角色
every day to type or send messages.
每天打字或发送消息。
Well, there's a huge character set that's
嗯，有一个巨大的角色集是
not supported here, whether it's accented characters
此处不支持，无论是重音字符
and a lot of Asian alphabets.
和很多亚洲字母。
You have many more symbols than can fit even on this screen here.
你拥有的符号比此处的此屏幕所能容纳的要多得多。
And so humans kind of painted themselves into a corner, early on, or really,
所以人类有点把自己画进了一个角落，很早就，或者真的，
Americans did.
美国人做到了。
But on a typical keyboard, US English keyboard, yeah, you
但是在典型的键盘上，美式英语键盘，是的，你
have A's and B's and C's, uppercase and lowercase,
有 A 和 B 和 C，大写和小写，
but you also have accented characters here.
但是你在这里也有重音字符。
And nowadays, not sure if this is maybe necessary, but nowadays,
如今，不确定这是否有必要，但如今，
you have other characters on your keyboard, like these.
键盘上还有其他字符，例如这些字符。
And these are a playful incarnation of what's actually
这些是实际内容的俏皮化身
a technical solution to this problem.
这个问题的技术解决方案。
If I claim for the moment that ASCII historically used 7 bits to represent
如果我暂时声称 ASCII 历史上使用 7 位来表示
letters-- and let's just round that up to a byte--
字母 - 让我们把它四舍五入到一个字节 -
8 bits to represent letters, ASCII can represent as many as 255,
8位代表字母，ASCII可以代表多达255个，
or really 256, total characters.
或者真的是256个，总字符数。
Why 256?
为什么是256？
Well, if you have them all 0, that's 0, and the highest number
好吧，如果你把它们都为 0，那就是 0，也是最高的数字
I claimed a moment ago was 255.
我刚才声称是255。
So that's 256 total possibilities.
所以总共有256种可能性。
That's not many letters.
这不是很多字母。
It's fine for English, but not a lot of human languages.
英语很好，但人类语言不多。
So what might the intuitive solution be, if you
那么直观的解决方案是什么，如果你
want to represent accented characters, Asian characters, emoji, even
想要代表重音字符，亚洲字符，表情符号，甚至
like these, which are just keys on a keyboard nowadays?
像这些，现在只是键盘上的键？
What's the intuitive solution, if a byte's too few?
如果一个字节太少，直观的解决方案是什么？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: Add another digit.
受众：添加另一个数字。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的。
So add another digit.
所以添加另一个数字。
Just like we had a 4th volunteer come on up to give us a 4th bid,
就像我们有第四个志愿者来给我们第四个投标一样，
let's just throw hardware at the problem and use a few more bits.
让我们把硬件扔到这个问题上，再用几个位。
So maybe instead of 1 byte, let's use 2, or heck, let's use 3 or 4 bytes.
所以也许让我们使用 2 而不是 1 个字节，或者哎呀，让我们使用 3 或 4 个字节。
Even though it's getting a little expensive--
即使它变得有点贵——
we're going from 8 to 16 to 24 or 32 bits--
我们从 8 到 16 到 24 或 32 位——
that's how computers do things, these days.
如今，这就是计算机做事的方式。
And thankfully, we have so much memory inside of our computers and phones,
值得庆幸的是，我们的电脑和手机内部有如此多的内存，
we can certainly spare a few to represent these things.
我们当然可以腾出一些来代表这些事情。
And the solution then to ASCII is what we'll call Unicode.
ASCII的解决方案就是我们所说的Unicode。
So Unicode is also just a mapping of numbers to letters
所以Unicode也只是数字到字母的映射。
but in many different languages.
但有许多不同的语言。
And indeed, the Unicode Consortium is a bunch
事实上，Unicode 联盟是一堆
of people from all different companies--
来自不同公司的人——
a lot of different companies and countries and cultures whose mission,
许多不同的公司、国家和文化，其使命，
as an organization, is to capture digitally all forms of human language
作为一个组织，就是以数字方式捕获所有形式的人类语言
in this case.
在这种情况下。
And to ensure that especially smaller demographics of humans speaking
并确保特别是较小的人口统计数据
lesser-known languages are nonetheless represented and preserved digitally
尽管如此，鲜为人知的语言仍以数字方式呈现和保存
using some mapping of these 0's and 1's.
使用这些 0 和 1 的一些映射。
It turns out, though, if you start using 32 bits, as many as 32 bits,
然而，事实证明，如果你开始使用 32 位，多达 32 位，
to represent characters on a keyboard, that's 4 billion possible permutations
在键盘上表示字符，这是 40 亿种可能的排列
of 0's and 1's.
的 0 和 1。
That's way more than we need for most human languages.
这比我们对大多数人类语言的需求要多得多。
So there's a little bit of room in there for some of those more playful things,
所以那里有一点空间来容纳一些更有趣的东西，
like those emoji.
就像那些表情符号一样。
So for instance, suppose you got a text message with this pattern
例如，假设你收到一条带有此模式的短信
of 0's and 1's.
的 0 和 1。
Or if we do out the math, suppose you receive a text message
或者，如果我们进行数学计算，假设你收到一条短信
that, if you do out the math in decimal, is 4,036,991,106.
如果你用十进制计算，那就是 4,036,991,106。
Anyone know what emoji you're looking at?
有人知道你在看什么表情符号吗？
It would be weird if you do, but what is this?
如果你这样做会很奇怪，但这是什么？
Well, it turns out that, as of this past year,
好吧，事实证明，截至去年，
this is the most popular emoji to be sent by many measures,
这是通过多种措施发送的最受欢迎的表情符号，
Face with Tears of Joy.
脸上带着喜悦的泪水。
So that is the pattern that a bunch of humans in the Unicode Consortium
这就是Unicode联盟中一群人的模式
decided would represent this.
决定将代表这一点。
But you'll notice, many of you might have iPhones, some of you
但你会注意到，你们中的许多人可能拥有iPhone，你们中的一些人
might have Android devices too, and sometimes, these
可能也有安卓设备，有时，这些
don't actually look quite the same.
实际上看起来不太一样。
This happens to be the current version of Face with Tears of Joy on iOS.
这恰好是iOS上Face with Tears of Joy的当前版本。
On Android, it tends to look a little something more like this,
在Android上，它看起来更像这样，
and here is kind of a curiosity.
这是一种好奇心。
Even though you and I look at these things and they look like images,
即使你和我看着这些东西，它们看起来像图像，
they're not images.
它们不是图像。
They're characters, at least as we've defined them now in Unicode.
它们是字符，至少正如我们现在在 Unicode 中定义的那样。
And iOS and Android and Windows and Facebook and other companies and apps,
还有iOS、Android、Windows、Facebook和其他公司和应用程序，
nowadays, really just have different fonts, if you will.
如今，如果你愿意的话，真的只是有不同的字体。
So just like fonts with English and other languages
所以就像英语和其他语言的字体一样
can give you different characters with serifs or not,
可以给你不同的角色衬线或不衬线，
emoji are themselves, yes, drawings that someone made,
表情符号本身就是，是的，有人画的图画，
but they're really just a font.
但它们实际上只是一种字体。
And so that same pattern of 0's and 1's might just render slightly differently
因此，0 和 1 的相同模式可能只是渲染略有不同
on someone's phone or another.
在某人的电话或其他手机上。
If you've ever gotten like an icon on your phone that's broken,
如果你曾经像手机上的图标一样坏了，
and you've been sent an emoji, but it's like a square or something arbitrary
并且你已经收到了一个表情符号，但它就像一个正方形或任意的东西
and not sensible, it might just mean that you have not
不明智，这可能只是意味着你没有
updated to the latest version of iOS or Android,
更新到最新版本的iOS或安卓，
which just updates the font of supported emoji.
它只是更新支持的表情符号的字体。
Because those folks at Unicode, pretty much every year
因为Unicode的那些人，几乎每年都
nowadays, are adding more and more emoji to that particular character set.
如今，正在向该特定字符集添加越来越多的表情符号。
Now, I went down the rabbit hole of figuring out the other day just which
现在，我前几天掉进了兔子洞，弄清楚了哪个
are the most popular emoji these days.
是当今最受欢迎的表情符号。
On Twitter specifically, this past year, the most popular emoji, by contrast,
特别是在Twitter上，在过去的一年里，最受欢迎的表情符号相比之下，
was Loudly Crying Face.
是大声哭泣的脸。
I don't know if that says more about 2021 or about Twitter,
我不知道这是否更多地说明了 2021 年或推特，
but you'll see different trends, certainly, in how these are used.
但你会看到不同的趋势，当然，在如何使用它们。
But even humans themselves didn't necessarily think two steps ahead,
但即使是人类自己也不一定提前思考两步，
and now a lot of the emoji are the default yellow color.
现在很多表情符号都是默认的黄色。
But there's a lot of emoji that aren't these cartoon characters,
但是有很多表情符号不是这些卡通人物，
but they're meant to represent humans in various professions
但它们旨在代表各种职业的人类
or gestures or the like.
或手势等。
And nowadays too, you've probably noticed on your phone and Macs and PCs,
如今，你可能已经注意到手机，Mac和PC上，
there are different skin tones that you can assign to certain emojis.
你可以为某些表情符号分配不同的肤色。
If it's supported by the company and by Unicode,
如果它得到公司和Unicode的支持，
you can actually touch and hold on a certain emoji,
你实际上可以触摸并按住某个表情符号，
and then you can choose the appropriate skin tone
然后你可以选择合适的肤色
to represent yourself or someone else.
代表自己或其他人。
And that then modifies the display.
然后修改显示。
Well, let's just think for a moment here,
好吧，让我们在这里想一想，
how did Apple and Google and Microsoft and others
苹果和谷歌和微软和其他人是如何做到的
go about implementing support for emoji with different skin tones?
去实现对不同肤色的表情符号的支持？
How could you do this?
你怎么能这样做？
If you want to represent some smiling emoji but in five,
如果你想代表一些微笑的表情符号，但用五个，
in this case, different skin tones, you could come up with what?
在这种情况下，不同的肤色，你能想出什么？
Five different patterns that are identical, structurally,
五种不同的模式，在结构上是相同的，
except for the skin tone used in places in that image.
除了该图像中某些地方使用的肤色。
But that's a little inefficient to just do copy, paste, paste, paste, paste,
但是，仅仅复制，粘贴，粘贴，粘贴，粘贴，粘贴，这有点低效，
and change the color in Photoshop, if you will.
并更改 Photoshop 中的颜色（如果你愿意的话）。
That's going to use more bits, more information than you might need to.
这将使用比你可能需要的更多的位，更多的信息。
How else, if you now start to think a little bit more
否则，如果你现在开始多想一点
like a computer scientist, if at the end of the day, all you have are
就像计算机科学家一样，如果在一天结束时，你所拥有的只是
0's and 1's, how else could you implement skin tones, might you think?
0和1，你还能怎么实现肤色，你会觉得吗？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: RGB.
观众：RGB。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
So RGB, we'll come to that in just a moment.
所以RGB，我们一会儿就会谈到这一点。
That stands for Red, Green, Blue.
这代表红色，绿色，蓝色。
That's one way.
这是一种方式。
In this case, though, I'm seeking an alternative
不过，在这种情况下，我正在寻找替代方案
to just using five different patterns of 0's and 1's to represent the same emoji
只使用五种不同的 0 和 1 模式来表示相同的表情符号
but different skin tones.
但肤色不同。
So not quite RGB.
所以不完全是RGB。
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
So store one copy of the emoji and then store different variants of the color
因此，存储表情符号的一个副本，然后存储颜色的不同变体
that you want to assign to that emoji.
你要分配给该表情符号。
Yeah.
是的。
So this is actually an example of-- do you want to elaborate?
所以这实际上是一个例子 - 你想详细说明吗？
AUDIENCE: You could use a loop.
观众：你可以使用循环。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
So you can use a loop to actually output these things.
所以你可以使用一个循环来实际输出这些东西。
More on that in a moment.
稍后会详细介绍。
Let me go down this road for just a moment.
让我沿着这条路走一会儿。
This would be in some sense a better design, if you will, but why?
这将是在某种意义上更好的设计，如果你愿意，但为什么呢？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: A filter?
观众：过滤器？
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
So filter, if we think of in the Instagram sense.
所以过滤，如果我们从Instagram的意义上考虑。
You can change the color of something, and that could be related here too.
你可以更改某些内容的颜色，这也可能与此处相关。
AUDIENCE: Could it be another font [INAUDIBLE]
观众：会不会是另一种字体[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, interesting.
DAVID J. MALAN：哦，有意思。
So maybe it could be just a completely different font.
所以也许它可能只是一种完全不同的字体。
And you have five different fonts that are almost identical,
你有五种几乎相同的不同字体，
except for the various interpretations of skin tone for those same emoji.
除了那些相同的表情符号对肤色的各种解释。
Let me spoil.
让我剧透一下。
I think if we go down this one particular road,
我想如果我们沿着这条路走下去，
the way the Unicode folks decided to do this some years ago where
几年前Unicode人士决定这样做的方式
the first byte or bytes that you receive via text or email
你通过文本或电子邮件收到的第一个字节或多个字节
just represent like the structure of the emoji, the default yellow version,
就像表情符号的结构一样，默认的黄色版本，
thereof.
其中。
But if it's immediately followed by a certain pattern of bits
但是，如果它紧随其后的是某种模式的位
that these humans standardize to represent
这些人类标准化来代表
each of these different shades of skin tone, then the phone, the Mac,
这些不同色调的肤色中的每一个，然后是手机，Mac，
the PC will change that default color, yellow in most cases,
PC将更改默认颜色，在大多数情况下为黄色，
to whatever the more apt human tone is.
无论更贴切的人性语气是什么。
So you just use twice as many bits, but you don't use five times as many bits.
所以你只使用两倍的位，但你不会使用五倍的位。
So what do I mean?
那我是什么意思？
You don't have five completely distinct patterns, per se.
你本身没有五种完全不同的模式。
For each of these possible variants, you have a representation
对于这些可能的变体中的每一个，你都有一个表示形式
of just the emoji itself, structurally, and then
只是表情符号本身，在结构上，然后
reusable patterns for those five skin tones.
这五种肤色的可重复使用模式。
Unfortunately, that wasn't quite versatile enough for other features
不幸的是，这对于其他功能来说还不够通用
that were in the pipeline, and nowadays too,
这些都在酝酿中，现在也是如此，
and there's a double meaning now to representation.
现在代表有双重含义。
Emojis intended to focus on certain professions, and early on too,
表情符号旨在专注于某些职业，而且早期也是如此，
were certain professions associated with certain genders and vice versa.
某些职业是否与某些性别相关，反之亦然。
And you couldn't necessarily be one gender or another,
而且你不一定是一种性别或另一种性别，
in a certain profession or another.
在某个职业或另一个职业中。
There were these combinatorics that just weren't possible.
有这些组合是不可能的。
But nowadays, as you might have seen, you
但是如今，正如你可能已经看到的，你
can have couples in love for instance that
可以有恋爱中的情侣，例如
actually look a little more like three emojis, but just kind of combined
实际上看起来更像三个表情符号，但只是结合在一起
into one.
合二为一。
And indeed, this is just one key press on your phone,
事实上，这只是你手机上的一个按键，
and you can combine different emoji on the left and then the right
你可以在左边和右边组合不同的表情符号
with the emoji in the middle.
中间是表情符号。
And so it turns out how computers nowadays
所以现在的电脑是如何
represent these patterns are one set of bits for the character on the left,
表示这些模式是左边字符的一组位，
one set of bits for a character on the right,
右边字符的一组位，
one set of bits for whatever emoji you want in the middle.
一组位，用于中间你想要的任何表情符号。
And then you assemble more complicated compositions of emoji
然后你组装更复杂的表情符号组合
by just reusing those same patterns and bits and bits.
只需重用这些相同的模式和位和位。
The Unicode folks don't have to come up with a whole new representation
Unicode的人不必想出一个全新的表示
for some very specific incarnation.
对于一些非常具体的化身。
They can create one for person, for male,
他们可以为男性创造一个，
for, female for other characters that you might want to display,
对于，女性表示你可能想要显示的其他字符，
and reuse those same patterns of 0's and 1's.
并重复使用0和1的相同模式。
And so here, you see the imperfection, of or lack
所以在这里，你看到了不完美，或缺乏
of foresight, of humans for building a system early on that
的远见卓识，人类早期建立一个系统
was entirely American-centric, no characters, emoji, or the like,
完全以美国为中心，没有字符，表情符号等，
that's evolved too.
这也进化了。
And so that's an important detail in computing, nowadays.
因此，这是当今计算中的一个重要细节。
It too is evolving, and the languages you're
它也在进化，你的语言
about to learn in the coming days, those too are evolving as well.
即将在未来几天学习，这些也在不断发展。
And new features are getting added, and even programming languages have
新功能不断增加，甚至编程语言也有
version numbers.
版本号。
You might have a different version of an app on your phone.
你的手机上可能有不同版本的应用。
Programming languages too have different versions as well.
编程语言也有不同的版本。
Questions then thus far on how information
到目前为止关于如何信息的问题
is represented using ASCII or Unicode or anything in between?
使用ASCII或Unicode或任何在两者之间表示？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, good question.
DAVID J. MALAN：哦，好问题。
So to recap, why can't you just--
所以回顾一下，你为什么不能——
well, let me summarize that as why can't you
好吧，让我总结一下，为什么你不能
similarly use different patterns to change the context of what
同样使用不同的模式来改变上下文
these patterns of bits represent, whether it's
这些位的模式代表，无论是
a number or a letter or a graphic?
一个数字、一个字母或一个图形？
In actuality, that's kind of what's happening underneath the hood.
实际上，这就是引擎盖下正在发生的事情。
It's not standardized in quite the same way, but starting next week,
它没有以完全相同的方式标准化，但从下周开始，
when we transition from scratch to C, you'll learn about types, data types.
当我们从零开始过渡到 C 时，你将了解类型、数据类型。
Where the onus initially is going to be on you, the programmer,
程序员最初的工作将由你负责，
to tell the program whether or not this pattern of bits
告诉程序这种位模式
should be interpreted as a number or as a letter
应解释为数字或字母
or as a color or something else.
或作为颜色或其他东西。
Nowadays, though, and toward the end of the semester,
不过，如今，在学期末，
you'll use languages, like Python, where the computer just figures it out
你将使用语言，如Python，计算机只是想办法解决它。
for you by context, which makes it even easier and faster to program as well.
通过上下文为你服务，这也使编程更加容易和快捷。
Other questions on Unicode, ASCII or the like?
关于Unicode，ASCII或类似的其他问题？
All right.
好吧。
Well, how about just a few other forms of information?
那么，其他几种形式的信息呢？
RGB was called out earlier, Red, Green, Blue.
RGB被称为较早，红色，绿色，蓝色。
How do images get represented in computers?
图像如何在计算机中呈现？
Well, in fact, it's typically an assembly of some amount of red,
嗯，事实上，它通常是一些红色的集合，
some amount of green, some amount of blue,
一定量的绿色，一些蓝色，
but there are other representations.
但还有其他表示形式。
If you're a graphic designer, you might know them,
如果你是一个平面设计师，你可能认识他们，
but RGB is still pretty common.
但RGB仍然很普遍。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
This means to represent every dot on your phone or every dot
这意味着代表手机上的每个点或每个点
on your TV or your laptop or desktop, there
在你的电视、笔记本电脑或台式机上，那里
is a number representing how much red that dot should show,
是一个数字，表示该点应显示多少红色，
a number representing how much green, and a number representing
一个数字代表多少绿色，一个数字代表
how much blue it should show, red, green, blue, respectively.
它应该显示多少蓝色，分别是红色、绿色、蓝色。
So for instance, if a dot on your screen were
例如，如果屏幕上的一个点是
using these three numbers, these three values or bytes, 72, 73, 33,
使用这三个数字，这三个值或字节，72，73，444，
in a text message or email, that would be interpreted as I claimed "High."
在短信或电子邮件中，这将被解释为我声称“高”。
But in Photoshop or in some graphical program,
但是在Photoshop或一些图形程序中，
that same pattern would be interpreted as let's
相同的模式将被解释为让我们
call it a medium amount of red, a medium amount of green,
称它为中等数量的红色，中等数量的绿色，
and a little bit of blue.
还有一点蓝色。
And why medium and little?
为什么是中等和很少？
Turns out, each of these are bytes, the smallest value you can have in a byte
原来，这些都是字节，你可以在一个字节中的最小值
we said is 0.
我们说是0。
The largest value you can have a byte is 255,
一个字节的最大值是 255，
so I'm just kind of spitballing here.
所以我只是在这里吐槽。
This is like medium, medium, and a low amount of red, green, blue,
这就像中等，中等，少量的红色，绿色，蓝色，
specifically.
具体说来。
Those three colors, like wavelengths of light, are combined in such a way
这三种颜色，就像光的波长一样，以这种方式组合在一起
that you would have this dot on the screen, a sort of murky shade
你会在屏幕上看到这个点，一种模糊的阴影
of yellow or brown.
黄色或棕色。
That is how a computer would store precisely that color,
这就是计算机如何精确存储这种颜色，
and in fact, we've seen this color.
事实上，我们已经看到了这种颜色。
When you type in Face with Tears of Joy, generally, on your screen,
当你带着喜悦的泪水在脸上打字时，一般来说，在你的屏幕上，
it looks like this, typically much smaller.
它看起来像这样，通常要小得多。
But let's zoom in, or let's Zoom in a little more.
但是让我们放大，或者再放大一点。
What are you starting to see, if you know the term?
如果你知道这个词，你开始看到什么？
AUDIENCE: Pixels.
受众：像素。
DAVID J. MALAN: So pixels, it's getting very pixelated.
DAVID J. MALAN：所以像素，它变得非常像素化。
A pixel is just a dot on the screen, and if you really zoom in on it,
像素只是屏幕上的一个点，如果你真的放大它，
you can literally see all of the dots that compose an emoji,
你可以从字面上看到组成表情符号的所有点，
in this case on iOS, in the font that Apple is using to represent this
在iOS上的这种情况下，在Apple用于表示此
particular pattern of 0's and 0's.
0 和 0 的特定模式。
So one of those yellow dots-- and there's many of them all kind of blend
所以其中一个黄点 -- 有很多都是混合的
together here--
一起在这里——
each dot on the screen I claim is 3 bytes.
我声称屏幕上的每个点都是 3 个字节。
How much red, green, blue for this dot?
这个点有多少红色、绿色、蓝色？
How much red green blue for this dot?
这个点有多少红绿蓝？
And you'll notice too, that when it gets to be sort of brownish here,
你也会注意到，当这里变成褐色时，
the dots really stand out.
这些点真的很突出。
The 3 values, the 3 bytes, a.k.a.
3 个值，3 个字节，又名
24 bits, are just slightly different.
24位，只是略有不同。
And so underneath the hood, this is why images, photographs
所以在引擎盖下面，这就是为什么图像，照片
that you take or gif that you download, get so darn big,
你拿的或者你下载的gif，变得如此之大，
potentially, because you have a number representing every dot on the screen.
潜在地，因为你有一个数字代表屏幕上的每个点。
Well, if this I claim is indeed how images are typically
嗯，如果我声称这确实是图像通常的样子
represented, using pattern of bits that are
表示，使用位模式
assigned to some amount of red, green, or blue, how do you get video?
分配到一定数量的红色，绿色或蓝色，你如何获得视频？
What is a video, if at the end of the day, all we have are 0's and 1's?
什么是视频，如果在一天结束时，我们只有0和1？
What's a video, perhaps?
也许什么是视频？
Yeah?
是的？
Let's go here, way in back.
让我们去这里，回到后面。
Yeah.
是的。
Pixels really changing values over time.
像素确实随时间变化值。
and do you want to confirm or deny, the hand that went up here?
你想确认还是否认，这里的手？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, or equivalently, a sequence
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，或者等效地，一个序列
of images that, over time, are changing on the screen.
随着时间的推移，屏幕上的图像正在发生变化。
So both of those are valid interpretations,
所以这两种解释都是有效的，
and just for fun, if you grew up with these picture books,
只是为了好玩，如果你和这些图画书一起长大，
you might remember a little something like this.
你可能还记得这样的小事。
if we could dim the lights?
如果我们能调暗灯光？
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[放歌！]
So that's the old school analog way to implement
所以这是老派的模拟实现方式
a video, in the sense that that artist wrote out like hundreds of pieces
一段视频，从某种意义上说，这位艺术家写了几百件作品
of paper, with almost identical images, but where the ink from their pencil
纸，几乎相同的图像，但那里的墨水从他们的铅笔
or pen was slightly moving.
或者笔在微微移动。
And if you digitize that, such that each of those strokes
如果你把它数字化，这样每个笔画
are represented with dots instead, that's really what you're seeing
用点表示，这就是你所看到的
is a sequence of all of these images flying across the screen.
是所有这些图像在屏幕上飞行的序列。
And if we dive into the real world, if you've ever watched a film,
如果我们潜入现实世界，如果你看过电影，
a Hollywood movie is typically 24 FPS, Frames Per Second.
好莱坞电影通常是每秒24 fps的帧数。
That really means you're seeing 24 images per second, or on TV or in soap
这实际上意味着你每秒或在电视或肥皂中看到24张图像
operas, it's often 30 frames per second.
歌剧，通常是每秒 30 帧。
That makes things look a little more smooth.
这让事情看起来更顺利一点。
So it's not actual motion picture, if you will.
所以这不是真正的电影，如果你愿意的话。
It's sequences of pictures, and your brain and mind
这是一系列的图片，你的大脑和思想
are interpolating that, oh, this is smooth movement, even though we're just
插值，哦，这是平滑的运动，即使我们只是
seeing a lot of pictures really fast.
看到很多图片的速度真的很快。
Now, that gets really big, and we'll talk later in the semester
现在，这真的很大，我们将在学期晚些时候讨论
how you can compress information, so that you're not using way
如何压缩信息，以便你不使用的方式
more bits than you actually need to.
比你实际需要的位数更多。
And there's fancy algorithms that folks have developed,
人们开发了一些奇特的算法，
but at the end of the day, that's really all a video might
但归根结底，这真的是一个视频可能
be is a sequence of images.
be 是一系列图像。
Conversely, if you want to represent the music that
相反，如果你想代表
accompanies that or something else, if any of you play an instrument
伴随着它或其他东西，如果你们中的任何一个演奏乐器
and can read sheet music, how could you digitize this?
并且可以阅读乐谱，你如何将其数字化？
[PIANO MUSIC]
[钢琴曲]
Like how could you represent musical notes in a computer?
比如你怎么能在电脑里表现音符？
You and I hear them when we play files, but what's
你和我听到他们当我们播放文件，但什么是
really going on underneath the hood?
真的在引擎盖下发生？
Any musicians, piano players?
有音乐家，钢琴演奏家吗？
Anyone?
任何人？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: Hertz value?
观众：赫兹值？
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so Hertz value, so some frequency.
DAVID J. MALAN:好的，那么赫兹值，一些频率。
So sound is some frequency, and it's kind of hitting your eardrum.
所以声音是某种频率，它有点击中你的耳膜。
And that's what makes it sound low or high or somewhere in between.
这就是让它听起来低或高或介于两者之间的原因。
So maybe we could assign, just like there's letters A through G here,
所以也许我们可以分配，就像这里有字母A到G一样，
maybe we could assign specific frequency values, which
也许我们可以分配特定的频率值，这
are just going to be numbers measured in something
只是用某种东西来衡量的数字
called Hertz, something per second.
叫赫兹，每秒某事。
And maybe we could have a few other numbers for each of these notes,
也许我们可以为每个笔记提供其他一些数字，
not just the note or the frequency.
不仅仅是音符或频率。
Maybe, we could represent the loudness of it, like how hard
也许，我们可以代表它的响度，比如有多难
or how softly a human might equivalently press it.
或者人类可以同等地轻柔地按压它。
Maybe a third number, like duration, like how long
也许是第三个数字，比如持续时间，比如多长时间
is there finger on the keyboard?
键盘上有手指吗？
So you can imagine quantifying something like music that in the real world
所以你可以想象在现实世界中量化音乐
is perfectly continuous as something more discrete,
作为更离散的东西是完全连续的，
by representing each note over time as just some sequence of values.
通过将每个音符随着时间的推移表示为一些值序列。
And there's so many different ways to do this, MIDI, if you've heard,
有很多不同的方法可以做到这一点，MIDI，如果你听说过的话，
mp3's, AAC.
mp3的，AAC。
Almost all of the file extensions you see on your Mac or PC,
你在Mac或PC上看到的几乎所有文件扩展名，
if you see them at all, ultimately just mean
如果你看到他们，最终只是意味着
there's a different form of representation for, in this case,
在这种情况下，有一种不同的表示形式，
something like sound.
类似声音的东西。
So let me just stipulate, there are these and many more
所以让我规定一下，有这些，还有更多
ways to represent inputs and outputs, and thankfully, humans
表示输入和输出的方式，谢天谢地，人类
have standardized a lot of this.
已经标准化了很多。
They don't always agree, and this is why we
他们并不总是同意，这就是为什么我们
have different file formats for Apple numbers
为Apple numbers提供不同的文件格式
and Microsoft Excel and Google Spreadsheets
Microsoft Excel和Google电子表格
and stupid incompatibilities like that.
以及像这样愚蠢的不兼容性。
But generally speaking, humans have standardized
但一般来说，人类已经标准化了
how we represent the inputs and outputs to and from problems.
我们如何表示问题的输入和输出。
But let's now focus on this Black box, so to speak,
但是现在让我们把注意力集中在这个黑匣子上，可以这么说，
in the middle, this abstraction.
在中间，这个抽象。
So abstraction is technically a term that you'll
所以抽象在技术上是一个术语，你会
see all over the place in computer science,
在计算机科学中到处可见，
and really, problem solving, that just refers
真的，解决问题，这只是指
to the simplification of something, so that you don't focus on the lower
简化某事，这样你就不会把注意力集中在下层
level implementation details.
级别实现详细信息。
You really just focus on the high level goals or the process itself.
你真的只是专注于高层次的目标或过程本身。
Therefore, your car, if you have a license
因此，你的车，如果你有执照
and have driven or have been in a car, a car, so far as you're concerned,
就你而言，开过车或坐过车，
is probably an abstraction.
可能是一个抽象。
Most of us, if you're like me, probably don't really
我们大多数人，如果你像我一样，可能不会真的
know or care how the engine works and all the parts that are moving.
了解或关心发动机的工作原理以及所有运动的零件。
To you, it's just a way of getting from point A
对你来说，这只是一种从a点
to point B. It's an abstraction, but someone, hopefully the mechanic,
到B点。这是一个抽象概念，但是有人，希望是机械师，
does know those lower level implementation details.
确实知道那些较低级别的实现细节。
If you had to understand how a car works every time you
如果你每次都要了解汽车是如何工作的
want to go to school or to the store, it's probably
想上学或去商店，可能是
going to be a pretty slow process.
这将是一个非常缓慢的过程。
You just want to think and operate at this higher level of abstraction,
你只想在这个更高的抽象层次上思考和操作，
and we're going to do this all the time when writing code and solving problems.
在编写代码和解决问题时，我们将一直这样做。
So what then is in this black box, this abstraction at the moment?
那么，这个黑盒子里现在是什么，这个抽象概念呢？
Well, generally, it's what a computer scientist
嗯，一般来说，这是一个计算机科学家
would call an algorithm, step-by-step instructions for solving some problem.
会调用一个算法，一步一步的指令来解决一些问题。
Now, let's consider the implementation details,
现在，让我们考虑一下实现细节，
that is to say how you might solve certain problems,
也就是说你如何解决某些问题，
and let's take a old school example but in modern form.
让我们举一个古老的学校例子，但以现代形式。
This icon, if you have an iPhone, is, of course for your contacts application.
这个图标，如果你有一个iPhone，当然是你的联系人应用程序。
And if you've got a whole bunch of family members or friends
如果你有一大群家人或朋友
or colleagues in your phonebook, you have
或电话簿中的同事，你有
some kind of contacts pictured here, and it's alphabetized typically
图中的某种联系人，通常是按字母顺序排列的
by first name and last name.
按名字和姓氏。
And odds are, you and I are in the habit,
很可能，你和我都有这个习惯，
if they're not already a favorite, of like clicking on Search
如果他们还不是最喜欢的，比如点击搜索
and then using autocomplete.
，然后使用自动完成功能。
And what happens when you start typing autocomplete?
当你开始输入自动完成时会发生什么？
Well if you type in the letter H, you'll see only, presumably,
如果你输入字母H，你大概只会看到，
Hagrid, Harry, Hermione, and so forth.
海格、哈利、赫敏等等。
If you type in H-A that shows you only Hagrid and Harry,
如果你输入只有海格和哈利的h-a，
and it all happens super fast.
这一切都发生得非常快。
So how is that happening?
那么这是怎么回事呢？
Well, typically, you could just start at the top and look to the bottom,
嗯，通常，你可以从顶部开始，看看底部，
searching for all of the H's or all of the H-A's, but for larger data
搜索所有H或所有h-a，但搜索更大的数据
sets that's going to get slow.
设置会变慢。
For the Googles of the world, that's going to get really slow.
对于世界上的google来说，这将变得非常缓慢。
And even on our phones when you have hundreds, thousands of contacts,
甚至在我们的手机上，当你有成百上千的联系人时，
eventually, even that kind of approach, that algorithm step by step
最终，即使是那种方法，那种算法一步一步地
it might be slow.
它可能很慢。
So how might we go about searching for someone in a phonebook
那么，我们如何在电话簿中搜索某人
like this, like say John Harvard?
像这样，就像约翰哈佛？
Well, here's an old school incarnation of this,
嗯，这是一个古老的学校化身，
and odds are, you might not have had occasion to even physically
很有可能，你甚至可能没有机会
use this thing, nowadays.
现在使用这个东西。
And in fact, this is a bit of a white lie,
事实上，这是一个善意的谎言，
because this is the yellow pages, which means
因为这是黄页，这意味着
this is a book of companies not people.
这是一本关于公司的书，而不是一本关于人的书。
But this is all you can find, and at that, it's even hard to find this.
但这是你能找到的全部，在那，甚至很难找到这个。
But this is the same thing in analog form, physical form.
但这在模拟形式，物理形式中是一样的。
So if I wanted to search for someone like John Harvard, how could I do that?
所以，如果我想寻找像约翰·哈佛这样的人，我该怎么做呢？
Well, I could start on page 1, and I could
嗯，我可以从第1页开始，我可以
start searching for page 2, page 3, page 4, page 5.
开始搜索第2页、第3页、第4页、第5页。
A little hard to do physically, especially since no
身体上有点难，特别是因为没有
one's used this phone book in a lot of years.
有人用过这个电话簿很多年了。
But is this algorithm correct, turning page by page, very inelegantly?
但是这个算法正确吗，一页地翻动，非常不优雅？
Is this correct?
这是对的吗？
Will I find John Harvard, if he's in here?
如果约翰·哈佛在这里，我会找到他吗？
All right.
好吧。
So yes.
所以是的。
This is a little stupidly tedious, because if there's like 1,000 pages,
这有点愚蠢乏味，因为如果有1,000页，
he might be a few hundred pages into this, but it's correct.
他可能有几百页的篇幅，但这是正确的。
At some point, I will find him, and if he's on the page, I'll be able to call.
在某个时候，我会找到他，如果他在页面上，我就可以打电话。
Why?
为什么？
Because presumably, the names are alphabetized in here,
因为大概，名字是按字母顺序排列的，
and there's no cheat sheet on the edge.
而且边缘没有备忘单。
So I have to search for John Harvard from left to right, searching for H,
所以我必须从左到右搜索约翰·哈佛，搜索H，
if it's alphabetized by last name.
如果按姓氏按字母顺序排列。
Well, what would be marginally better?
那么，什么会稍微好一点？
Well, how about two pages at a time?
好吧，一次两页怎么样？
It's hard to do with a 20-year-old phone book,
用20年的电话簿很难做到，
where the pages are grown together, but 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12.
其中页面生长在一起，但是2，4，6，8，10，12。
This algorithm, is this correct?
这个算法，这是正确的吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
观众：没有。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, so no.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，所以没有。
Why?
为什么？
AUDIENCE: You're skipping pages.
观众：你在跳过页面。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的。
So I'm skipping every other page.
所以我跳过每隔一页。
So if I don't consider that, and I find myself in like the I section or the J
所以如果我不考虑这一点，我发现自己在像I节或J节
section, well, I might accidentally conclude,
部分，嗯，我可能会意外得出结论，
nope, I haven't found John Harvard yet, just because I skipped him, because it
不，我还没有找到约翰·哈佛，只是因为我跳过了他，因为它
was sandwiched between two pages.
夹在两页之间。
Now, I can fix this, I think, if I do hit the I section,
现在，我可以解决这个问题，我想，如果我点击了I部分，
well, let me just double back one page, just in case he was in that last page.
好吧，让我翻回一页，以防他在最后一页。
So it's recoverable, but it's almost twice as fast, minus that hiccup there.
所以它是可以恢复的，但它的速度几乎是原来的两倍，减去那里的打嗝。
But what most of us would do, and what your phones
但是我们大多数人会做什么，你的手机
are doing, albeit digitally, is they open up
正在做的，尽管是数字化的，是他们开放的
roughly to the middle of the phonebook.
大致到电话簿的中间。
And they look down, and they say, oh, I'm in roughly the M section.
他们往下看，他们说，哦，我大约在M区。
So I'm roughly halfway through the 1,000-page phonebook.
所以我已经看了1,000页电话簿的一半了。
But what do I now know about John Harvard?
但是我现在对约翰·哈佛了解多少？
Where is he, to my left or to my right?
他在哪里，在我的左边还是在我的右边？
All right.
好吧。
So alphabetically, he's presumably to my left,
按字母顺序，他大概在我的左边，
and so here I can, both metaphorically and physically,
所以在这里，无论是隐喻还是身体上，
tear the problem in half.
把问题撕成两半。
You don't need to be impressed.
你不需要留下深刻的印象。
It's really easy down the spine that way,
这样很容易下到脊椎，
but I know that John Harvard is to the left here.
但我知道约翰·哈佛在左边。
But now I can throw, unnecessarily dramatically, half and page one out
但是现在我可以不必要地戏剧性地扔掉一半和第一页
of the way, and what do I now know?
路，我现在知道什么？
I've gone from 1,000 pages to like 500.
我已经从 1,000 页变成了 500 页。
I can repeat roughly the same algorithm.
我可以重复大致相同的算法。
Go to the half of this, and so this time, I went back a little too far.
走到一半，所以这一次，我回去有点太远了。
I'm in now the E section.
我现在在E部分。
So what do I know?
那我知道什么？
Is John Harvard to my left or to my right?
约翰·哈佛在我左边还是右边？
To my right, so I can, again, tear the problem in half.
在我的右边，所以我可以再次将问题撕成两半。
Throw this half away, and now I'm really flying.
扔掉这一半，现在我真的在飞。
I'm doing it verbally slowly, but that went from 1,000 pages to 500
我说得很慢，但从1,000页到500页
to now 250.
到现在250。
And now I can do it again, 125.
现在我可以再做一次，125。
I do it again, roughly like 67, and keep doing it again and again and again,
我再做一次，大约67岁，然后一遍又一遍地做，
until I get left with, hopefully, just one single page or in this case
直到我得到，希望，只有一页或在这种情况下
an ad for, ironically, a mechanic.
具有讽刺意味的是，一个机械师的广告。
OK, so what is the implication for our performance?
好吧，那对我们的表现有什么影响呢？
Well, let's just do this sort of in the abstract, if you will,
好吧，如果你愿意的话，让我们抽象地做一下，
if that first algorithm were to be plotted just quickly on a chart
如果第一个算法被快速绘制在图表上
without even numbers.
没有偶数。
Here's my x-axis, size of problem on the x-axis.
这是我的x轴，x轴上的问题大小。
So the bigger the problem, the farther out that way.
所以问题越大，那条路就越远。
Time to solve the problem.
是时候解决问题了。
The higher you go up on the y-axis, the more time you're taking to solve it.
你在y轴上走得越高，你解决它的时间就越多。
How would we draw the running time, the amount of time
我们如何绘制运行时间，时间量
taken to run that first algorithm?
运行第一个算法？
Well, it's going to be a straight line.
好吧，这将是一条直线。
Why?
为什么？
Because if you add one more page next year
因为如果你明年多加一页
because more people move to Cambridge, you're
因为更多的人搬到剑桥，你
going to add one more page turn potentially, so
可能会再增加一页，所以
one more second, one more unit of time.
多一秒，多一个时间单位。
So it's a straight line.
所以这是一条直线。
And we'll abstract it away as "n."
我们将它抽象为“n”。
If there's n pages in the phone book, the slope of this line
如果电话簿中有n页，则这条线的斜率
is essentially n.
本质上是 n。
The second algorithm, wherein I was doing two pages at a time,
第二种算法，我一次做两页，
was twice as fast, but it's still a straight line.
快了两倍，但仍然是一条直线。
And in fact, let me just draw some dotted lines here.
事实上，让我在这里画一些虚线。
If the phone book is this big, with my first algorithm,
如果电话簿这么大，用我的第一个算法，
it might take this many units of time, this many steps, this many page turns.
它可能需要这么多的时间单位，这么多的步骤，这么多的翻页。
But with that second algorithm, notice that the intersection is much lower
但是使用第二种算法，请注意交集要低得多
on the yellow line than on the red.
在黄线上比在红线上。
So n over 2 means there's half as many pages here,
所以n超过2意味着这里有一半的页面，
if n is the number of pages.
如果 n 是页数。
So indeed, that algorithm-- the second one--
所以实际上，那个算法 -- 第二个 --
is twice as fast minus the little hiccup that I have to double back one page.
减去我必须翻倍一页的小问题，速度是原来的两倍。
But that's not a big deal if I'm still doing things twice as fast.
但是，如果我仍然以两倍的速度做事，那没什么大不了的。
But the third algorithm looks fundamentally different.
但第三种算法看起来根本不同。
It looks like this.
它看起来像这样。
Logarithms, if you recall from high school or prior--
对数，如果你回忆起高中或以前的-
if you don't, that's fine too.
如果你不这样做，那也没关系。
It's just a fundamentally different function, a different shape.
它只是一个根本不同的功能，一个不同的形状。
And notice that the green line is going up
请注意，绿线正在上升
and up and up but a much slower rate of increase, which means crazy things
但增长速度要慢得多，这意味着疯狂的事情
are possible.
是可能的。
If two towns in Massachusetts, like Cambridge and Allston,
如果马萨诸塞州的两个城镇，比如剑桥和奥尔斯顿，
across the river, merge next year, for instance, in terms of their phone book,
过河，明年合并，例如，在他们的电话簿方面，
they're phone book just got twice as big.
他们的电话簿只有两倍大。
For the first algorithm, that's going to take me twice as many steps
对于第一个算法，这将花费我两倍的步骤
to go through.
通过。
The second algorithm, almost it's going to take me 50% more steps
第二个算法，几乎要我多走50% 步
to go through, two at a time.
要通过，一次两个。
But the third algorithm, that I ended with, tearing things again and again,
但是第三个算法，我结束了，一次又一次地撕裂东西，
dividing and conquering, if you will, in half and in half and in half,
分而治之，如果你愿意，分成两半，分成两半，
how many more steps will my third algorithm
我的第三个算法还有多少步
take if Cambridge and Allston merge into a phone book that's twice as big?
以剑桥和奥尔斯顿合并成一个两倍大的电话簿为例？
AUDIENCE: Four steps.
观众：四个步骤。
DAVID J. MALAN: Just one more step, right?
DAVID J. MALAN：再走一步，对吧？
No big deal.
没什么大不了的。
You just take a really big bite out of the problem
你只是从这个问题中咬了一大口
once you decide if John Harvard is to the left or to the right.
一旦你决定约翰·哈佛是向左还是向右。
And so you've made much faster progress.
所以你取得了更快的进展。
And so this, in essence, is what your computer, your phone
所以从本质上讲，这就是你的电脑，你的手机
is probably doing underneath the hood when searching for Harry or Hermione
在寻找哈利或赫敏时，可能是在引擎盖下做的
or Hagrid or anyone else because it's that much faster,
或者海格或者其他人，因为它快得多，
especially when you have large data.
尤其是当你拥有大量数据时。
If you don't have that many contacts, it probably
如果你没有那么多联系人，它可能
doesn't matter if you search from top to bottom or more
不要紧，如果你搜索从上到下或更多
in the form of this divide-and-conquer algorithm.
以这种分而治之算法的形式。
But if you're the Googles of the world or you're analyzing large data sets,
但是如果你是世界上的谷歌人，或者你正在分析大型数据集，
indeed, this is going to add up quite quickly.
事实上，这将很快增加。
So where do we go with this?
那么我们该何去何从呢？
Well, we're going to introduce next something called pseudocode.
好，我们接下来要介绍一种叫做伪代码的东西。
How can I translate what I did verbally there,
我怎样才能翻译我在那里口头所做的，
sort of intuitively, to actual code?
有点直观，到实际代码？
Well, this won't be Scratch.
好吧，这不会是Scratch。
This won't be C or Python just yet.
这还不是C或Python。
It's just going to be an English-like syntax.
这将是一个类似英语的语法。
And this is how many programmers would start solving a problem.
这就是许多程序员开始解决问题的方式。
They don't start typing out code in C or Python or the like.
他们不会开始用C或Python等输入代码。
They use English or whatever their human language is
他们使用英语或任何人类语言
to jot down an outline for their ideas.
记下他们的想法的大纲。
My first step, really, was picking up the phone book.
我的第一步，真的，是拿起电话簿。
My second step was opening to the middle of the phone book.
我的第二步是打开电话簿的中间。
My third step was somewhat different-- look at the page, because why?
我的第三步有点不同 -- 看看页面，因为为什么？
My fourth step was if person I'm looking for is on the page, I then do what?
我的第四步是，如果我要找的人在页面上，那么我做什么？
It never happened in my example, but I call the person.
在我的例子中从来没有发生过，但我打电话给那个人。
So I'm done.
所以我完成了。
Else if the person is earlier in the book
否则，如果该人在书中较早
alphabetically, as John Harvard was in the case of my H, then
按字母顺序排列，就像约翰·哈佛在我的H的情况下，然后
I should search to the middle of the left of the phone book.
我应该搜索到电话簿左边的中间。
And then I should go back to step three.
然后我应该回到第三步。
Step 3 is look at the page, thereby repeating the same process
步骤3是查看页面，从而重复相同的过程
again and again.
一次又一次。
Step 9, though, might be else if the person is later in the book,
但是，如果该人在书中稍后，则步骤9可能是其他步骤，
then let's go ahead and open to the middle of the right half of the book
然后让我们继续打开书的右半部分的中间
and then go back to line 3.
然后返回第 3 行。
Else there's a fourth scenario we should probably consider,
否则我们可能应该考虑第四种情况，
lest my search process freeze or crash or give me one of those spinning beach
以免我的搜索过程冻结或崩溃，或者给我一个旋转的海滩
balls with a bug.
带有虫子的球。
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, what if John Harvard isn't in the phone book?
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，如果约翰·哈佛不在电话簿上怎么办？
I'd prefer that my algorithm, my phone not just reboot or freeze.
我更喜欢我的算法，我的手机不只是重新启动或冻结。
I should handle that with some kind of catch all.
我应该用某种方式来处理这件事。
Else, so to speak, let's just quit the program.
否则，可以这么说，让我们退出程序。
So there's well-defined behavior for every possible scenario of the four.
因此，对于这四种可能的情况，都有明确定义的行为。
Now, let's call out a few of these salient terms.
现在，让我们提出一些重要的术语。
It turns out, if I highlight in yellow here,
事实证明，如果我在这里突出显示黄色，
there's a pattern to what I've been doing here.
我在这里做的事情是有规律的。
These are all of my English verbs.
这些都是我的英语动词。
And in a moment, we're going to start calling those verbs "functions."
稍后，我们将开始称这些动词为 “函数”。
When you program or write code and you want the program or the computer
当你编程或编写代码时，你想要程序或计算机
to do something for you, some action or verb,
为你做某事，一些动作或动词，
we're going to refer to those actions or verbs
我们将提到那些动作或动词
as these things called "functions," like those here.
这些东西叫做 “函数”，就像这里的一样。
By contrast, I've just highlighted, instead,
相比之下，我刚刚强调了，
my "if," my "else if," my "else if," and "else."
我的 “if”，我的 “else if”，我的 “else if” 和 “else”。
This is going to represent what we're going
这将代表我们将要做的事情
to start calling a "conditional," a proverbial fork in the road where
开始调用一个 “有条件的”，一个众所周知的岔路口，在那里
you can either go this way or that way, do this thing or this other thing.
你可以走这条路或那条路，做这件事或其他事情。
And you're going to decide which of those things
你将决定哪些事情
to do based on what I've now highlighted here, which are going
根据我现在在这里强调的内容来做，这些内容将会
to be called "Boolean expressions"--
被称为“布尔表达式”——
Boole, referring to a mathematician, last name Boole.
布尔，指的是数学家，姓布尔。
A Boolean expression is just a question with a yes/no, a true/false, a 1 or a 0
布尔表达式只是一个带有是/否，真/假，1或0的问题
answer, if you will.
回答，如果你愿意的话。
And it governs whether you do this thing or this thing or this thing or that.
它支配着你是做这件事还是做这件事，还是做这件事，还是做那件事。
The indentation, in this case, is important.
在这种情况下，压痕很重要。
The fact that I've indented line 5 implies, by convention in programming,
事实上，我已经缩进了第5行，这意味着，按照编程中的约定，
that I should only do line 5 if the answer to line 4 is a yes or a true,
如果第4行的答案是肯定或正确，我只应做第5行，
and same for these other indented lines as well.
对于这些其他缩进行也是如此。
And the last characteristic here is this here.
这里的最后一个特征是这里。
Someone called this out earlier, in fact.
事实上，早些时候有人这么说。
These lines, 8 and 11, are now highlighted and represent what?
这些线，8和11，现在突出显示，代表什么？
What might we call these in code if you've done--
如果你已经完成了，我们可以在代码中称之为什么-
yeah, so these are loops, some kind of cycles
是的，这些是循环，某种循环
that result in my doing the same thing again and again,
导致我一次又一次地做同样的事情，
but there's a key detail with this algorithm in pseudocode.
但是这个算法在伪代码中有一个关键的细节。
Even though it's telling me to go back to line 3,
即使它告诉我回到3号线，
why is this algorithm eventually going to stop?
为什么这个算法最终会停止？
Why do I not constantly keep looking for John Harvard
为什么我不一直找约翰·哈佛
forever by nature of these loops telling me to keep going back to line 3?
这些循环的性质永远告诉我继续回到第3行？
Good.
好。
Eventually, he'll be on the page or, to your point earlier, he won't be at all
最终，他会出现在页面上，或者，就你之前的观点而言，他根本不会出现
and we're out of pages, and so we just quit.
我们没有页数了，所以我们就辞职了。
And that's the key about going to the left half or the right half.
这是进入左半部分或右半部分的关键。
It doesn't matter if you do the same thing again and again.
如果你一遍又一遍地做同样的事情也没关系。
You're not going to get stuck in a so-called infinite loop
你不会陷入所谓的无限循环
so long as you keep dividing the problem and shrinking it into something
只要你继续划分问题并将其缩小
smaller, smaller, smaller.
更小，更小，更小。
Eventually, there's going to be no problem left to solve.
最终，将没有问题需要解决。
So even if you don't think of yourself as a computer person,
所以即使你不认为自己是一个电脑人，
even if you've never written code, what you'll find in the coming days
即使你从未写过代码，在未来的日子里你会发现
is that these ideas that we've just kind of harnessed from real life
我们从现实生活中得到的这些想法
are at your fingertips already.
已经触手可及。
And a lot of the process of learning to code
很多学习代码的过程
is just going to be some bumps in the road
只是路上会有一些颠簸
because you can't quite see the new syntax in a familiar way.
因为你不能以熟悉的方式看到新的语法。
But you'll find that the ideas, in fact, are
但是你会发现这些想法，事实上，是
going to be more familiar than you might otherwise think.
会比你想象的更熟悉。
And so we'll see in a bit-- and we'll take a break
所以我们稍后会看到 -- 我们会休息一下
in a moment to take a breather-- that you
在片刻休息一下-你
will see these same ideas in a moment in the context of Scratch,
会在Scratch的背景下看到这些相同的想法，
an actual programming language via which we'll drag and drop
一种实际的编程语言，我们将通过它拖放
puzzle pieces to make actual code work.
使实际代码工作的拼图。
We'll see some variants of these ideas, things
我们会看到这些想法的一些变体，事情
called "arguments" and "return values" and "variables."
称为 “参数” 和 “返回值” 和 “变量”。
But we'll ultimately convert it into this somehow.
但我们最终会把它变成这样。
Anyone want to wager what this program will
任何人都想打赌这个程序会
do if fed to your Mac or PC or phone?
如果喂到你的 Mac 或 PC 或手机，该怎么办？
Here's just a massive pattern of zeros and ones.
这里只是一个巨大的零和一的模式。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: It will indeed say, rather disappointingly, apparently,
DAVID J. MALAN：它确实会说，显然相当令人失望，
just, "Hello, world."
只是，“你好，世界。
And indeed, baked into all of these 0's and 1's are not just the H-E-L-L-O,
事实上，融入所有这些0和1的不仅仅是h-e-l-l-o，
but also the verbs, the action of printing something to the screen.
还有动词，将某些东西打印到屏幕上的动作。
And there's other stuff too so that the program knows how to start
还有其他的东西，所以程序知道如何开始
and how to stop, a lot of stuff that we won't
以及如何停止，很多我们不会的东西
have to worry about, that whoever designed the computer or the language
必须担心，无论是谁设计了计算机或语言
did.
做到了。
But at the end of the day, you're never going
但在一天结束的时候，你永远不会去
to be writing the 0's and 1's yourselves,
自己写0和1，
though our ancestors, once upon a time, did in some form.
虽然我们的祖先曾经以某种形式做过。
We'll be using a much higher-level language, like this in C,
我们将使用更高级的语言，就像C，
or better yet, in just a moment, like in Scratch, like this.
或者更好的是，在一瞬间，就像在Scratch，像这样。
And indeed, this is why today we focus on and begin
事实上，这就是为什么今天我们关注和开始
with Scratch, this graphical programming language,
使用Scratch，这种图形编程语言，
so we have a way of expressing ourselves with functions, conditionals, loops,
所以我们可以用函数，条件，循环来表达自己，
and more, but in a way that doesn't have stupid parentheses and curly braces
更多，但没有愚蠢的括号和大括号
and all of these visual distractions in the way
所有这些视觉上的干扰
and will translate that thereafter to this lower-level language.
然后将其翻译成这种低级语言。
But for now, that was a lot.
但就目前而言，这是很多。
That was definitely a fire hose.
那绝对是消防水带。
Let's go ahead and take a 10-minute break.
我们休息10分钟吧。
Feel free to get up or stay here.
随意起床或留在这里。
And we'll resume in a bit with some actual code.
稍后我们将继续进行一些实际的代码。
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频播放]
[MUSIC - THE WEATHER GIRLS, "IT'S  RAINING MEN"] [MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐-天气女孩，“这是男人下雨”][音乐播放]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[雷声隆隆]
- (SINGING) Hi.
- （唱）嗨。
Hi.
你好。
We're your Weather Girls, and have we got news for you.
我们是你们的天气预报员，我们有消息要告诉你们。
You better listen.
你最好听着。
Get ready, all you lonely girls.
准备好了，你们这些孤独的女孩。
And leave those umbrellas at home.
把那些雨伞留在家里。
All right.
好吧。
Humidity is rising.
湿度正在上升。
Hmm, rising.
嗯，上升。
Barometer's getting low.
晴雨表越来越低。
How low, girl?
姑娘，多低？
According to all sources--
根据所有消息来源——
what sources, now-- the street's the place to go.
什么来源，现在-街道是去的地方。
We better hurry up.
我们最好快点。
'Cause tonight, for the first
“因为今晚，第一次
half-past 10:00-- for the first time in history,
10：00过半——历史上第一次，
it's going to start raining men-- start raining men!
开始下雨，开始下雨！
It's raining men, hallelujah!
下雨了，哈利路亚！
It's raining men, amen!
下雨了，阿门！
I'm going to go out.
我要出去。
I'm going to let myself get absolutely soaking wet!
我要让自己完全湿透了！
It's raining men, hallelujah!
下雨了，哈利路亚！
DAVID J. MALAN: [CHUCKLES] All right, so--
DAVID J. MALAN：（轻笑）好吧，所以——
[END PLAYBACK]
[结束播放]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So this then is Scratch, a graphical programming language from our friends
这就是Scratch，我们朋友的图形编程语言
down the road at MIT's Media Lab that indeed some of you
在麻省理工学院的媒体实验室，你们中的一些人
might have used in grade school or the like,
可能用在小学或类似的地方,
for playing and writing code and the like,
用于玩和编写代码之类的,
but you maybe didn't necessarily think about how some of these primitives
但是你可能没有考虑到这些原始人
ultimately worked.
最终奏效了。
And in fact, everything you've done-- if you've used Scratch before--
事实上，你所做的一切如果你以前用过刮擦
and everything you'll see today is going to apply to all of the weeks to come,
你们今天看到的一切都将适用于接下来的几周,
as we explore these things called "functions"
当我们探索这些叫做“函数”的东西时
and "loops" and "conditionals," "Boolean expressions" and more.
以及“循环”、“条件句”、“布尔表达式”等等。
With Scratch, because it's so graphical and animated-congruent,
使用 Scratch，因为它是如此的图形化和动画一致,
can you create animations, like this one, interactive art, and software
你能创造动画，像这个，互动艺术，和软件
more generally.
更一般地说。
But you'll do so by dragging and dropping
但是你可以通过拖拽和下降来达到这个目的
puzzle pieces that only lock together if it makes logical sense to do so.
只有在合乎逻辑的情况下才会拼在一起的拼图块。
And you won't have to deal with, in this first week of class,
你们不用在第一周的课上面对,
is curly braces, parentheses, all of the weird symbology
是花括号，括号，所有这些奇怪的符号
that you might recall seeing, when we just wanted to say, "Hello, world."
你可能还记得，当我们只是想说“你好，世界”的时候
Now, this particular program, "Raining Men,"
现在，这个特别的节目“雨人”
was written by a former CS50 teaching fellow, Andrew Berry,
作者是 CS50前教师 Andrew Berry,
who's actually now the general manager of the Cleveland
他现在是克利夫兰的总经理
Browns, the American football team.
布朗斯，美式橄榄球队。
And so these are just some of the programs
这些只是其中的一些程序
that some of your predecessors in the class have created.
你们班上的一些前辈创造的。
And you'll see, in the remainder of class here, a couple of others
你们会看到，在剩下的课程中，还有其他一些
as well, and more in the course's first assignment, namely, problem set zero.
同样，在本课程的第一个作业中，也就是问题集0中也有更多的内容。
So how do we get there?
那么我们如何到达那里呢？
Well, first a quick tour of what it is we're going to do.
好吧，首先我们简单介绍一下接下来要做的事情。
This, in Scratch, is perhaps the simplest program you can write.
在 Scratch 中，这可能是你能编写的最简单的程序。
And even if you've never seen Scratch or any programming language before,
即使你以前从未见过 Scratch 或任何编程语言,
you can probably guess that this just says, on the screen somehow,
你大概能猜到，屏幕上显示的是,
"Hello, World."
“你好，世界。”
But what you don't have to do is type esoteric commands and weird syntax,
但是你不需要输入深奥的命令和奇怪的语法,
those curly braces and parentheses I keep alluding to.
我一直暗示的那些花括号和括号。
You just drag this yellow puzzle piece.
你只需拖动这个黄色拼图。
You drag this purple puzzle piece.
你拖动这个紫色的拼图。
Let them magnetically lock together, so to speak.
可以说，让它们磁性地锁在一起。
Click a button and boom.
单击按钮并动臂。
With those same building blocks and several others,
有了这些积木和其他一些东西,
can you make exactly the sorts of things that Andrew brought to life as well.
你能做出安德鲁创造出来的东西吗。
So here's what we're about to see.
这就是我们将要看到的。
At Scratch.MIT.edu is a cloud-based programming environment on MIT servers.
Edu 是 MIT 服务器上的一个基于云的编程环境。
You can also download it offline on your own Mac or PC.
你也可以在自己的 Mac 或 PC 上离线下载。
And it gives you an interface like this.
它为你提供了这样的界面。
On the left-hand side of the screen, you'll see a blocks palette.
在屏幕的左侧，你将看到一个方块调色板。
These puzzle pieces, a.k.a. blocks, come in different colors
这些拼图块，也叫积木，有不同的颜色
which rather categorize them.
而是对它们进行分类。
So pictured here, for instance, in blue, are
比如这张蓝色的照片
a whole bunch of motion-related blocks.
一大堆与运动相关的块。
So Andrew used a whole bunch of those to have the singer and the men
所以安德鲁用了一大堆这样的东西让歌手和男人们
moving around on the screen in synchronicity
在屏幕上同步移动
with the song that was playing in the background.
背景音乐。
Meanwhile, in the middle of this interface is going to be the code area.
同时，在这个接口的中间是代码区。
And this is where Andrew, and soon you, will drag and drop
这就是安德鲁，很快还有你，将要下坠的地方
some of those puzzle pieces and other colors as well
还有一些拼图和其他颜色
and lock them together to get your character-- soon
然后把它们锁在一起，很快就能得到你的角色了
to be invented-- to do something on the screen.
被发明出来，在屏幕上做点什么。
Indeed, at the bottom right here, will you see, ultimately,
事实上，在这里的底部，你会看到，最终,
a sprite area, where a sprite is a technical term
精灵区，精灵是一个专业术语
for like a character in a video game or a programming environment like this.
比如电子游戏中的角色，或者像这样的编程环境。
By default, historically, Scratch is the cat, the mascot, if you will,
默认情况下，从历史上看，抓挠先生是猫，吉祥物，如果你愿意的话,
for this programming environment.
对于此编程环境。
And so here we see, by default, just one sprite
这里我们看到，默认情况下，只有一个精灵
selected because on the top right of the screen is the stage for that sprite.
选择是因为屏幕右上角是精灵的舞台。
And you can click and zoom in to make it full screen.
你可以点击并放大，使它成为全屏。
But this is the world in which Scratch--
但这就是Scratch的世界——
by default, the cat-- will live.
默认情况下，猫 - 将活着。
But you can change Scratch's costume so that it looks like a singer or the man
但是你可以改变刮擦的服装，让它看起来像一个歌手或男人
falling from the sky or the like or anything else,
从天而降之类的,
either creating the art yourself or importing some of the things that
要么自己创作，要么引进一些
come with it or elsewhere online.
随身携带或在线其他地方。
So what is this world that Scratch rather lives in?
那么刮擦生活在什么样的世界里呢？
Well, generally speaking, we won't have to care too much about numbers
一般来说，我们不需要太在意数字
because we'll be able to ask questions, like interactive ones,
因为我们可以问问题，比如互动问题,
like is Scratch the cat, or any character
就像是抓猫，或者任何角色
otherwise, touching the edge of the screen, touching something else?
否则，触摸屏幕边缘，触摸其他东西？
But Scratch does exist in this two-dimensional coordinate-system
但刮擦确实存在于这个二维坐标系中
world.
世界。
So when the cat or any character is dead center in the middle,
所以当猫或者任何角色在中间的时候,
that would be xy location 0,0, if you will.
那就是 xy 位置0,0，如果你愿意的话。
Meanwhile, over here is 240 pixels, or dots, all the way to the right.
同时，这里是240像素，或点，一直到右边。
So this would be 240,0, where y is 0 because it's right on that midline.
所以这是240，这里 y 是0因为它就在中线上。
So it's neither up or below.
所以它既不是向上也不是低于。
Over here to the left, of course, would be -240 and 0.
这里左边，当然是 -240和0。
Above the cat would be x equals 0, because it's
在猫的上方是 x 等于0，因为它是
right on that vertical midline, and 180.
就在那个垂直的中线上，和180。
And then down here, as you might guess, would be 0, negative 180.
然后这里，你可能猜到了，是0，负180。
Generally speaking, we don't have to care
一般来说，我们不需要在乎
about those precise pixel coordinates.
关于那些精确的像素坐标。
But it's helpful, ultimately, if you do want the cat to move up, down, left,
但这是有帮助的，最终，如果你想让猫向上，向下，向左移动,
or right.
或对。
Having some sense of direction according to the x-axis and y-axis
根据 x 轴和 y 轴有方向感的
as well can help you express your ideas, ultimately.
也可以帮助你表达你的想法，最终。
So what might some of those ideas be?
那么其中一些想法可能是什么？
Well, let's do this.
好吧，让我们这样做。
I'm going to go ahead and create, on Scratch.MIT.edu, just
我将继续创建，在 Scratch.MIT. edu 上
an empty screen like this one here.
像这样的空屏幕在这里。
And so this is the exact same interface.
所以这是完全相同的界面。
But now I'm in my browser, full screen, so that I can start writing some code.
但现在我在浏览器里，全屏，这样我就可以开始写代码了。
And let's get that cat to say something actually on the screen.
让那只猫在屏幕上说点什么。
Now, this takes a little bit of practice.
这需要一点练习。
But honestly, just by scrolling through these puzzle pieces can
但老实说，只要翻阅这些拼图就可以
you quickly get a sense of what's possible, not just categorically,
你很快就会知道什么是可能的，不仅仅是绝对的,
but specifically.
但具体来说。
And I'll jump around because I've done this, of course, before.
我会跳来跳去，因为我以前也这么做过。
But I'm going to go to events, in yellow, first.
但我要先穿黄色去参加活动。
And I'm going to drag and drop this first block, called
我将拖放第一个块，命名为
when Green Flag clicked.
当绿旗点击时。
And I've zoomed in there just to make it a little more legible.
我把它放大了，让它更清晰一点。
And notice that the shape of this Green Flag
注意这个绿旗的形状
just so happens to mirror this Green Flag here
正好反映了这个绿旗
at top, next to this red Stop Sign, of sorts.
最上面，红色的停车标志旁边。
And the Green Flag is going to mean go and the red Stop Sign
绿旗代表开车，红色的停车标志
is going to mean stop, to start or stop our program.
将意味着停止，启动或停止我们的计划。
Next week, you're going to be writing a textual command at your keyboard
下周，你将在键盘上编写一个文本命令
to do the exact same idea.
做完全相同的想法。
But for now, it's a button.
但就目前而言，它是一个按钮。
So when Green Flag clicked, what do I want Scratch to do?
那么当绿旗点击时，我想让 Scratch 做什么呢？
Well, how about we have Scratch just initially say something like, "Hello,
不如让刮擦先说“你好”
world," which indeed, historically, is the first program
的确，从历史上看，这是第一个
that most any programmer might write.
大多数程序员都可能写。
So anything related to what the cat looks like it's doing
所以任何与猫的行为相关的东西
is actually going to be under looks, here in purple.
实际上会穿紫色的衣服。
So I'm going to drag over Say "hello."
所以我要拖过去说“你好”。
And you'll notice something curious and different about this purple block.
你会注意到这个紫色块有些奇怪和不同的地方。
It says, of course, "Say" in purple.
当然，它用紫色写着“说”。
But then there's this white oval and some text that, by default, is "hello"
但是还有这个白色椭圆和一些默认是“ hello”的文字
because MIT just decided that, by default, the placeholder will
因为麻省理工刚刚决定，默认情况下，占位符将
be "hello."
“你好”。
But anytime you see this white oval, it's
但是当你看到这个白色的椭圆形时
an opportunity to provide an input into the function called Say.
提供一个输入到名为 Say 的函数中的机会。
And so here I'm borrowing terminology from before.
这里我借用了之前的术语。
Problem solving, again, is all about inputs producing outputs.
同样，解决问题的关键在于投入产出。
And in between there is some algorithm.
中间有一些算法。
In a moment, we're going to start referring to algorithms
稍后，我们将开始讨论算法
quite frequently as "functions."
经常作为“函数”。
Why?
为什么？
Because it's the implementation of some algorithm.
因为这是某种算法的实现。
So let me override the default with, "Hello, world."
让我用“ Hello，world”覆盖默认值
I'll zoom out.
我会缩小。
And now if I go to the top right of the screen and click the Green Flag,
现在如果我到屏幕右上角点击绿旗,
we'll see, hopefully, my very first program in code.
希望我们能看到我的第一个代码程序。
Now, it wasn't a huge lift, right?
现在，这不是一个巨大的提升，对吧？
It only was a matter of dragging and dropping puzzle pieces.
这只是一个拖放拼图块的问题。
But what has now happened?
但是现在发生了什么？
Well, it turns out that two things have happened.
结果发生了两件事。
When I, the human, clicked on that Green Flag,
当我，那个人类，点击那个绿旗时,
I triggered, what we're going to start calling now, an "event."
我触发了，我们现在要称之为“事件”
An event is generally something graphical or interactive that
事件通常是图形化的或交互式的
just happens in a computer program.
只是发生在计算机程序中。
You and I trigger events on our phones all day long.
你和我每天都在手机上触发事件。
Whenever you tap or drag or long press or pinch
无论你什么时候点击，拖拽，长按或捏
or any of those gestures in vogue nowadays on phones,
或者手机上流行的那些手势,
you are triggering events.
你正在触发事件。
And people at Apple and Google and elsewhere
还有苹果，谷歌和其他公司的人
have written code that listen for those events
编写了监听这些事件的代码
and do something when that event happens.
然后在事情发生的时候做点什么。
That's what I just did.
这就是我刚刚所做的。
When Green Flag is clicked, I want something
当点击绿旗时，我想要一些东西
to happen, namely, I want this purple function, this verb, this action called
也就是说，我想要这个紫色的函数，这个动词，这个动作叫做
Say, to do something.
说，做点什么。
What do I want it to do?
我希望它做什么？
I want it to say what this input is.
我希望它说出这个输入是什么。
And I'm going to introduce another vocabulary term.
我将介绍另一个词汇。
The white ovals here are, yes, inputs, very generically.
这里的白色椭圆，是的，输入，非常一般。
But in a programmer's terminology, they're
但用程序员的术语来说
called "arguments," otherwise known as "parameters."
称为“参数”，也称为“参数”
And that just means an input to a function
这意味着一个函数的输入
that modifies its behavior in some way.
这以某种方式修改了它的行为。
When I click Stop, that's just another event.
当我单击 Stop 时，这只是另一个事件。
And that one is just built into Scratch.
而那个只是内置在Scratch中。
Scratch knows that when you click the green Stop Sign,
刮擦知道当你点击绿色的停止标志时,
everything should just stop automatically.
一切都会自动停止。
I don't have to write code to support that feature.
我不需要编写代码来支持这个特性。
So that's all fine and good, "Hello, world."
所以这一切都很好，“你好，世界。”
But if I keep doing stop and start and stop and start,
但如果我一直这样，停停停,
it's going to do the same thing again and again.
它会一次又一次地做同样的事情。
And it's really not that interesting, at the end of the day,
其实也没什么意思，说到底,
maybe gratifying once, but it'd be nice if this were a little more interactive.
也许有一次很让人满意，但如果能多一点互动就更好了。
So it turns out that we can do that too.
所以事实证明，我们也可以这样做。
But we need a different mental model instead.
但我们需要一个不同的思维模式。
So in this case here, when we think about this function,
在这个例子中，当我们考虑这个函数时,
Say, in this input, "Hello, world," this actually
在这个输入中，“ Hello，world”实际上
maps pretty cleanly to this model earlier,
与之前的模型非常吻合,
that I propose is problem solving, is computer science, if you will.
我认为是解决问题，是计算机科学，如果你愿意。
The input to the current problem is going to be in white here,
当前问题的输入是白色的,
"Hello, world."
“你好，世界。”
The algorithm is the "say" algorithm.
该算法是“说”算法。
Now, I don't know how MIT got it to print out the little, pretty speech
现在，我不知道麻省理工是怎么把这个漂亮的演讲稿打印出来的
bubble on the screen.
屏幕上冒泡。
But they wrote those underlying low-level implementation details.
但是他们编写了那些底层的实现细节。
And they gave me and you a purple function, called Say,
他们给了我和你一个紫色函数，叫做,
that just does that for you.
那只是为你做这件事。
You and I don't have to reinvent that wheel.
你和我不必重新发明轮子。
The output of Say is another technical term, now, called a "side effect."
Say 的输出是另一个技术术语，现在称为“副作用”
A side effect is usually something visual that happens,
副作用通常是视觉上的,
like as a side effect of you calling a function.
比如你调用函数的副作用。
And so the side effect here is that the cat
所以这里的副作用是猫
has this speech bubble magically appear, inside of which is "Hello, world."
就会神奇地出现这个语音泡泡里面是“你好，世界”
So we have an input.
所以我们有一个输入。
We have an output.
我们有一个输出。
We have an algorithm.
我们有一个算法。
But now we're talking about these ideas in the context of programming.
但是现在我们在编程的背景下讨论这些想法。
So now the input is an "argument."
所以现在输入是一个“参数”。
The algorithm is a "function."
该算法是一个“函数”。
And the output, in this case, is a "side effect"--
在这种情况下，输出是一个“副作用”——
terminology that you'll just hear more and more.
你会听到越来越多的术语。
And it'll eventually sink in, but not to worry if the terminology doesn't
最终会理解的，不过不用担心术语不理解
come naturally early on.
很早就自然而然地来了。
So what more might I do with this?
那么我还能用这个做什么呢？
Let me go back to Scratch here and make this maybe perhaps more interactive
让我们回到 Scratch 这里，让它更具互动性
and actually get the cat to say something a little more dynamically.
实际上让猫说一些更动态的东西。
So instead of "Hello, world," why don't we
所以与其说"你好，世界"不如我们
get him to say hello to me or to you or anyone else?
让他跟我或你或其他人打招呼?
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
Let me go under, say--
让我下，说——
let me get rid of this first.
让我先摆脱这个。
And you'll notice this neat trick.
你会注意到这个巧妙的技巧。
As soon as you start dragging on a block, if it gets close to it,
一旦你开始拖拽一个方块，如果它靠近它，
it kind of goes gray, and it can be magnetically snapped together.
它会变成灰色，并且可以被磁力合在一起。
You don't have to do it very precisely.
你不必非常精确地执行此操作。
Conversely, if I want to get rid of a puzzle piece,
相反，如果我想去掉一块拼图，
I can just drag it anywhere on the left, let go, and that deletes it.
我可以把它拖到左边的任何地方，然后放手，这样就会删除它。
Or you can Right-click or Control-click and a little menu
或者你可以右键单击或者Control-click，然后出现一个小菜单
will let you delete it as well.
也会让你删除它。
Well, let me do this instead.
好吧，让我来做这个。
Under Sensing, which I know is there because I've done this before,
在感应下，我知道它在那里，因为我以前做过这个，
are a whole bunch of things related to Sensing, whereby the cat can kind
是不是有很多东西都与感应有关，猫可以通过感应来说话
of feel out its world, in some sense.
在某种意义上感受它的世界。
It can do things like ask this question, "Am I touching the mouse pointer?"--
它可以问这样的问题，“我触摸到鼠标指针了吗?”--
like the user's cursor.
就像用户的光标一样。
"Am I touching a specific color that you can override to be anything you want?"
“我是否触碰到了一个特定的颜色，你可以改写成任何你想要的颜色?”
"Is the distance to the mouse pointer some specific value?"
“到鼠标指针的距离是某个特定值吗?”
But for now, I'm going to focus on this, this blue puzzle piece that
但现在，我要关注的是这个，这个蓝色的拼图
asks a question, which itself is this white oval that I can apparently
问了一个问题，它本身就是这个白色的椭圆形，我可以
change, and then it's going to wait for a response.
改变，然后等待响应。
But this puzzle piece is a little different.
但这个拼图有点不同。
It's a little special.
这有点特别。
It comes with a freebie.
它带有免费赠品。
It comes with what we're going to call, technically, a "return value."
从技术上讲，它带有一个“返回值”
So some functions don't just do something on the screen.
有些函数不只是在屏幕上做一些事情。
They hand you back, so to speak, a value that you
可以这么说，他们还给了你一个价值
can do anything that you want with.
可以做任何你想做的事情。
Nothing happens immediately unless you do something
没有什么事情会立即发生，除非你做些什么
with that so-called return value.
具有所谓的返回值。
So let me go ahead and drag this thing over here, ask, "What's your name?"
我把这个拖到这里，问"你叫什么名字?"
And I'll use the default question.
我将使用默认问题。
That seems a reasonable place to start.
这似乎是一个合理的起点。
I'm not going to override that default. And now let me go ahead and zoom out.
我不会重写这个默认值。现在我把它缩小。
Let me go back to Looks.
让我回到外观。
Let me go to Say.
让我去说。
And let me just form the English sentence I want.
让我来组成我想要的英语句子。
So let me zoom in here and type in "hello," maybe comma, space.
让我放大这里，输入"hello "也许是逗号，空格。
I could do "David," but that's obviously not right
我可以叫大卫，但那显然不对
because I'm asking for a name, and then I'm like,
因为我想要一个名字，然后我说，
in advance, hard-coding my name.
事先，硬编码我的名字。
That's not what I want.
那不是我想要的。
I just want, "hello," comma.
我只想要，“你好，”逗号。
And now let me zoom out and grab one more Say block.
现在我把它缩小，再抓取一个block。
Let me maybe Say here.
让我在这里说。
OK, I don't want to say, "Hello, hello."
好吧，我不想说，“你好，你好。
I don't want to just type in my own name because, again, then
我不想只输入自己的名字，因为
what's the point of asking the user for their name?
问用户名字有什么意义?
But notice this.
但请注意这一点。
If I go back to the sensing block, this is where that oval that's blue,
如果我回到感应块，这就是那个蓝色的椭圆形，
called Answer, is useful.
叫答案，是有用的。
This will be the so-called "return value" of that function.
这将是该函数的所谓“返回值”。
So I'm just going to go ahead and do this and drag and drop.
我要做这个，拖放。
Even though it's not the right size, it is the right shape.
虽然它的大小不对，但它的形状是对的。
And so Scratch will be smart about it and grow
所以Scratch会很聪明，并且会成长
to fill that puzzle piece for you.
为你填补这块拼图。
Let me zoom out now.
现在让我缩小。
And now let me click the Green Flag.
现在让我点击绿旗。
You'll see that Scratch is indeed prompting me with a speech bubble,
你会看到Scratch确实在用一个语音泡泡提示我，
"What's your name?"
“你叫什么名字？”
Notice the little text box below the cat is asking, what's your name?
注意猫下面的小文本框在问，你叫什么名字?
So I'm going to type in D-A-V-I-D and hit Enter.
所以我要输入D-A-V-I-D然后回车。
Or I can click the blue check.
或者我可以点击蓝色复选标记。
Enter.
进入。
OK, it's a little weird.
好吧，这有点奇怪。
I wanted him to say, "hello," not just my name.
我想让他打招呼，而不仅仅是叫我的名字。
So let me Stop.
所以让我停下来。
Let me start it again.
让我重新开始。
All right, hello, what's your name?
好吧，你好，你叫什么名字？
D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
D-A-V-I-D.进入。
Huh-- kind of rude.
呵呵——有点粗鲁。
Why is there this bug?
为什么会有这个错误？
Like, I wanted to say, "Hello, David," not just "David."
我想说"你好，大卫"而不仅仅是"大卫"
And yet twice it has failed to do so.
然而，它两次未能做到这一点。
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, the computer's processing my directions,
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，计算机正在处理我的方向，
my actions, really quickly.
我的行动，真的很快。
And so it actually is doing it.
所以它实际上正在这样做。
It's just, you and I, in the room, are just way
只是，你和我，在这个房间里，只是
too slow to notice that it said-- (QUICKLY) "Hello, David."
太慢了，没有注意到上面写着——(迅速地)“你好,大卫。”
It just seems to have just said, "David."
上面好像只写了"大卫"
So all right, how can I fix this?
那么好吧，我该如何解决这个问题？
Well, here's where you start to poke around and think
好吧，这就是你开始摸索和思考的地方
about how you might solve this.
关于如何解决这个问题。
Let me go back under Looks.
让我回到外观下。
Maybe there's a smarter way to do this.
也许有一种更聪明的方法可以做到这一点。
Maybe I could do--
也许我能做到——
OK, I could do this.
好的，我可以这样做。
How about instead of just Say "hello," there's
别只说"你好"了怎么样
apparently another puzzle piece where I can time it so I can maybe slow things
显然是另一个我可以计时的拼图，这样我就可以放慢速度
down a little bit.
往下一点。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
Let me throw away all of this.
让我抛弃这一切。
Let me drag a Say "hello" for 2 seconds.
让我拖一个说“你好”2秒钟。
Let me drag another Say "hello" for 2 seconds.
让我再拖一个，说“你好”2秒钟。
Let me change the first one to, indeed, "hello" comma.
我把第一个改成，"hello"逗号。
And then let me go back to Sensing.
然后让我回到感应。
Let me grab that same answer because I threw it away a second ago,
让我抓住同样的答案，因为我刚把它扔掉了，
and I'll just change it.
我会改变它。
I don't even have to delete "hello."
我什至不必删除“你好”。
I can just overwrite it like this.
我可以这样覆盖它。
So now I think we'll kind of pump the brakes and see things more slowly.
所以现在我想我们应该停下脚步，慢慢地看问题。
Let me Stop.
让我停下来。
Let me start.
让我开始吧。
D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
D-A-V-I-D，输入。
Hello, David.
你好，大卫。
OK, so it's better, like it seems to be working.
好了，看起来好多了，好像起作用了。
I think your hypothesis was right, just looks kind of stupid, right?
我认为你的假设是对的，只是看起来有点傻，对吧?
Like, the fact that it's saying Hello--
就像，它在说你好——
[PAUSE]
[暂停]
--David, like we can do better.
--大卫，好像我们可以做得更好。
And like, literally every piece of software on your phone or Mac or PC
就像你手机、Mac或PC上的每一个软件一样
is better than that.
比这更好。
It adds words together in the user interfaces you and I are familiar with.
它在你和我都熟悉的用户界面中添加单词。
So let's go a little more fishing here.
所以让我们在这里多钓鱼一点。
Let me throw away these.
让我扔掉这些。
Let me go back to Looks and just get the simpler Say.
让我回到look，用更简单的Say。
I want this to say, "Hello" comma name, where name
我想让它说，"Hello"，逗号name, where name
comes from that Answer return value.
来自该答案返回值。
So how can I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me go under Operations, which we haven't been before.
那就让我去行动组吧，我们以前从没去过。
There's a lot of stuff in here.
这里面有很多东西。
Some of it's mathematically related, adding, subtracting, and so forth.
有些是数学相关的，加减法，等等。
You can generate random numbers which might be useful.
你可以生成随机数，这可能很有用。
And if I keep scrolling down, there's this Join "apple" and "banana."
如果我继续往下滚动，就会看到"苹果"和"香蕉"
But that's just placeholder text.
但这只是占位符文本。
You can join one piece of text with another piece of text,
你可以把一段文字和另一段文字连接起来，
by default "apple" and "banana."
默认情况下，“苹果”和“香蕉”。
But let's change it to "hello" and my name.
但让我们把它改成"你好"和我的名字。
So this, too, wrong size but right shape.
所以这个也是，大小不对但形状正确。
So let me let it snap into place.
所以让我让它卡入到位。
Let me go ahead now and do "hello" comma.
让我继续写"hello"逗号。
And now I think I just want to go grab that Answer return value.
现在我想去获取那个Answer返回值。
Let me drag the same oval as before, clobber--
我再拖一个和之前一样的椭圆
that is, overwrite-- banana.
也就是说，覆盖 - 香蕉。
So now I'm kind of composing functions.
所以现在我有点组合函数。
The output of one function, Join, is going
函数Join的输出是这样的
to be the input of another function, Say.
作为另一个函数的输入，比如说。
So let's see what happens now that they're kind of stacked on top
让我们看看现在发生了什么它们堆在了上面
of each other or nested, so to speak.
可以这么说，彼此或嵌套。
Click the Green Flag, D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
单击绿色旗帜，D-A-V-I-D。进入。
"Hello, David."
“你好，大卫。”
All right, that was pretty fast.
好吧，这很快。
Let's just do it once more.
让我们再做一次。
Stop.
停。
Start.
开始。
Here we go, D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
我们开始了，D-A-V-I-D。进入。
OK.
还行。
All right, it's not the most exciting program in the world.
好吧，这不是世界上最刺激的节目。
But it's more correct.
但它更正确。
It's better designed just because that's what you would kind of expect
它设计得更好，因为这是你所期望的
the software to do and not be some kind of lame user interface that's just
软件的功能，而不是一些蹩脚的用户界面，只是
inserting random delays to just make it kind of work, like that's
插入随机延迟来让它正常工作，就像这样
a workaround, a hack, if you will.
一个解决方法，一个黑客，如果你愿意的话。
But there's some cool things you can do with Scratch.
但是你可以用Scratch做一些很酷的事情。
And we won't really go down the rabbit hole
我们不会真的掉进兔子洞
of all of the fun and family-friendly features that it has.
所有的有趣和适合家庭的功能。
But there is one that's kind of cool here.
但这里有一个很酷。
Let me go into the Extensions button at the bottom left of my screen.
让我进入屏幕左下角的扩展按钮。
And this one's kind of cool.
这个有点酷。
Let me go to Text to Speech.
让我转到文本到语音。
And you'll notice that this one requires internet because it's cloud based.
你会注意到这个需要互联网，因为它是基于云的。
But this just gave me some new puzzle pieces in a new category,
但这只是给了我一个新类别的新拼图，
Text to Speech.
文本到语音转换。
And these green ones do exactly what they say.
而这些绿色的确实言出必行。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
Let me zoom out again.
让我再缩小一下。
Let me keep the Join block.
让我保留联接块。
And I'm just going to temporarily toss it over here.
我暂时把它扔到这里。
It's not going to delete itself because I didn't drag it over
它不会自我删除，因为我没有拖拽它
to the other side.
到另一边。
But I'm going to get rid of the Say block, in purple.
但是我要把Say方块去掉，用紫色表示。
I'm going to do the Speak block here, in green, and let it snap into place.
我要在这里画出Speak方块，用绿色，让它固定到位。
And then I'm going to drag and drop this onto the input to Speak.
然后我要把这个拖放到Speak的输入上。
And now, perhaps a little more adorably, let's try this.
现在，也许更可爱一点，让我们试试这个。
Green Flag, what's your name?
绿旗，你叫什么名字？
D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
D-A-V-I-D.进入。
And--
和--
COMPUTER: Hello, David.
计算机：你好，大卫。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
It's a little robotic.
有点机器人。
But at least now it has synthesized speech.
但至少现在它有了合成语音。
And I've kind of got my own, like, Siri or Google Assistant or Alexa
我也有自己的Siri、谷歌助手或Alexa
thing going on here now, where it's now recognized whatever text
现在这里发生的事情，现在可以识别任何文本
it is, and it's played it.
它是，它被播放了。
Well, let's make this an actual cat that doesn't talk in that weird human voice.
好吧，让我们把它变成一只真正的猫，它不会用那种奇怪的人类声音说话。
Let me go ahead and get rid of most of this stuff.
让我先把这些东西擦掉。
And let's get the cat to actually meow, like a cat tends to.
让这只猫真正地喵喵叫，就像猫一样。
And let me go under the Sounds block.
让我进入声音块。
Now MIT gives you a few sounds for free because it's designed around a cat,
现在麻省理工学院给你一些免费的声音，因为它是围绕一只猫设计的，
by default. And I'm going to go ahead and grab
默认情况下。我将继续抓取
this one, Play Sound Meow until done.
这个，播放声音喵喵直到完成。
And now-- and we heard a teaser for this earlier in the crowd--
现在——我们之前在人群中听到了一个预告片——
[MEOW]
[喵]
It's a little piercing, admittedly.
诚然，这有点刺耳。
Maybe we can lower the volume a little bit there.
也许我们可以把这里的音量调低一点。
But notice, if I want the cat to meow a second time, I'll just click it again.
但请注意，如果我想让猫再次喵喵叫，我只需再次点击它。
[MEOW]
[喵]
OK, and over there, too, I hear--
好吧，在那边，我也听到了——
[MEOW]
[喵]
OK.
还行。
[MEOW]
[喵]
All right, so it's kind of cute now, right?
好了，现在看起来挺可爱的，对吧?
So it's just meow--
所以只是喵喵——
OK, yes, echo, echo.
好的，是的，回声，回声。
So it's meowing now every time I hit the Green Flag.
所以现在每次我打到绿旗它都会叫。
Now, that's great, but even a kid is probably going to--
这很好，但即使是孩子也可能会
[MEOW]
[喵]
--like would prefer that it--
--喜欢它--
[MEOW]
[喵]
--just meow, perhaps, like again and again, without having to keep--
——只是喵喵，也许，就像一遍又一遍，不用保持——
[MEOW]
[喵]
--hitting the button.
--按下按钮。
So how might we do this?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
All right, well, if I want it to meow multiple times, why don't I just, like,
好吧，如果我想让它多次喵喵叫，为什么我不直接，比如，
grab it another time and another time?
再抓一次又一次？
Alternatively, you can Right-click or Control-click a puzzle piece
或者，你可以右键单击或Control-click拼图块
and just duplicate it from a little menu that drops down.
然后从下拉菜单中复制它。
So here we go, three meows.
所以我们来了，三声喵喵。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
All right, that's not really a happy cat.
好吧，这只猫可不怎么开心。
It sounds maybe hungry.
听起来可能饿了。
So can we slow that down?
那么我们可以放慢速度吗？
Well, maybe.
好吧，也许吧。
In fact, if I poke around, let me go under Control.
事实上，如果我四处乱戳，让我在控制下。
It looks like there's a Wait block.
看起来有一个等待块。
Wait 1 Second, by default. And notice, Scratch will be pretty accommodating.
缺省值为1秒。注意，Scratch是很方便的。
If you just hover in between blocks, it will grow to fill that too.
如果你只是悬停在块之间，它也会填满。
So I could change it to 1 or 2 or anything, seconds.
所以我可以把它改成1或2或任何东西，秒。
I'll just leave it at the default for now, 1.
我现在让它保持默认值，1。
And now I'll go ahead and do this.
现在我继续做这个。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
OK, so cuter and less hungry and just more friendly.
好吧，更可爱，更不饿，更友好。
But this isn't the best design.
但这不是最好的设计。
It is correct.
这是正确的。
And let's use that as a term of art.
让我们把它作为一个艺术术语。
Correct means the code does what you want it to do.
正确意味着代码做了你想让它做的事情。
I want the cat to meow three times slowly.
我想让猫慢慢地喵喵叫三次。
And it did.
它确实做到了。
So I'd wager this is correct.
所以我敢打赌这是正确的。
But it's not the best design.
但这不是最好的设计。
And this is where things get more subjective, right?
这就是事情变得更加主观的地方，对吧?
Like, you could write accurate sentences in an essay for an English class,
比如，你可以在英语课的作文中写出准确的句子，
but otherwise, it's just completely a mess.
但除此之外，它完全是一团乱。
Like, your arguments here and there, and you don't say anything wrong,
比如，你的争论到处都是，你没有说错任何话，
but you don't say it well.
但你说得不好。
In the context of code, we can do better than this.
在代码上下文中，我们可以做得更好。
And Copy/Paste or repeating yourself again and again tends
复制/粘贴或者一遍又一遍地重复
to be bad practice.
是不好的做法。
Why?
为什么？
Suppose that you want to change the Wait to 2 seconds instead of 1.
假设你希望将Wait更改为2秒而不是1秒。
It's admittedly not a big deal.
诚然，这没什么大不了的。
Fine, I click there, I change it to 2.
很好，我单击那里，将其更改为 2。
I click there, I change it to 2.
我单击那里，将其更改为 2。
But what if you meow 5 times, 10 times?
但是如果你喵喵叫 5 次、10 次怎么办？
Now I have to change the Wait, like, in 5, 10 different places.
现在我得改一下等等，大概要改5到10个地方。
Like, that's just stupid.
就像，那只是愚蠢的。
It's taking unnecessary human time, and you're going to screw up eventually,
这会占用不必要的人力时间，而且你最终会搞砸的，
especially if your program is getting longer.
特别是如果你的节目越来越长。
You're going to miss one of the inputs.
你将错过其中一个输入。
You're going to leave the number wrong.
你会把数字留错。
And that's a bug.
这是一个错误。
So just based on what you've seen already
基于你们已经看到的
or if you've program before, which a few of you have,
或者如果你以前编过程序，你们中的一些人编过，
what's the term of art here that will solve this?
解决这个问题的术语是什么?
How can we design this better?
我们如何才能更好地设计它？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: I heard it here.
DAVID J. MALAN：我在这里听到了。
Yeah, so a loop-- a loop, some kind of cycle that says, do that again.
是的，一个循环，一个循环，某种循环说，再做一次。
Do that again-- not infinitely many times, necessarily,
再做一次——不一定是无限次，
but some finite number.
而是一些有限的数字。
Well, you can perhaps see a spoiler on the screen.
嗯，你可能会在屏幕上看到剧透。
Under the same orange Control category is a Repeat block.
在同一个橙色控制类别下是一个重复块。
And by default, it's proposing 10.
默认情况下，它建议 10 个。
But we can change that.
但我们可以改变这一点。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
I'm going to throw away most of this Copy/Paste as redundant.
我打算把复制/粘贴的大部分内容都扔掉，因为它们是多余的。
I'm going to detach this temporarily just to make room for something else.
我要暂时把这个分离出来给别的东西腾出空间。
And I'm going to drag a Repeat block over here and let that snap into place.
我要拖一个Repeat block到这里让它固定在这里。
And I'm going to change it for now, just to be 3, for consistency.
为了一致性，我现在把它改成3。
And this is the correct shape even though it's too small,
这是正确的形状，尽管它太小了，
but Scratch will accommodate that for us.
但是Scratch会为我们解决这个问题。
And now-- same output but arguably better designed.
而现在——同样的输出，但可以说是更好的设计。
Why?
为什么？
Because if I want to change the number of meows, I change it in one place,
因为如果我想改变喵喵叫的数量，我在一个地方改变它，
no Copy/Paste messiness.
没有复制/粘贴混乱。
If I want to change the waiting, one place.
如果我想改变等待，一个地方。
I don't have to change it in multiple places and not screw up.
我不需要在很多地方修改它而不搞砸。
So let me hit the Green Flag.
所以让我打绿旗。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
All right, so-- nice.
好吧，所以 - 很好。
Now, it would have been nice if MIT had just given us a meow block that
现在，如果麻省理工学院给我们一个这样的“喵”块就好了
just automates all of this for us.
只是为我们自动化了所有这些。
Let me wager, they gave us the low-level implementation details.
我敢打赌，他们给了我们底层的实现细节。
They gave us the Play Sound Meow.
他们给了我们播放声音喵喵。
But I had to implement a decent number of blocks
但我必须实现相当数量的块
just to get a cat to meow again and again.
只是为了让猫一遍又一遍地喵喵叫。
I feel like we should have gotten that for free from MIT.
我觉得我们应该从麻省理工免费得到这个。
Well, they don't have to be the only ones that invent blocks for us to use.
他们不一定是唯一发明积木供我们使用的人。
You can write your own functions, your own verbs or actions.
你可以编写自己的函数，自己的动词或动作。
So how can we do this?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
Let's make our own puzzle piece, called Meow, that uses this code
让我们制作自己的拼图，叫做“喵”，使用这个代码
but creates it in such a way that it's reusable elsewhere.
但是以一种可以在其他地方重复使用的方式来创建它。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
Under my blocks in pink here, I'm going to go ahead and click,
在粉色方块下面，我要点击，
literally, Make a Block.
从字面上看，做一个块。
Now, here's an interface by which I can give the block a name.
现在，这里有一个接口，我可以通过它给块命名。
M-E-O-W will be the name of this block.
M-E-O-W 将是这个区块的名称。
And I'm just going to go ahead and quickly click OK.
我要继续，快速点击确定。
That just gives me a very generic, pink puzzle piece
这就给了我一个非常普通的粉红色拼图
that starts with the word Define because scratch
以Define开头，因为scratch
is asking me to define, that is, implement or create,
要求我定义，也就是实现或创造，
this new puzzle piece for me.
对我来说，这是一块新的拼图。
Well, what does it mean to Meow?
那么，这对喵喵意味着什么？
I'm going to claim that it means to do these two steps, to play the sound meow
我要说的是，它的意思是做这两步，发出喵喵的声音
and then just wait for 1 second.
然后等待 1 秒钟。
But what's powerful about this idea is look at this up top.
但这个想法的强大之处在于，看看上面这个。
Now that I've made a block, it exists in Scratch.
现在我已经创建了一个块，它存在于Scratch中。
MIT didn't need to create this for me.
麻省理工学院不需要为我创建这个。
I created it for myself and even you, if we end up sharing code.
我是为我自己甚至是你，如果我们最终共享代码的话。
So I can now drag Meow up in here.
所以我现在可以把喵喵拖到这里。
And what's nice about Meow is that itself is, yes, a function,
喵的好处在于，它本身就是一个函数，
but it's also an abstraction.
但它也是一种抽象。
Like, never again do I or even you need to worry or care about what
就像，我甚至你都不需要担心或关心什么
it means to meow or implement it.
它的意思是喵喵叫或实施它。
I can sort of drag it out of the way.
我可以把它拖开。
I didn't delete it-- drag it out of the way.
我没有删掉它，只是把它拖开了。
Out of sight, out of mind.
离久情疏。
Why?
为什么？
Because my code is now even better designed, in some sense,
从某种意义上说，因为我的代码现在设计得更好了，
because it's more readable.
因为它更具可读性。
What is it doing?
它在做什么？
When the Green Flag is clicked, repeat 3 times Meow.
点击绿旗后，重复喵喵3次。
It just says what it means.
它只是说它的意思。
And so it's a lot easier to read it, and it's
这样读起来就容易多了
a lot easier to think about it, especially
想起来容易多了，尤其是
if you're using Meow in other projects too.
如果你也在其他项目中使用喵。
Now, let me go ahead and click Play.
现在，让我继续并单击播放。
[MEOW]
[喵]
Same thing.
同样的事情。
[MEOW]
[喵]
So it's not really fundamentally any different.
所以本质上并没有什么不同。
[MEOW]
[喵]
But I can make this custom puzzle piece, this own function of mine, Meow,
但是我可以做这个自定义的拼图，我自己的这个功能，喵，
even more powerful.
甚至更强大。
Let me kind of rewind a bit and go to my Meow puzzle piece.
让我倒带一下，回到我的“喵”拼图。
And I am going to Control-click or Right-click on my pink puzzle piece.
然后ctrl -click或者右键单击我的粉色拼图。
And I'm going to edit it.
我要编辑它。
So I kind of regret making Meow so simple.
所以我有点后悔把喵喵弄得这么简单。
Wouldn't it be nice if Meow took an input, a.k.a.
如果喵喵有个输入，也就是。
an argument, that tells Meow how many times to meow.
它告诉喵喵该叫几次。
Then I can get rid of that loop and just tell
然后我可以去掉这个循环，然后告诉
Meow how many meows I actually want.
喵喵我到底想要多少喵。
So I'm going to click on another button here called, literally, Add an Input.
我要点击这里的另一个按钮，字面意思是，添加输入。
And it's going to have placeholder here.
这里会有占位符。
So I'm just going to put a placeholder there.
我在这里放一个占位符。
I keep using "n" for number, which is a go to in computer scientist terms.
我一直用“n”来表示数字，这在计算机科学家的术语中是很常见的。
And I'm going to add some descriptive text just so that it's
我要添加一些描述性的文字，这样
a little more self-explanatory.
更不言自明。
I'm just going to say Meow n Times.
我只想说喵喵n次。
But there's only one oval.
但是只有一个椭圆形。
Times is just going to be explanatory text.
Times只是一个解释性的文本。
And now notice what has happened.
现在注意发生了什么。
Now my puzzle piece takes an input, a.k.a.
现在我的拼图有一个输入，也就是。
an argument, that will tell that function to meow some number of times.
一个参数，它会告诉那个函数喵喵叫几次。
But it's not just going to work magically.
但它不会神奇地起作用。
I need to implement that lower level detail.
我需要实现那个较低级别的细节。
So let me zoom out.
所以让我缩小。
I have to remind myself what this function was.
我必须提醒自己这个函数是什么。
So I'm going to drag it higher up just so they're
所以我要把它往上拖，这样它们就
on the screen at the same time.
同时在屏幕上。
I'm going to go ahead now and temporarily move this over here.
我现在要把这个暂时移到这里。
I'm going to temporarily detach this over here.
我暂时把这个分开。
Why?
为什么？
Because what I thing I want to do is move my loop into the function itself,
因为我想做的是把循环移到函数本身，
move the Play and the Wait into the loop.
将播放和等待移动到循环中。
But I don't want a hardcode 3.
但我不想要硬编码 3。
Notice that n here is its own oval I can drag a copy of n
注意这里的n是它自己的椭圆，我可以拖一个n的副本
and just let it go there.
然后让它去那里。
So now I have a new version of Meow that takes an argument, n,
现在我有了一个新版本的喵，它有一个参数n，
that tells Meow how many times to meow.
这告诉喵喵多少次喵喵。
And now let me, again, drag this out of sight, out of mind,
现在让我再一次把它从视线中拖出来，从脑海中拖出来，
because who cares how I implemented it?
因为谁在乎我是如何实现的？
Once it's implemented, it's sort of done.
一旦它被实现，它就完成了。
Now my program is even better designed, in some sense.
从某种意义上说，现在我的程序设计得更好了。
Why?
为什么？
Because now it really just says what it means.
因为现在它只是表达了它的意思。
There's no loop.
没有循环。
There's no repeat, no implementation details.
没有重复，没有实现细节。
When Green Flag Clicked, Meow 3 Times.
当绿旗点击时，喵喵叫了 3 次。
And so functions indeed let you implement algorithms,
函数确实可以让你实现算法，
like they're just code that do something for you.
就好像它们只是帮你做事的代码。
But they're also themselves abstractions.
但它们本身也是抽象的。
Why?
为什么？
Because once a function exists, it has a name.
因为一旦函数存在，它就有了名字。
And you can think about it in that term.
你可以用这个术语来考虑它。
And you can use it by its name.
你可以用它的名字来使用它。
You don't have to care or remember how the function itself was built,
你不需要关心或记住函数本身是如何构建的，
whether it's by you or even MIT.
无论是你还是麻省理工学院。
So again, here I'll click the Green Flag.
再次点击绿旗。
It's the same thing.
这是一回事。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
So still correct, but better and better designed.
所以仍然是正确的，但是设计得越来越好。
And so any time, here and out, with Scratch, or soon C,
所以任何时候，在这里和外面，用Scratch，或者很快的C，
and eventually Python, when you find yourself doing anything
最后是Python，当你发现自己在做任何事情的时候
resembling Copy/Paste or again and again grabbing the same code, probably
类似于复制/粘贴或一次又一次地抓取相同的代码，可能
an opportunity to say, wait a minute.
有机会说，等一下。
Let me refactor this, so to speak, that is, rip out
让我来重构一下，也就是说，把它撕掉
the code that seems to be repeated again and again
代码似乎被重复了一遍又一遍
and put it in its own function so you can give it a descriptive name
把它放在它自己的函数里，这样你就可以给它一个描述性的名字
and use and reuse it.
并使用和重用它。
Any questions just yet on now saying or these loops or these functions
现在还有什么问题吗，关于这些循环或者这些函数
that we're using?
我们正在使用？
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: How did I make it so it meows three times?
DAVID J. MALAN：我是怎么做到让它喵喵叫三次的？
So I originally only had a puzzle piece called Meow.
所以我一开始只有一个叫喵的拼图。
And I decided to improve it.
我决定改进它。
So I held down Control and I Right-clicked or Control-clicked
所以我按住Control键右键点击Control键
on the pink puzzle piece at top left.
在左上角的粉色拼图上。
And I clicked Edit.
我点了“编辑”。
And that brought back the original interface
这让我想起了最初的界面
that lets me add some arguments to the puzzle piece itself.
这样我就可以给拼图本身添加一些参数。
And I clicked Add an Input on the left here.
我点击左边的 Add an Input。
And then I clicked on Add a Label over here.
然后我点击这里添加一个标签。
So that just lets you customize it even further.
所以这只是让你进一步定制它。
All right, so we've done this.
好吧，我们已经谈过了。
Let's add one of those other primitives too to do something optionally.
让我们添加一个其他原语，以便可选地执行某些操作。
So how about we make the cat meow only if it's being petted by a human,
不如我们让猫喵喵叫只有被人类抚摸的时候,
as by moving the mouse to hover over the cat, like a human would pet a cat?
比如让老鼠在猫身上盘旋，就像人类会抚摸猫一样？
Well, let me go ahead and throw away the meowing for now.
好吧，让我先把喵喵声扔掉。
And let me simplify it by just using a sound.
让我用一个声音来简化它。
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要开始了。
I'm going to go ahead and have a Control block that
我将继续，并有一个控制块
says If, because I want to implement the idea of if the cursor is touching
说，如果，因为我想实现，如果光标是触摸的想法
the cat, then play sound meow.
猫，然后播放声音喵喵。
Or I could use my same pink puzzle piece.
或者我也可以用我的粉色拼图。
But I'm going to throw that away and focus only now on the sounds.
但是我现在要把它扔掉，把注意力集中在声音上。
And I'm going to do this.
我要这么做。
If touching mouse pointer-- so I need to sense something about the world.
如果触摸鼠标指针-，所以我需要感觉一些关于这个世界的东西。
And we saw this earlier--
我们之前看到过这个
so If Touching Mouse Pointer.
所以如果触摸鼠标指针。
So notice this shape here, way too big.
注意这个形状，太大了。
But it is the right shape.
但它的形状是正确的。
So if I hover just right, it'll snap into place.
所以如果我悬停得恰到好处，它就会自动到位。
And this now, in blue, is my Boolean expression, a yes/no question,
这个蓝色的是我的布尔表达式一个是或否的问题,
true false.
真假。
"If" is a conditional.
“如果”是一个条件。
And what do I want to do?
我想做什么？
Well, if the cat is touching the mouse pointer,
如果猫碰到了鼠标指针,
I want to go ahead and play sound meow until done.
我想继续播放声音喵喵直到完成。
So let's do this.
我们开始吧。
I'm going to hit Green Flag, click.
我要点击“绿旗”按钮。
Now nothing's happened yet because it's a conditional, right?
现在什么都没有发生，因为这是一个条件，对不对？
It's only supposed to do something if I'm touching the cat.
只有当我碰到猫的时候它才会有反应。
Let me move the cursor over to the cat.
让我把光标移到猫身上。
And-- wait for it.
等等。
Hmm-- another bug.
又一个窃听器。
Why is the cat not meowing even though I very explicitly
为什么猫不喵喵叫，即使我非常明确
said, If Touching Mouse Pointer, Meow?
说，如果触摸鼠标指针，喵？
Yeah, in the middle--
是的，在中间
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, this is-- again, my computer's
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，这是 - 再次，我的电脑的
just so darn fast, like yours.
太快了，就像你一样。
I click the Green Flag, it asks the question,
我点击绿旗，它会提问,
am I touching the mouse pointer?
我碰到鼠标指针了吗？
Well, no, because my cursor was up there, not touching the cat.
没有，因为我的光标在上面，没碰到猫。
It's too late.
太迟了。
The cat's out of the bag.
秘密已经泄露了。
And so we have to instead solve this by some other means.
所以我们必须用其他方法来解决这个问题。
How can we fix this?
我们该怎么补救？
How do we fix that sort of race?
我们如何解决这种种族问题？
Yeah--
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so why don't we just keep
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，那我们为什么不保留
asking the question until I eventually am or am not actually petting the cat?
问这个问题，直到我最终是不是真的在抚摸这只猫？
So let me detach this temporarily.
让我暂时把这个分开。
Let me go under Control.
让我去控制。
Let me go under-- instead of repeat some finite number of times,
让我重复一遍，不要重复有限次数,
let's just do it forever.
我们就永远这样吧。
So sometimes loops that do work forever are a good thing.
所以有时候永远有效的循环是件好事。
The clock on your phone, that's in a loop
你手机上的时钟在循环
forever because you want it to always tell time and not
因为你想让它永远显示时间
stop at the end of the day.
在一天结束的时候停下来。
So sometimes you do want code to loop forever, as in this case.
所以有时候你确实希望代码永远循环下去，就像这个例子一样。
So let me go ahead and drag and drop it there.
所以让我继续把它拖到那里。
Let me, again, click the Green Flag.
让我再次点击绿旗。
Nothing's happening yet.
什么都没发生。
But notice, the program is still running.
但请注意，程序仍在运行。
And so if I move my cursor, move my cursor, move my cursor, and--
如果我移动光标，移动光标，移动光标，然后..
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
OK, so maybe we could add some Waiting.
好吧，也许我们可以加点“等待”。
But the cat does not want to be pet, in this case.
但在这种情况下，猫不想被宠物。
But it's indeed conditional.
但这确实是有条件的。
So there we have an incarnation in Scratch
所以，我们有一个化身在刮擦
of doing something conditionally.
有条件地做某事。
Now, we can make this really cool, really fast, if you will.
如果你愿意的话，我们可以让这个变得很酷，很快。
Let me stop this version.
让我停止这个版本。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我来吧。
Let me go ahead and throw all of this away.
让我把这一切都扔掉。
Let me go into my little Extensions bucket over here.
让我进入我的小扩展桶在这里。
And let me do Video Sensing, since most laptops or phones these days have
让我来做视频传感，因为现在大多数笔记本电脑或手机都有
cameras.
摄像头。
And there, indeed, I am, with Sanders behind me.
我确实在那里，桑德斯在我身后。
And let me do this.
让我来吧。
When Video Motion-- and let me get out of the way.
当视频运动-让我离开的方式。
When Video Motion is Greater Than some value.
当视频运动大于某个值时。
So 10 is the default. This is just a number that measures how much motion
所以默认值是10，这是一个测量运动量的数字
there is or isn't.
不管有没有。
So small number is like no motion.
所以小数字就像没有运动。
Big number is lots of motion.
大数字意味着大量的运动。
So I'm going to choose 50, somewhat arbitrarily here-- so 50.
所以我要选择50，这里有点随意，所以是50。
This is not normal to program off to the side.
在一边编程是不正常的。
But I'm now going to say this.
但我现在要说的是。
When Video Motion is 50, go ahead and Play Sound Meow like this.
当视频运动为 50 时，继续像这样播放声音喵喵。
So the cat is still in that world.
所以猫还在那个世界。
I'm going to stop the program and rerun it.
我将停止程序并重新运行它。
So here we go, Green Flag.
所以我们开始了，绿旗。
And now here comes-- all right, this is a little creepy,
现在来了——好吧，这有点令人毛骨悚然，
the way I'm petting the cat, but--
我抚摸猫的方式，但是——
and-- [SIGH]
还有——[叹息]
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
OK.
还行。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
There we go.
我们开始吧。
OK, so 50 was too big of a number.
好吧，所以50是一个太大的数字。
I have to pet the cat faster.
我必须更快地抚摸猫。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵]
Whereas this, if--
而这，如果——
I don't know--
我不知道--
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Yeah, so--
是的，所以——
[MEOW]
[喵]
OK, so you can make things even more interactive in this way
好的，所以你可以用这种方式使事情更具交互性
by just assembling different puzzle pieces.
只需组装不同的拼图。
And honestly, there are so many different puzzle pieces in here.
老实说，这里有许多不同的拼图。
We're not going to even scratch the surface of a lot of them.
我们甚至不会触及其中很多的表面。
But they generally just do what they say.
但他们通常只是按照他们说的去做。
And indeed, when you see on the screen here this pallet
事实上，当你在屏幕上看到这个托盘时
of puzzle pieces, really a lot of programming, especially early on,
的拼图，真的很多编程，尤其是在早期，
when learning a language, is just trying different things and try and fail.
在学习一门语言时，只是尝试不同的事情并尝试失败。
And if it doesn't work quite right, look for an alternative solution
如果它不能正常工作，请寻找替代解决方案
there too, as even I just had to do a moment ago.
那里也是，就像我刚才不得不做的那样。
Well, let's go ahead and use, actually, how about another example of something
好吧，让我们继续使用，实际上，另一个例子怎么样
a predecessor of yours made?
你的前辈做了？
Let me go ahead and grab a program I opened in advance here called
让我继续拿一个我在这里提前打开的程序，叫做
Whack-A-Mole Might we get a brave volunteer to come up,
打鼹鼠 愿我们找一个勇敢的志愿者上来，
who is willing to whack a mole with their head, virtually?
谁愿意用他们的头打鼹鼠，虚拟？
Maybe-- OK, let's see, how about in way back?
也许——好吧，让我们看看，回去怎么样？
You want to come on down?
你想下来吗？
All right, come on down.
好了，下来吧。
Sure, a round of applause for our volunteer.
当然，为我们的志愿者鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right, so here we have--
好了，我们来了——
come on down.
下来吧。
AUDIENCE: Hi there.
观众：你好。
DAVID J. MALAN: What's your name?
DAVID J. MALAN：你叫什么名字？
AUDIENCE: I'm Josh.
观众：我是乔希。
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, actually, say it into the microphone.
DAVID J. MALAN：哦，实际上，对着麦克风说。
AUDIENCE: Hi, I'm Josh.
观众：嗨，我是乔希。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, nice.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，很好。
Welcome, Josh.
欢迎你，乔希。
Come on over.
过来吧。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right, so same idea here--
好吧，这里的想法是一样的——
I'll take the mic back.
我把麦克风拿回来。
You'll have to stand in front of the camera.
你必须站在镜头前。
In just a moment, you're going to have to position your head in a box
在短短一会儿，你将不得不将你的头放在一个盒子里。
that your classmate from yesteryear created.
你过去的同学创造的。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[放歌！]
And we'll start with Beginner.
我们将从初学者开始。
AUDIENCE: OK.
观众：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: So line your head up in the box in a moment.
DAVID J. MALAN：所以一会儿把你的头放在盒子里。
AUDIENCE: All right.
观众：好的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
DAVID J. MALAN：很好。
12 seconds.
12秒。
5 seconds.
5秒。
Notice the score's up to 18 already.
请注意，分数已经达到了 18。
Pretty good.
相当不错。
All right, a round of applause for Josh, if we could.
好吧，如果可以的话，为乔希鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So notice how using some fairly simple primitives,
所以请注意如何使用一些相当简单的基元，
things do get interesting pretty fast.
事情确实很快变得有趣。
And how was that implemented?
这是如何实施的？
Well, there were probably at least four sprites.
嗯，可能至少有四个精灵。
So you're not confined to just one cat.
所以你不仅限于一只猫。
You can create more and more sprites, change what they look like.
你可以创建越来越多的精灵，更改它们的外观。
So they actually look like a mole, in this case.
所以在这种情况下，它们实际上看起来像一颗痣。
There's probably some conditionals in there, some loops for 30 seconds.
里面可能有一些条件，一些循环 30 秒。
That's checking if Josh's head's movement is exceeding
这是在检查乔希的头部是否超过。
some value over this way or over this way,
一些价值超过这种方式或这种方式，
then increment something called a variable.
然后递增称为变量的东西。
We'll see those too.
我们也会看到这些。
Just like in algebra you might have x and y
就像在代数中一样，你可能有 x 和 y
and z, storing values like numbers, so can computer programs,
z，存储数字等值，计算机程序也可以，
have variables called x or y or z, or more descriptively called Score,
有称为 x 或 y 或 z 的变量，或者更描述地称为 Score，
as in this case at top right, or another variable
如本例中的右上角或其他变量
called Countdown, typically one word in code, but in this case
称为倒计时，通常在代码中是一个单词，但在这种情况下
two words, that just store some value.
两个词，只是存储一些价值。
So there's probably some math going on in there
所以那里可能有一些数学问题
whereby the author of this program just is incrementing, that is,
因此，该程序的作者只是递增，即
adding 1 and 1 every time it detected that a mole had been whacked,
每次检测到鼹鼠被殴打时加 1 和 1，
in this case, with movement.
在这种情况下，有运动。
So back in the day, I, myself, actually implemented my very first program
所以回到过去，我，我自己，实际上实施了我的第一个程序
in Scratch when I was a graduate student, actually, at MIT--
在我读研究生的时候，在麻省理工学院——
cross-registered at MIT, taking a class from MIT's Media Lab,
在麻省理工学院交叉注册，从麻省理工学院媒体实验室上课，
specifically, the lifelong kindergarten group, which is the group that created
具体来说，终身幼儿园组，即创建
Scratch, itself.
划痕，本身。
And the program I wrote all those years ago and still
还有我多年前写的程序，现在仍然
rather cling to is a little something here
宁愿坚持在这里有点东西
called Oscartime, that I thought I'd play just a quick excerpt of myself
叫奥斯卡时间，我以为我只是播放自己的一个快速摘录
here.
这里。
So in this case, consider, as the music starts playing,
所以在这种情况下，当音乐开始播放时，请考虑一下，
how this program, which is much more sophisticated, certainly,
当然，这个程序如何更加复杂，
than the earliest "Say hello" examples we just did might also be implemented.
比我们刚刚做的最早的“打招呼”示例也可能实现。
Let me go ahead now and click the Green Flag.
现在让我继续并单击绿旗。
[MUSIC - OSCAR THE GROUCH, "I LOVE  TRASH"]
[音乐 - 奥斯卡·格鲁奇，“我爱垃圾”]
OSCAR THE GROUCH: (SINGING) Oh, I love trash.
OSCAR THE GROUCH：（唱）哦，我喜欢垃圾。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so some trash is moving, presumably in some kind of loop
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，所以一些垃圾正在移动，大概是在某种循环中
from the top.
从顶部。
If I'm touching the mouse cursor, it follows me.
如果我触摸鼠标光标，它会跟随我。
If I hover over the trash can, it responds.
如果我将鼠标悬停在垃圾桶上，它会做出响应。
If I let go, in some kind of loop, Oscar pops out,
如果我放手，在某种循环中，奥斯卡会弹出，
creates a variable with the current score.
创建具有当前分数的变量。
And it happens again.
它再次发生。
OSCAR THE GROUCH: (SINGING) It's awful, the holes.
OSCAR THE GROUCH：（唱）太糟糕了，洞。
And the laces are torn.
而且鞋带被撕裂了。
A gift from my mother the day I was born.
我出生那天母亲送给我的礼物。
I love it because it's trash.
我喜欢它，因为它是垃圾。
Oh, I--
哦，我——
DAVID J. MALAN: It's pretty easy at first but--
DAVID J. MALAN：一开始很容易，但是——
OSCAR THE GROUCH: (SINGING) --anything dirty or dingy--
奥斯卡：（唱）--任何肮脏或肮脏的东西---任何肮脏的东西-
DAVID J. MALAN: So I don't need to keep playing this up
DAVID J. MALAN：所以我不需要继续玩这个
on stage in front of everyone.
在所有人面前的舞台上。
So my score is already now up to some 6 or so.
所以我的分数现在已经达到了6分左右。
But in a moment, too, you'll see that it's going to escalate.
但过一会儿，你也会看到它会升级。
So I'm taking into account some time apparently.
所以我显然正在考虑一些时间。
So now--
所以现在——
OSCAR THE GROUCH: (SINGING) I have here some newspaper, 13 months old.
OSCAR THE GROUCH：（唱）我这里有一些报纸，13个月大。
DAVID J. MALAN: So more and more sprites are suddenly appearing.
DAVID J. MALAN：所以越来越多的精灵突然出现。
And notice, that each time they're appearing
请注意，每次它们出现时
from a different part of the screen.
从屏幕的不同部分。
That's an illusion, perhaps, too, that--
那是一种错觉，也许，那也是——
pick a random number between x and y.
在 x 和 y 之间选择一个随机数。
So you can actually pick some range of values
因此，你实际上可以选择一些值范围
to have the game constantly changing.
让游戏不断变化。
And indeed, I'm going to go ahead and click Stop,
事实上，我将继续并单击“停止”，
since I spent like eight hours plus, years ago, making this.
因为我花了大约八个多小时，几年前，制作这个。
And I can never listen to the song again,
我再也不能听这首歌了，
not that I should be anyway at this point in my life.
并不是说我应该在我生命中的这个时刻。
But this song is synchronized then with a lot of the actions that's happening.
但是这首歌与正在发生的许多动作同步。
And ultimately, there's just a lot of building blocks.
最终，有很多构建块。
But I didn't sit down and implement Oscartime, as I called it, all at once.
但我并没有坐下来实施奥斯卡时间，正如我所说的那样，一下子。
I really did take baby steps, so to speak.
可以这么说，我确实采取了一些小步骤。
And I figured out, well, how could I decompose this vision I had at the time
我想通了，好吧，我怎么能分解我当时的这个愿景。
to create this game ultimately?
最终创造这个游戏？
And how do I bite off maybe the easiest parts first?
我如何先咬掉最简单的部分？
And honestly, the first thing I did was I found this image, and I just dragged
老实说，我做的第一件事就是我找到了这张图片，我只是拖了
and dropped it into Scratch--
并把它放进了Scratch——
OK, done-- like, lamppost is installed.
好了，完成了——就像安装了灯柱一样。
It doesn't do anything.
它什么都不做。
It's not interactive.
它不是交互式的。
But I at least set the stage, so to speak, for the program.
但我至少为该计划奠定了基础。
Then what else might I have done?
那我还能做什么呢？
Well, let me do this.
好吧，让我来做这个。
Let me go ahead and open up in another editor here
让我继续在这里的另一个编辑器中打开
an early incarnation of Oscartime by doing this.
奥斯卡的早期化身。
Let me go into Oscartime here.
让我在这里进入奥斯卡时间。
Let me full screen this.
让我全屏显示这个。
And here you have--
而这里你——
let me hide the trash for just a moment--
让我把垃圾藏一会儿——
is what I might call the second version of my program, wherein,
是我可能称之为我的程序的第二个版本，其中，
at the top right of the stage here, I had the lamppost, which I just
在舞台的右上角，我有一根灯柱，我刚刚
dragged and dropped and got going, but then I added an actual sprite.
拖放并开始，但随后我添加了一个实际的精灵。
And it has to be a sprite if you want it to do things interactively.
如果你想让它以交互方式做事，它必须是一个精灵。
The lamppost-- not a sprite.
灯柱——不是精灵。
It's just an image a costume, if you will, for the whole
这只是一个图像，一个服装，如果你愿意的话，对于整个
stage itself, a backdrop.
舞台本身，一个背景。
But this thing is indeed a sprite because it
但这东西确实是精灵，因为它
needs to respond to code and events, like dragging and dropping.
需要响应代码和事件，例如拖放。
So what might I have done early on with that code?
那么我早期可能会用这些代码做什么呢？
Well, maybe the first version would have been
好吧，也许第一个版本是
something like this, whereby my very first version of Oscartime
像这样的东西，我的第一个版本的奥斯卡时间
might have said something like, oh, this.
可能会说，哦，这个。
How about, let me control the program as before-- or, rather, events.
怎么样，让我像以前一样控制程序 - 或者更确切地说，事件。
When the Green Flag is clicked, what do I want to do?
单击绿旗时，我想做什么？
Well, I want to go ahead and forever do something like this.
好吧，我想继续做这样的事情。
Forever-- so I want the lid to open up if I touch it.
永远——所以我希望如果我触摸它，盖子就会打开。
So if the cursor gets near the lid, I want the lid to open up.
因此，如果光标靠近盖子，我希望盖子打开。
And then if I move away, I want it to close.
然后如果我搬走，我希望它关闭。
So how can I do that?
那我该怎么做呢？
I want an If, but I just don't want one question, I really want two,
我想要一个如果，但我只是不想要一个问题，我真的想要两个，
a fork in the road that goes left or right, so to speak.
可以这么说，向左或向右的岔路口。
And let me grab this puzzle piece here, as I did long ago.
让我在这里抓住这个拼图，就像我很久以前所做的那样。
So notice, it grows to fill.
所以请注意，它长到填充。
What's the question I want to ask?
我想问什么问题？
Well, under Sensing, I'm going to go ahead here
好吧，在感应下，我将在这里继续
and say If this trashcan is Touching the Mouse Pointer--
并说如果这个垃圾桶在触摸鼠标指针——
what do I want to do?
我想做什么？
Well, I want to change what the trashcan looks like.
好吧，我想改变垃圾桶的样子。
And this part, I did in advance of class.
而这部分，我在上课前做了。
If you go up here to Costumes, this is where all the graphical stuff happens.
如果你去看服装，这是所有图形发生的地方。
And you'll see that I imported a whole bunch of different costumes
你会看到我进口了一大堆不同的服装。
that effectively, much like a video, when you play them quickly,
这很有效，就像视频一样，当你快速播放它们时，
creates the illusion of movement, some animation.
创造运动的错觉，一些动画。
But it's really just dot, dot, dot, dot, dot--
但它真的只是点，点，点，点，点——
different images showing on the screen.
屏幕上显示不同的图像。
Well, some of these costumes are called like Oscar1, Oscar2.
嗯，其中一些服装被称为奥斯卡1，奥斯卡2。
Oscar1 is closed.
奥斯卡1已关闭。
Oscar2 is open.
奥斯卡2开放。
So let's just deal with those first.
因此，让我们先处理这些。
So if I'm touching the mouse pointer, let me go under-- how about Looks?
所以，如果我触摸鼠标指针，让我进入 - 外观怎么样？
And we didn't use this before, but there's this block,
我们以前没有使用过这个，但是有这个块，
Switch Costume to Something Else.
将服装换成其他东西。
I'm going to drag and drop this inside of the If.
我要把它拖放到If中。
And notice it's a little bit indented.
请注意，它有点缩进。
I'm going to change it not to Oscar8, but Oscar2.
我不会把它改成奥斯卡8，而是奥斯卡2。
Otherwise, If Not Touching the Mouse Pointer--
否则，如果不触摸鼠标指针——
this is the other direction in the fork in the road--
这是岔路口的另一个方向——
let's go ahead and switch the costume back to what I described as Oscar1.
让我们继续将服装切换回我所描述的奥斯卡1。
So let me run this program.
所以让我运行这个程序。
And not much of interest is happening yet.
而且还没有太多的兴趣发生。
But notice, if I move the cursor up, down--
但请注意，如果我向上、向下移动光标——
but how is that working?
但这是如何工作的呢？
It's just changing the costume that's being overlaid on the sprite.
它只是改变了覆盖在精灵上的服装。
So it looks like interactivity, but you are really
所以它看起来像互动性，但你真的是
just changing the aesthetics.
只是改变美学。
And we humans are just kind of assuming, oh, it's opening up.
我们人类只是假设，哦，它正在开放。
Well, no, it's just changing a costume.
嗯，不，只是换了一套服装。
So here's the difference.
所以这就是区别。
The high-level abstraction-- trashcan opening.
高级抽象——垃圾桶打开。
The lower-level implementation detail-- costume
较低级别的实现细节——服装
changing, creating that illusion.
改变，创造那种错觉。
And if I want it to look prettier, I could just have many other costumes
如果我想让它看起来更漂亮，我可以有很多其他的服装。
and go boom, boom, boom, boom, boom to create more frames per second,
然后去轰隆隆，轰隆隆，轰隆隆，轰隆隆，
if you will.
如果你愿意的话。
So I need to do one other thing.
所以我需要做另一件事。
Maybe if I accidentally leave the trashcan open,
也许如果我不小心把垃圾桶打开了，
let me make one change here.
让我在这里做一个改变。
Let me make sure that the very first thing
让我确保第一件事
I do when the Green Flag is clicked, is always start with the trashcan
当绿旗被点击时，我总是从垃圾桶开始
closed because otherwise, you might accidentally leave it open.
已关闭，否则，你可能会意外将其保持打开状态。
So this gets me into some default state.
所以这让我进入了一些默认状态。
So now it's always closed until I manually hover over it instead.
所以现在它总是关闭，直到我手动将鼠标悬停在它上面。
Well, what might I have done next?
那么，我接下来可能会做什么？
Well, if I wanted to introduce something like the trash, I need a second sprite.
好吧，如果我想引入垃圾之类的东西，我需要第二个精灵。
And here, in advance, I grabbed the image already.
在这里，提前，我已经抓住了图像。
Let me pretend that this never happened.
让我假装这从未发生过。
Let me drag this away here.
让我把这个拖到这里。
And now I have nothing in my code area for this piece of trash.
现在我的代码区域中没有这个垃圾。
But it is the second sprite.
但它是第二个精灵。
And all I did was I clicked on the little cat plus icon here,
我所做的只是点击这里的小猫加图标，
created a second sprite.
创建了第二个精灵。
I named it trash.
我把它命名为垃圾。
I added a costume for it.
我为它添加了一套服装。
Sort of the aesthetic stuff, I did in advance.
有点美学的东西，我提前做了。
But here I'll do now the code.
但是在这里，我现在将执行代码。
How do I want to do this?
我想怎么做？
Well, how about when the Green Flag is clicked, for the trash can,
好吧，当绿旗被点击时，对于垃圾桶，
I want the trash can in parallel to do--
我要垃圾桶并行做——
I want the trash, the piece of trash, to do its own thing.
我希望垃圾，垃圾，做自己的事情。
So what I want it to do is maybe let's do Motion, how about?
所以我希望它做的是也许让我们做Motion，怎么样？
And let's go to a specific coordinate.
让我们转到一个特定的坐标。
Now, there's a lot of options here.
现在，这里有很多选择。
There's Turning, Go to a Random Position, Go to x,y, Glide,
有转弯，去一个随机的位置，去x，y，滑行，
more elegantly.
更优雅。
There's a lot of different ways to implement movement.
有很多不同的方法可以实现运动。
I just want it to go to a very specific location first.
我只是想让它先去一个非常具体的位置。
So I'm just going to go to x,y first.
所以我要先去x，y。
And I'm going to say x, how about, will be--
我要说x，怎么样，将会是——
let's not hardcode this.
我们不要对此进行硬编码。
Let's just have it be-- well, let's do it at 0, initially, and then 240.
让我们就这样吧——好吧，让我们在 0 开始，然后是 240。
So-- whoops-- let's do 0,240 so that this piece of trash
所以 - 哎呀 - 让我们做0,240，这样这块垃圾
always starts at the top middle of the screen.
始终从屏幕的顶部中间开始。
If you think back to that coordinate system, 0,0 is in the middle.
如果你回想一下那个坐标系，0,0 在中间。
240 is straight above it.
240 在它的正上方。
All right, now, after I do that, what do I want to do?
好吧，现在，在我这样做之后，我想做什么？
Well, how about I control this thing by forever falling.
好吧，我通过永远坠落来控制这个东西怎么样。
Now, how do I make the trash move?
现在，我该如何让垃圾移动？
We haven't seen this puzzle piece yet.
我们还没有看到这个拼图。
But under Motion, the very first thing is called Move Some Number of Steps.
但是在“运动”下，第一件事称为“移动一些步骤数”。
By default, it's 10.
默认情况下，它是 10。
But we'll do it more simply.
但我们会做得更简单。
Let me go ahead and move--
让我继续前进——
oh, sorry.
哦，对不起。
Move is going to move it in whatever direction it's facing.
移动将把它移动到它面对的任何方向。
I only want it to move down.
我只希望它向下移动。
So here, even I'm getting confused as to how many different ways there
所以在这里，即使我也对有多少种不同的方式感到困惑
are to do things.
是做事。
What I thing I want to do is this.
我想做的就是这个。
Let me only change my y-axis as follows.
让我只更改我的 y 轴，如下所示。
So here's another puzzle piece called Change y.
所以这是另一个拼图，叫做改变y。
So again, y is the vertical.
所以同样，y是垂直的。
So let me just change y by one pixel downward
所以让我把y向下改变一个像素
at a time, so -1 one pixel at a time.
一次，所以一次 -1 一个像素。
So it's kind of slow.
所以它有点慢。
And I think now--
我现在想——
I think that's it.
我想就是这样。
Let me hit Stop.
让我按停止。
Notice that my trashcan is still going to be interactive.
请注意，我的垃圾桶仍然是交互式的。
I haven't changed or deleted that code.
我没有更改或删除该代码。
I've just added now code for my piece of trash.
我现在刚刚为我的垃圾添加了代码。
If I click the Green Flag, notice that--
如果我点击绿旗，请注意——
after I enable it-- let me start that again.
启用它后 - 让我重新开始。
I had it hidden for before class.
我把它藏起来了，直到上课前。
But let me enable it now--
但是现在让我启用它——
Green Flag, notice it starts dead center, at x equals 0, y equals 240,
绿旗，注意它从死点开始，x 等于 0，y 等于 240，
and it's dropping one pixel at a time.
它一次下降一个像素。
If that seems a little boring, we can change it to -10 pixels at a time
如果这看起来有点无聊，我们可以一次将其更改为 -10 像素
and, boom, it's done.
而且，轰，它完成了。
So that's how you might change the speed of a program.
所以这就是你可以改变程序速度的方式。
But I'm going to leave it more simply as -1.
但是我将更简单地将其保留为-1。
And honestly, it would be nice if it doesn't always start from the top.
老实说，如果它并不总是从顶部开始，那就太好了。
Otherwise, this game is not going to be very interactive.
否则，这个游戏不会有很强的互动性。
I'm literally going to be grabbing the trash from the same place every time.
我每次都会从同一个地方抓垃圾。
So why don't I, instead, Stop this.
那么我为什么不，相反，阻止这个。
Let me go under Operators, and let's pick a random number.
让我在运算符下，让我们选择一个随机数。
So let me change the hardcoded--
所以让我改变硬编码——
the manually inputted-- 0, and let's make x be somewhere between 0,
手动输入的 -- 0，让我们让 x 介于 0 之间，
so in the middle and all the way over to--
所以在中间，一直到——
what was it-- oh, I got my numbers wrong--
那是什么——哦，我弄错了数字——
240 and my y will be 180.
240，我的y将是180。
Sorry, I got my x and my y confused.
对不起，我把我的 x 和我的 y 弄糊涂了。
So let me play this again.
所以让我再玩一遍。
And now we have a game that's more like games
现在我们有了一款更像游戏的游戏。
you might have played growing up or even now,
你可能在成长过程中甚至现在都玩过，
like there's some randomness to it.
就像它有一些随机性。
So the CPU, so to speak, is doing something more interesting.
所以可以说，CPU正在做一些更有趣的事情。
Let me run it again.
让我再运行一次。
Now it's a little to the left.
现在它有点左边。
Let me run it again.
让我再运行一次。
Now it's a little more to the left.
现在它更靠左一点。
Again-- now it's back to the right.
再说一遍，现在它又回到了右边。
So randomness just makes games more interesting.
所以随机性只会让游戏更有趣。
And this is why when you play any video game, if different things are
这就是为什么当你玩任何视频游戏时，如果不同的东西是
happening, there's probably just some randomness.
发生时，可能只是一些随机性。
And it's quantized as just a simple number.
它被量化为一个简单的数字。
Now, I think I just need one final flourish here, if I may.
现在，我想我只需要在这里最后一次繁荣，如果可以的话。
Let me go ahead and add this.
让我继续添加这个。
How about Events-- or rather--
事件怎么样 - 或者更确切地说 -
yes, Events.
是的，事件。
When Green Flag is clicked, I can do multiple things within the same sprite.
当绿旗被点击时，我可以在同一精灵中做多件事。
They don't all have to be attached to the same one.
它们不必都附加到同一个。
Let me go ahead and forever go ahead and do something else.
让我继续前进，永远继续做别的事情。
How about, Whenever the Trash is--
怎么样，每当垃圾在的时候——
how about-- Touching the Trash Can--
怎么样——摸垃圾桶——
so Forever If-- let's see, I need a Sensing block.
所以永远如果 - 让我们看看，我需要一个感应块。
So how about, Is Touching--
那么怎么样，感人是——
not the Mouse Pointer, this time, but Touching Oscar himself there.
这次不是鼠标指针，而是触摸奥斯卡本人。
Now let's see what happens.
现在让我们看看会发生什么。
All right, so let's go ahead and click the Green Flag.
好的，让我们继续点击绿旗。
Now I go down over here and let go.
现在我到这边去放手。
OK, I kind of want it to go into the trash can.
好吧，我有点想让它进入垃圾桶。
How do I make it go into the trash can?
如何让它进入垃圾桶？
How can we take this high-level idea, put trash into the trash can,
我们怎么能把这个高层次的想法，把垃圾扔进垃圾桶，
and make it seem to disappear?
让它看起来消失了？
Logically, what could we do?
从逻辑上讲，我们能做什么？
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so when it touches it, let's have it disappear.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，所以当它碰到它时，让我们让它消失。
So I could hide it.
所以我可以隐藏它。
Or honestly, if the game is going to be ongoing, like it was,
或者老实说，如果游戏要继续下去，就像以前一样，
letting me drop more and more trash, let me just
让我扔越来越多的垃圾，让我只是
have it go ahead and pick a new random location.
让它继续并选择一个新的随机位置。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这个。
Let me go ahead and Copy this puzzle piece up here and Duplicate.
让我继续将这个拼图复制到这里并复制。
And I don't want the whole thing, sorry.
而且我不想要整件事，对不起。
Let me get rid of this.
让我摆脱这个。
Let me just do this.
让我这样做。
Let me go back to some random location at the top.
让我回到顶部的某个随机位置。
So now notice what happens.
所以现在注意会发生什么。
If I click and drag on it-- here it goes--
如果我点击并拖动它 - 在这里 -
and I let go, it looks like it's going into the trash can
我松开手，看起来它要进垃圾桶了
because it snaps back up to some random location.
因为它会回扣到某个随机位置。
Now, the only thing I'm not doing really is keeping track of any kind of score.
现在，我唯一没有做的就是跟踪任何类型的分数。
And it turns out, if I full screen this, it's not going to be draggable,
事实证明，如果我全屏显示，它将无法拖动，
by default.
默认情况下。
So just as a corner case, so to speak, something
所以就像一个角落的情况，可以这么说，一些东西
that you might trip over otherwise, let me go ahead and under, let's
否则你可能会绊倒，让我继续下去，让我们
see, Sensing, it turns out I also need this for the piece of trash.
看，感应，原来我也需要这个垃圾。
There's this way of setting, in Scratch, a sprite
在Scratch中，有这种设置精灵的方式
to be draggable or not draggable.
可拖动或不可拖动。
I need to explicitly make it draggable so
我需要明确地使其可拖动，以便
that when I do full screen this thing now,
当我现在全屏做这件事时，
it still remains draggable and someone like myself
它仍然可以拖动，像我这样的人
can play it again and again.
可以一遍又一遍地播放。
Well, how about we supplement this with one final flourish?
好吧，我们用最后的繁荣来补充一下怎么样？
Why don't we keep track now of the user score?
为什么我们现在不跟踪用户分数？
So how about, when the user actually drags the piece of trash
那么，当用户实际拖动垃圾时呢？
to the trash can, let me go under Variables here,
到垃圾桶，让我在这里的变量下，
where, in advance, I've already made myself a variable called Score.
事先，我已经给自己做了一个叫做分数的变量。
I could have called it x or y or z or ABC, but that's not very descriptive.
我本可以称它为x或y或z或ABC，但这不是很具有描述性。
In programming, you typically give things a more descriptive English,
在编程中，你通常会给事物一个更具描述性的英语，
or some other language, name.
或其他语言，名称。
So I called this one Score.
所以我称这个为分数。
So how do I want to do this in my Score?
那么我想如何在我的分数中做到这一点呢？
Well, let me go ahead and initially set this game
好吧，让我继续，初步设置这个游戏
score to 0 at the very top of one of these scripts--
在其中一个脚本的最顶部得分为 0——
one of these programs up here.
这些程序之一在这里。
And then any time my piece of trash is touching
然后每当我的垃圾接触时
Oscar, let's not just jump to the top, let's change the score by 1 up here.
奥斯卡，让我们不要只是跳到顶部，让我们在这里将分数改变 1 分。
So now notice, If Touching Oscar, Change the Score-- that is,
所以现在请注意，如果触摸奥斯卡，改变分数——也就是说，
Add 1 to the Score--
分数加1——
and then Pick a new Random location.
，然后选择一个新的随机位置。
And now Green Flag--
现在绿旗——
let's do this slowly.
让我们慢慢来。
Here it goes.
来了。
The trashcan opens.
垃圾桶打开。
I let go.
我放手了。
And now notice, at the top left of my program, notice the score is now 2.
现在请注意，在我的程序的左上角，请注意分数现在是 2。
Notice the score, if I do this again, is about to become 3.
请注意，如果我再次这样做，分数即将变为 3。
And so here we have building blocks, literally,
所以在这里我们有构建块，从字面上看，
of making this program better and better and better.
使这个程序越来越好，越来越好。
And so, indeed, that's how you generally approach solving any problem with code,
所以，事实上，这就是你通常如何用代码解决任何问题，
be it in Scratch or C or Python or some other.
无论是在Scratch，C或Python或其他一些东西中。
You take this vision you might have or some vision
你采取你可能有的这个愿景或一些愿景
you've been assigned in a homework assignment
你被分配了家庭作业
and try to break it down into these constituent parts
并尝试将其分解为这些组成部分
and just pluck off the easy ones first.
然后先拔掉容易的。
Put the lamp post there first, and at least
先把灯柱放在那里，至少
feel like you're making some progress.
感觉你正在取得一些进展。
Then pluck off something like the trash can, and just
然后拔掉垃圾桶之类的东西，然后
make it do a little thing.
让它做一件小事。
And it doesn't have to be in some same order here.
而且它在这里不必按相同的顺序排列。
I could have done this in a million different ways.
我本可以用一百万种不同的方式做到这一点。
But figure out what the small pieces are that, ultimately,
但是弄清楚小块是什么，最终，
like a few of the problems we've solved today, assemble into a greater solution
就像我们今天解决的一些问题一样，组装成一个更好的解决方案
there too.
那里也是。
So that you have now a mental model for these types of blocks and others,
这样你现在就有了这些类型的块和其他块的心智模型，
let's return for a moment to this.
让我们回到这个。
We saw a moment ago that when I started saying, "Hello, David,"
我们刚才看到，当我开始说，“你好，大卫，”
and nesting those puzzle pieces, we had a whole different paradigm altogether.
嵌套这些拼图，我们有一个完全不同的范式。
My input for that second version of, "Hello, world," was to now pass in,
我对第二个版本的输入，“你好，世界”，现在是传入，
for instance, "What's Your Name?"
例如，“你叫什么名字？
into my function, called Ask.
进入我的函数，称为询问。
That gave me not a side effect, but what I called,
这给我的不是副作用，而是我所说的，
again, a return value, called Answer, by default, in Scratch.
同样，返回值，默认情况下称为 Answer，在 Scratch 中。
And now notice and recall, when I had that same output
现在注意并回忆，当我有相同的输出时
become the input to my next block, it looked a little something like this--
成为我下一个块的输入，它看起来有点像这样——
Say.
说。
So how does this type of block and this nesting, this stacking of blocks,
那么这种类型的块和这种嵌套，这种块的堆叠是如何进行的，
fit into the same mental model?
适合同一个心智模式？
Well, same idea-- my input for that part of the story is now taking in not one
嗯，同样的想法 - 我对故事的那部分的投入现在没有接受一个
input but two--
输入但两个——
two arguments-- "hello" and the answer from before.
两个论点 - “你好”和之前的答案。
The function, in this case, is that new block called Join.
在本例中，函数是名为 Join 的新块。
The output thereof is, "Hello, David," which itself became--
它的输出是，“你好，大卫”，它本身变成了——
if we sort of animate this--
如果我们把这个动画化——
the input to my final function, which indeed was still Say.
我的最终函数的输入，确实仍然是 Say。
And this is only to say-- no pun intended--
这只是说——没有双关语的意思——
that almost everything that you do with these puzzle pieces,
你用这些拼图做的几乎所有事情，
be it in the context of Oscartime or the mole whacking
无论是在奥斯卡时代还是鼹鼠鼬的背景下
or even just something simple like, "Hello, world,"
甚至只是一些简单的东西，比如“你好，世界，”
will ultimately fit into that relatively simple mental model there.
最终会适合那里相对简单的心智模型。
Now, I thought we'd end by taking a look at just a couple of final examples.
现在，我想我们最后看几个最后的例子。
These ones, too, made by some of your predecessors.
这些也是你的一些前辈做的。
And for this, I thought we would not write code together,
为此，我认为我们不会一起编写代码，
but read it instead.
而是阅读它。
And so allow me to open up one other example here
因此，请允许我在这里打开另一个例子
that will show us a few different versions of a program
这将向我们展示程序的几个不同版本
that a predecessor made.
前辈做出的。
Give me just a moment here.
给我一点时间。
And we'll see how we might build up to something even more interactive.
我们将看到如何构建更具交互性的东西。
And in just a moment, we'll see something
一会儿，我们会看到一些东西
they called Ivy's Hardest Game, focused here on these particular mechanics.
他们称之为常春藤最难的游戏，专注于这些特殊的机制。
So here is version 0, so to speak, of this program, wherein
所以这是该程序的版本 0，可以这么说，其中
the goal was to create a game where you have to get out of some kind of maze.
我们的目标是创建一个游戏，你必须走出某种迷宫。
And you have to get out, in this case, the Harvard crest from this maze.
在这种情况下，你必须从这个迷宫中走出哈佛的徽章。
Let me go ahead and just hit Play on this Green Flag
让我继续，点击这个绿旗上的播放
so you can see what the first building block for this program might have been.
因此，你可以看到该程序的第一个构建块可能是什么。
Notice that my hand here is actually on the Arrow keys on my keyboard.
请注意，我的手实际上在键盘上的箭头键上。
And it seems that by moving up, down, left, or right,
似乎通过向上、向下、向左或向右移动，
this little crest on the screen responds in exactly that way.
屏幕上的这个小波峰正是以这种方式响应的。
Now, let's hypothesize for just a moment.
现在，让我们假设一下。
Even though we've not done anything quite like this before,
即使我们以前没有做过这样的事情，
how might this code be implemented?
如何实现此代码？
How do you get a sprite, be it a cat or a crest,
你如何得到一个精灵，无论是猫还是徽章，
to respond to keys on a keyboard-- might you think intuitively?
响应键盘上的键 - 你可以直观地思考吗？
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, there could be something
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，可能有一些东西
sensing what key you're pressing on.
感应你按下的键。
And if you do it again in forever a loop,
如果你在永远循环中再做一次，
you'll just constantly be listening for keystrokes.
你只会不断聆听击键。
And this is how, like, every piece of software nowadays works.
这就是现在每个软件的工作方式。
It's constantly waiting for your phone to be tapped
它一直在等待你的手机被窃听
or something to be typed on the screen.
或要在屏幕上键入的内容。
So let me go ahead and look inside of this existing program here.
因此，让我继续查看此现有程序的内部。
And there's more going on, but we'll take a quick glance
还有更多的事情要做，但我们会快速浏览一下
what's actually going on.
到底是怎么回事。
Well, up here at top left, notice, we just
好吧，在左上角，请注意，我们只是
have Go To x Equals 0 and y Equals 0.
有 转到 x 等于 0 和 y 等于 0。
That means put the Harvard crest dead center in the middle of the stage.
这意味着将哈佛的徽章死中心放在舞台中间。
Then we have Forever two functions that we
然后我们有永远的两个函数，我们
made in advance as custom functions--
预先制作为自定义功能--
Listen for Keyboard, Feel for Walls.
听键盘，感受墙壁。
So it's doing two things at once.
所以它同时做两件事。
It's forever listening for the keyboard-- up,
它永远在听键盘——向上，
down, left, right-- and feeling for the walls,
向下，向左，向右 - 对墙壁的感觉，
in the sense that if I get too far to the left,
从某种意义上说，如果我向左走得太远，
I don't want it to keep moving past that black wall.
我不希望它一直越过那堵黑墙。
And if it moves too far to the right, I don't want it to blow through that wall
如果它向右移动得太远，我不希望它吹穿那堵墙。
either.
也。
So it's going to do two things constantly, listening for keyboard
所以它会不断地做两件事，听键盘。
and feeling for walls, so to speak.
可以这么说，对墙壁的感觉。
And how are those implemented?
这些是如何实施的？
Well, this one's a bit long.
嗯，这个有点长。
But on the left here is Listen for Keyboard.
但是在左边是听键盘。
So this pink puzzle piece, Listen for Keyboard,
所以这个粉红色的拼图，听键盘，
first checks If the Key Up Arrow is Pressed, question mark,
首先检查 如果按下向上键箭头，问号，
Boolean expression in a conditional, Change y By 1.
条件中的布尔表达式，将 y 更改为 1。
That means, move it up 1.
这意味着，将其向上移动 1。
Else If the Key Down Arrow is Pressed, then Change y by -1,
否则，如果按下向下键，则将 y 更改为 -1，
and similar for Left Arrow, similar for Right Arrow.
左箭头类似，右箭头类似。
And even though there's not a loop in this pink function,
即使这个粉红色函数中没有循环，
there is where I'm using it.
有我正在使用它的地方。
So it's constantly being asked again and again.
所以它不断地被问到一次又一次。
How about feeling for walls?
对墙壁的感觉怎么样？
Well, over here to the right--
好吧，右边这边——
it's a little cut off-- but here you have, If Touching Left Wall,
它有点切断 - 但这里有，如果触摸左墙，
Change x by 1.
将 x 更改为 1。
So if you hit the wall, it's too late.
所以如果你碰壁，为时已晚。
You're kind of blowing through it already.
你已经有点吹过它了。
So I want to move it back one pixel so it's no longer touching that wall.
所以我想把它移回一个像素，这样它就不会再碰到那堵墙了。
Similarly, if it's touching the right wall, I want to back it up one pixel
同样，如果它碰到右墙，我想备份一个像素。
so it's no longer touching that wall.
所以它不再碰到那堵墙。
So it's kind of like bouncing off ever so slightly so that it
所以这有点像稍微反弹，这样它
doesn't slip through that actual wall.
不会穿过那堵真正的墙。
And what are those walls?
那些墙是什么？
Well, notice down here, it's just a simple sprite with a black line
好吧，注意这里，它只是一个带有黑线的简单精灵
that I've oriented vertically instead of horizontally.
我垂直而不是水平方向。
And that's just so that I can ask questions of these other two sprites.
这只是为了让我可以问另外两个精灵的问题。
Now, that gives me that form of interactivity.
现在，这给了我这种形式的交互性。
What more can I now do?
我现在还能做什么？
Well, what if we make things a little more interactive here?
好吧，如果我们在这里让事情更具互动性呢？
Let me go ahead and see inside version 1 our second.
让我继续查看我们的第二个版本 1 内部。
And let me propose what's going to happen here.
让我提出这里将要发生的事情。
Well, how might we add a little something like Yale into the mix?
那么，我们如何在组合中添加一些像耶鲁这样的东西呢？
Well, what's Yale going to do when I hit the Green Flag now based on this code?
那么，当我现在根据这段代码击中绿旗时，耶鲁大学会怎么做？
Any hunches?
有什么预感吗？
Here is the code for my Yale sprite.
这是我的耶鲁精灵的代码。
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, it's kind of going to be
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，它将会是
an adversarially by blocking my path, theoretically,
理论上，通过阻挡我的路径来对抗，
if I keep writing more code.
如果我继续编写更多的代码。
So why?
为什么呢？
It too goes to the middle of the screen.
它也到了屏幕中间。
It points in direction 90 degrees.
它指向 90 度的方向。
So similarly, there's a whole degree system as well.
所以同样，还有一个完整的学位系统。
And it forever asks this.
它永远问这个。
If Touching the Left Wall Or--
如果触摸左墙或——
notice the green block--
注意绿色块——
Touching the Right Wall, then just Turn around 180 Degrees.
触摸右墙，然后只需转180度。
And indeed, if you think this through logically,
事实上，如果你从逻辑上考虑这一点，
that just means you're bouncing this way and this way
那只是意味着你以这种方式和这种方式弹跳
by just flipping yourself around 180 degrees for just this Yale sprite.
只需将自己翻转 180 度，只为这个耶鲁精灵。
So if I go ahead and zoom in on this and click the Green Flag,
因此，如果我继续放大并单击绿旗，
I can still move up and down.
我仍然可以上下移动。
But Yale is just kind of doing this all day long, back and forth
但耶鲁只是整天这样做，来来回回
and back and forth, forever.
来来回回，永远。
Nothing bad happens if I try to go through it.
如果我尝试经历它，就不会发生任何不好的事情。
But we could add that, certainly, to the mix.
但是，我们当然可以将其添加到组合中。
In fact, let's add one final feature before we play this particular game.
事实上，在玩这个特定的游戏之前，让我们添加一个最后一个功能。
And let me go ahead and open up the final version of these building blocks
让我继续打开这些构建块的最终版本
that adds MIT to the mix.
这增加了麻省理工学院。
So here is MIT.
这是麻省理工学院。
Someone want to explain what this code does?
有人想解释一下这段代码的作用吗？
And this is what we're doing.
这就是我们正在做的。
This itself is a skill.
这本身就是一种技能。
Reading someone else's code and understanding it
阅读并理解别人的代码
is half of the part of programming besides writing.
是除了写作之外的一半编程部分。
Yeah--
是的--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, it's chasing down the Harvard logo outline.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，它正在追逐哈佛的标志轮廓。
So this is apparently the name of the costume
所以这显然是服装的名称
that this student made, Harvard logo outline.
这个学生做的，哈佛标志勾勒出来。
And apparently, it goes to a random position first.
显然，它首先进入随机位置。
But then it forever points to Harvard.
但它永远指向哈佛。
So no matter where I'm moving it, up, down, left,
所以无论我把它移到哪里，向上、向下、向左，
or right, MIT is being a little more strategic than Yale,
或者对，麻省理工学院比耶鲁更具战略意义，
bouncing back and forth like this.
像这样来回蹦蹦跳跳。
So let's go ahead and play this one in full screen.
因此，让我们继续全屏播放此游戏。
And here we have a Green Flag.
在这里，我们有一面绿旗。
So if I move up, MIT, rather strategically,
因此，如果我上升，麻省理工学院，相当战略性地，
is following me no matter where I go.
无论我走到哪里，都跟着我。
All right, so still, nothing bad happens.
好吧，所以仍然没有发生任何不好的事情。
But now it's struggling, right?
但现在它正在挣扎，对吧？
It's going up, down, up, down.
它正在上升，下降，上升，下降。
It's trying to follow me even though I'm not moving.
它试图跟着我，即使我不动。
So we need some final flourishes.
因此，我们需要一些最后的繁荣。
And so I think, for this, we need perhaps one final volunteer.
所以我认为，为此，我们也许需要最后一个志愿者。
After this, cake awaits for everyone outside,
在这之后，蛋糕在外面等待着每个人，
as is an end of first lecture CS50 tradition.
这是第一讲CS50传统的结束。
Would you like to come up and be our volunteer?
你想上来做我们的志愿者吗？
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好吧。
And so this will be the actual version but written by one of your predecessors
所以这将是实际的版本，但由你的一位前任写的
that I'll full screen here.
我会在这里全屏显示。
It's going to stitch together all of these same primitives and more,
它将把所有这些相同的基元拼接在一起，甚至更多，
but add the notion of scores and lives so that there's actually
但是加上分数和生活的概念，这样实际上就有了
a goal, which in this case is to move the Harvard crest to constantly pursue
一个目标，在这种情况下是移动哈佛徽章不断追求
the character on the right-hand side so that your sprite touches that one.
右侧的角色，以便你的角色触摸该角色。
Would you like to introduce yourself?
你想自我介绍一下吗？
AUDIENCE: Hi, my name is Mohammed.
观众：嗨，我叫穆罕默德。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, wonderful.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，太好了。
Welcome aboard.
欢迎登船。
And here we come with some instructions and final
在这里，我们提供一些说明和最终
flourish if we want to keep the lights up but perhaps increase the music.
如果我们想保持灯光，但也许增加音乐，那就繁荣起来。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[放歌！]
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH  THIS"]
[音乐 - MC HAMMER，“U CAN'T TOUCH THIS”]
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) You can't this.
MC HAMMER：（唱）你不能这样。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
DAVID J. MALAN: Notice he is using the up, down, left, right.
DAVID J. MALAN：注意他使用的是上、下、左、右。
But there's many more walls now.
但现在有更多的墙。
First level's pretty easy.
第一级很容易。
But now Yale's in the mix, bouncing back and forth.
但现在耶鲁在混合中，来回蹦蹦跳跳。
Again, pretty easy.
同样，很容易。
Now there's two Yale's at slightly different positions.
现在有两个耶鲁大学的位置略有不同。
MIT is coming soon.
麻省理工学院即将到来。
But first, we have three Yales.
但首先，我们有三个耶鲁大学。
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) As such.
MC HAMMER：（唱）因此。
And this is a beat, uh, you can't touch.
这是一个节拍，呃，你不能碰。
DAVID J. MALAN: Very nice.
DAVID J. MALAN：非常好。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) I told you, homeboy, you can't touch this.
MC HAMMER：（唱）我告诉过你，老家伙，你不能碰这个。
Yeah, that's how it look when you know you can't touch this.
是的，当你知道你不能碰这个时，这就是它的样子。
Look at my eyes, man, you can't touch this.
看看我的眼睛，伙计，你不能碰这个。
Yo, let me bust the funky lyrics. you can't touch this.
哟，让我打破时髦的歌词。你不能碰这个。
Fresh new kicks and pants, you got to like that.
新鲜的新踢腿和裤子，你必须喜欢这样。
Now, you know you want to dance.
现在，你知道你想跳舞了。
So move out of your seat and get a fly--
所以离开你的座位，去飞一只苍蝇——
DAVID J. MALAN: You got to go quick.
DAVID J. MALAN：你必须快点。
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) Catch this beat while it's rolling.
MC HAMMER：（唱）在滚动时抓住这个节拍。
Hold on.
坚持。
Pump a little bit, and let them know what's going on, like that, like that.
抽一点，让他们知道发生了什么，像那样，那样。
Cold on a mission, so fall on back.
在任务中冷漠，所以落在后面。
Let them know that you're too much and this a beat, uh, they can't touch.
让他们知道你太过分了，这是一个节拍，呃，他们不能碰。
Yo, I told you.
哟，我告诉过你。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Yo, sound the bell.
哟，按铃。
School's in, sucker.
学校来了，傻瓜。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Give me a song, a rhythm.
给我一首歌，一种节奏。
Making them sweat, that's what I'm giving them.
让他们出汗，这就是我给他们的。
Now they know, you talk about the Hammer,
现在他们知道了，你谈论锤子，
you talking about a show that's hyped and tight.
你说的是一个炒作和紧张的节目。
Singers are sweating, so pass them a wipe or a tape to learn.
歌手们汗流浃背，所以给他们擦拭或磁带来学习。
What's it going to take--
这需要什么——
DAVID J. MALAN: Second-to-last level.
DAVID J. MALAN：倒数第二级。
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) Legit.
MC HAMMER：（唱）合法。
Either work hard or you might as well quit.
要么努力工作，要么退出。
That's word because you know--
这是这个词，因为你知道——
DAVID J. MALAN: Last level.
DAVID J. MALAN：最后一关。
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) You can't touch this.
MC HAMMER：（唱）你不能碰这个。
DAVID J. MALAN: Hey!
DAVID J. MALAN：嘿！
[LAUGHS]
[笑]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Congrats.
恭喜。
All right, that's it for CS50.
好的，这就是CS50。
Welcome.
欢迎。
Cake is now served.
蛋糕现在上桌了。
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。
[PROJECTOR CLICKING]
[投影仪点击]